<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2016-06-01-548" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-06-01-548">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2016-06-01-548</id>
    <dato>01.06.2016 nr. 548</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2016-06-01</dato>
    <publisert>I 2016 hefte 7 s 1164</publisert>
    <ikraft>02.06.2016</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2016-06-02</ikraft>
    <departement>Samferdselsdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="lov-1993-06-11-101-§4-1">L11.06.1993 nr. 101 § 4-1</ref>, <ref id="lov-1993-06-11-101-§9-1">§ 9-1</ref>, <ref id="for-1999-12-10-1273">F10.12.1999 nr. 1273</ref></hjemmel>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2016-0475</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Airbus Helicopters EC225LP and AS332L2 - Limitation of all operations</korttittel>
    <korttittel>3 Safety and operational directive - Airbus Helicopters EC225LP and AS332L2 - Limitation of all operations in the Kingdom of Norway due to fatal accident on the 29th of April 2016 (Nr. 548)</korttittel>
    <tittel>Safety and operational directive - Airbus Helicopters EC225LP and AS332L2 - Limitation of all operations in the Kingdom of Norway due to fatal accident on the 29th of April 2016</tittel>
    <marg niv="1" id="/marg/1"><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Luftfartstilsynet 1. juni 2016 med hjemmel i lov 11. juni 1993 nr. 101 om luftfart (luftfartsloven § 4-1 og § 9-1, jf. delegeringsvedtak 10. desember 1999 nr. 1273.
<br/></marg>
    <ledd id="/ledd/1">This Safety and Operational Directive contains mandatory action that is required to ensure an acceptable level of safety. It is issued under paragraphs 4-1 and 9-1 of the Aviation Act (luftfartsloven) and in accordance with regulation (EC) No 216/2008 article 14.1.</ledd>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-06-01-548/k1">
      <kverdi>1</kverdi>
      <ktittel>Introduction</ktittel>
      <liste id="/kapittel/1/ledd/1/liste/1.1">
        <lverdi>1.1</lverdi>
        <avsnitt id="/kapittel/1/ledd/1/liste/1.1/avsnitt/1">This Safety and Operational Directive is applicable to operators conducting public transport helicopter operations or commercial air transport operations in the jurisdiction of the Kingdom of Norway.</avsnitt>
      </liste>
      <liste id="/kapittel/1/ledd/1/liste/1.2">
        <lverdi>1.2</lverdi>
        <avsnitt id="/kapittel/1/ledd/1/liste/1.2/avsnitt/1">Recipients must ensure that this Directive is copied to all members of their staff who need to take appropriate action or who may have an interest in the information, including any «in-house» or contracted maintenance organisation and relevant outside contractors.</avsnitt>
      </liste>
      <liste id="/kapittel/1/ledd/1/liste/1.3">
        <lverdi>1.3</lverdi>
        <avsnitt id="/kapittel/1/ledd/1/liste/1.3/avsnitt/1">This Safety and Operational Directive supersedes SAFETY DIRECTIVE No. 16/05616-5 and extends the applicability of measures put in place on 29 April 2016 and 11 May 2016 to all Airbus Helicopters EC225LP and AS332L2 helicopters.</avsnitt>
      </liste>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-06-01-548/k2">
      <kverdi>2</kverdi>
      <ktittel>Compliance/action to be taken</ktittel>
      <liste id="/kapittel/2/ledd/1/liste/2.1">
        <lverdi>2.1</lverdi>
        <avsnitt id="/kapittel/2/ledd/1/liste/2.1/avsnitt/1">The Norwegian Civil Aviation Authority directs operators of any Airbus Helicopters EC225LP or AS332L2 helicopter which is:</avsnitt>
        <liste id="/kapittel/2/ledd/1/liste/2.1.a">
          <lverdi>a)</lverdi>
          <avsnitt id="/kapittel/2/ledd/1/liste/2.1.a/avsnitt/1">registered in the Kingdom of Norway or</avsnitt>
        </liste>
        <liste id="/kapittel/2/ledd/1/liste/2.1.b">
          <lverdi>b)</lverdi>
          <avsnitt id="/kapittel/2/ledd/1/liste/2.1.b/avsnitt/1">flying in the Kingdom of Norway or in the neighborhood of an offshore location to comply with the requirements set forth in paragraph 2.2.</avsnitt>
        </liste>
      </liste>
      <liste id="/kapittel/2/ledd/1/liste/2.2">
        <lverdi>2.2</lverdi>
        <avsnitt id="/kapittel/2/ledd/1/liste/2.2/avsnitt/1">Operators must not conduct any flight with an Airbus Helicopters EC225LP or AS332L2 helicopter.</avsnitt>
      </liste>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-06-01-548/k3">
      <kverdi>3</kverdi>
      <ktittel>Reason</ktittel>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/3/ledd/1">This Safety and Operational Directive is made in the interest of ensuring safe operations following a fatal accident with an Airbus Helicopters EC225LP on the 29 April 2016.</avsnitt>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/3/ledd/1/avsnitt/1">As a result of the preliminary report from AIBN 1 June 2016 and contact between the UK Civil Aviation Authority and Norwegian Civil Aviation Authority on 1 June 2016, it was decided that Norwegian Civil Aviation Authority will extend the scope of their Airbus Helicopters EC225LP and AS332L2 Safety Directives to all operations, including SAR operations.</avsnitt>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-06-01-548/k4">
      <kverdi>4</kverdi>
      <ktittel>Notifications and queries</ktittel>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/4/ledd/1">Notifications and queries should be sent to Luftfartstilsynet at
<lenke url="https://lovdata.no/static/mailto:postmottak@caa.no">postmottak@caa.no</lenke>, and referring to Case 16/05616.</avsnitt>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/5" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-06-01-548/k5">
      <kverdi>5</kverdi>
      <ktittel>Entry into force and cancellation</ktittel>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/5/ledd/1">This Safety and Operational Directive shall enter into force on 2 June 2016 00:00 hrs local time and will remain in force until revoked by the Civil Aviation Authority</avsnitt>
    </kapittel>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
