<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2016-02-12-149" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2016-02-12-149</id>
    <dato>12.02.2016 nr. 149</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2016-02-12</dato>
    <publisert>I 2016 hefte 3 s 408</publisert>
    <ikraft>12.02.2016</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2016-02-12</ikraft>
    <departement>Helse- og omsorgsdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§23">L19.12.2003 nr. 124 § 23</ref>, <ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§16">§ 16</ref></hjemmel>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2016-0130</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Forskrift om import av paanblader fra India</korttittel>
    <korttittel>3 Forskrift om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av paanblader fra India (Nr. 149)</korttittel>
    <tittel>Forskrift om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av paanblader fra India</tittel>
    <redaksjonell_note><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Mattilsynet 12. februar 2016 med hjemmel i lov 19. desember 2003 nr. 124 om matproduksjon og mattrygghet mv. (matloven) § 23 tredje ledd, jf. § 16.
<br/><b>EØS-henvisninger:</b> EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kap. I del 7.1 nr. 13 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2016/166).</redaksjonell_note>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/p1">
      <pverdi>§ 1.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Virkeområde</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/1/ledd/1">Forskriften gjelder kontroll ved import av paanblader (Piper Betle), eller næringsmidler som inneholder dette produktet, med opprinnelse i eller sendt fra India til bruk som næringsmiddel når Norge er innførselssted i EØS-området. Dette omfatter også produkter som blant annet går under varenummer ex 14.04.9000.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/1/ledd/2">Forskriften omfatter ikke personlige forsendelser beregnet på privat bruk.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/p2">
      <pverdi>§ 2.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Importbetingelser for paanblader fra India</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/2/ledd/1">EØS-avtalens vedlegg I kapittel I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2016/166) om særlige importbetingelser ved import av næringsmidler som består av eller inneholder paanblader ('Piper betle') fra India og endring av forordning (EF) nr. 669/2009 gjelder som forskrift med de tilpasninger som følger av vedlegg I og II, protokoll 1 til avtalen og avtalen for øvrig.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/p3">
      <pverdi>§ 3.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Utpekte importsteder</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/3/ledd/1">Mattilsynets grensekontrollstasjoner ved Oslo lufthavn, Oslo havn, Borg havn og Larvik havn utpekes som innførselssteder i henhold til forordning (EU) 2016/166 artikkel 3.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/3/ledd/2">Driftsansvarlig for næringsmiddelforetaket eller dennes representant skal fremstille forsendelsen for kontroll ved ett av disse importstedene.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/p4">
      <pverdi>§ 4.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Gebyr</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/4/ledd/1">Driftsansvarlig for næringsmiddelforetaket eller dennes representant skal betale gebyr for den offentlige kontrollen ved import av forsendelser av næringsmidler.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2">For import av forsendelser av næringsmidler skal det betales:
<liste id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/a/avsnitt/1">kr 1470,- per forsendelse for dokumentkontroll,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/b/avsnitt/1">kr 735,- per time eller kr 365,- per påbegynt halvtime når det gjennomføres identitetskontroll og fysisk kontroll av forsendelsen, og</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/c/avsnitt/1">kostnadene for analyseprøvene for forsendelsen.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/5" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/p5">
      <pverdi>§ 5.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Tilsyn og vedtak</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/5/ledd/1">Mattilsynet fører tilsyn og kan fatte nødvendige enkeltvedtak, jf. matloven § 23, for å oppnå etterlevelse av bestemmelser gitt i eller i medhold av denne forskriften. Mattilsynet kan også fatte enkeltvedtak i henhold til matloven § 24 til § 26.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/6" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/p6">
      <pverdi>§ 6.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Straff</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/6/ledd/1">Overtredelse av bestemmelser gitt i denne forskriften eller enkeltvedtak gitt i medhold av forskriften, er straffbart i henhold til matloven § 28.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/7" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/p7">
      <pverdi>§ 7.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Ikrafttredelse</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/7/ledd/1">Denne forskriften trer i kraft straks.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/k1">
      <kverdi/>
      <ktittel> Forordninger</ktittel>
      <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/1/overskrift/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/k1/?2">
        <kverdi/>
        <ktittel> Forordning (EU) 2016/166</ktittel>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/1/overskrift/2/ledd/1">Nedenfor gjengis til informasjon EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kapittel I del 7.1 nr. 13 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2016/166) med de endringer og tillegg som følger av EØS-tilpasningen av rettsakten i samsvar med vedlegg I og II, og protokoll I til EØS-avtalen.</ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/1/overskrift/2/ledd/2">Helsesertifikatet nevnt i artikkel 5 finnes under vedlegget i pdf-filen nedenfor under avsnittet Forordninger i PDF.</ledd>
        <forordning>
          <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166">
            <kverdi/>
            <ktittel align="center"> COMMISSION IMPLEMENTING REGULATION (EU) 2016.166 <br/> of 8 February 2016 <br/> laying down specific conditions applicable to the import of foodstuffs containing or consisting of betel leaves ('Piper betle') from India and amending Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 <br/></ktittel>
            <marg niv="1" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/marg/1">(Text with EEA relevance)
<br/></marg>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/1">THE EUROPEAN COMMISSION,</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/2">Having regard to the Treaty on the Functioning of the European Union,</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/3">Having regard to Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 28 January 2002 laying down the general principles and requirements of food law, establishing the European Food Safety Authority and laying down procedures in matters of food safety,<fref id="/fotnote/1">1</fref> and in particular Article 53(1)(b)(ii) thereof,</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/4">Having regard to Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 29 April 2004 on official controls performed to ensure the verification of compliance with feed and food law, animal health and animal welfare rules,<fref id="2">2</fref> and in particular Article 15(5) thereof,</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5">Whereas:
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/1"><lverdi>(1)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/1/avsnitt/1">Article 53 of Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 provides for the possibility to adopt appropriate Union emergency measures for feed and food imported from a third country in order to protect human health, animal health and the environment, where the risk cannot be contained satisfactorily by means of measures taken by the Member States individually.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/2"><lverdi>(2)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/2/avsnitt/1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 669/2009<fref id="3">3</fref> provides for an increased level of official controls on imports of certain feed and food of non-animal origin listed in Annex I to that Regulation. Betel leaves (Piper betle L.) originating from India are subject as of 1 April 2014 to an increased frequency of official controls as regards the presence of many Salmonella strains.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/3"><lverdi>(3)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/3/avsnitt/1">The results from the increased frequency of controls carried out by the Member States in the framework of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 on those foodstuffs show a continuous high frequency of non-compliance with microbiological criteria for foodstuffs established in Union legislation. Since 2011, around 90 notifications<fref id="4">4</fref> have been issued to the Rapid Alert System for Food and Feed due to the presence of a wide range of pathogenic Salmonella strains in foodstuffs containing or consisting of betel leaves originating in or consigned from India.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/4"><lverdi>(4)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/4/avsnitt/1">Those results provide evidence that the import of those foodstuffs constitutes a risk for human health. Despite the increased frequency of controls at Union borders in place the situation has been not improved. Furthermore, the Indian authorities have not provided a concrete and satisfactory action plan to remediate the shortcomings and deficiencies in the production and control systems, despite the European Commission's explicit request.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/5"><lverdi>(5)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/5/avsnitt/1">To protect human health in the Union, it is necessary to provide for additional guarantees in relation to those foodstuffs from India. Therefore all consignments of betel leaves from India should be accompanied by a health certificate stating that those foodstuffs were produced in line with the hygiene provisions set up in Regulation (EC) No 852/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council,<fref id="5">5</fref> sampled and analysed for the presence of Salmonella and were found compliant with Union legislation, and by the results of the analytical tests.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/6"><lverdi>(6)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/6/avsnitt/1">It is appropriate to exclude non-commercial consignments from the application of the provisions of this Regulation.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/7"><lverdi>(7)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/7/avsnitt/1">The sampling and the analysis of consignments should be performed in accordance with the relevant Union legislation. Commission Regulation (EC) No 2073/2005<fref id="6">6</fref> lays down both the microbiological criteria for foodstuffs and the provisions on sampling for the official control of microbiological criteria for foodstuffs applicable in the Union.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/8"><lverdi>(8)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/8/avsnitt/1">The Indian authorities have informed the Commission of the name of the competent authority whose authorised representative is entitled to sign the health certificate.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/9"><lverdi>(9)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/9/avsnitt/1">Regulation (EU) No 669/2009 should be amended accordingly.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/10"><lverdi>(10)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/5/liste/10/avsnitt/1">The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on Plants, Animals, Food and Feed,
<fotnote id="/fotnote/1">1 OJ L 31, 1.2.2002, p. 1.</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/2">2 OJ L 165, 30.4.2004, p. 1.</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/3">3 Commission Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 of 24 July 2009 implementing Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council as regards the increased level of official controls on imports of certain feed and food of non-animal origin and amending Decision 2006/504/EC (OJ L 194, 25.7.2009, p. 11).</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/4">4 From 2011 till 15 October 2015 (12 in 2011, 6 in 2012, 13 in 2013, 17 in 2014 and 43 on 15.10.2015).</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/5">5 Regulation (EC) No 852/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 29 April 2004 on the hygiene of foodstuffs (OJ L 139, 30.4.2004, p. 1).</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/6">6 Commission Regulation (EC) No 2073/2005 of 15 November 2005 on microbiological criteria for foodstuffs (OJ L 338, 22.12.2005, p. 1).
<br/></fotnote></avsnitt></liste></ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/ledd/6">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</ledd>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g1">
              <pverdi>Article 1</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Scope</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/1/ledd/1">1. This Regulation shall apply to consignments of foodstuffs containing or consisting of betel leaves ('Piper betle L.' commonly known as 'Paan leaf' or 'Betel quid') including those declared under CN codes 1404 90 00, originating in or consigned from India, set out in Annex I to this Regulation.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/1/ledd/2">2. This Regulation shall not apply to consignments of foodstuffs referred to in paragraph 1 which are destined to a private person for personal consumption and use only. In case of doubt, the burden of proof lies with the recipient of the consignment.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g2">
              <pverdi>Article 2</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Definitions</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/2/ledd/1">For the purpose of this Regulation, the definitions laid down in Articles 2 and 3 of Regulation (EC) No 178/2002, Article 2 of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 and Article 3 of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 shall apply.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g3">
              <pverdi>Article 3</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Import into the Union</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/3/ledd/1">Consignments of foodstuff referred to in Article 1(1) may only be imported into the Union in accordance with the procedures laid down in this Regulation. Consignments of such foodstuff may only enter the Union through the Designated Point of Entry (DPE) as defined in Regulation (EC) No 669/2009.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g4">
              <pverdi>Article 4</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Results of sampling and analysis</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/4/ledd/1">1. Consignments of the foodstuff referred to in Article 1(1) shall be accompanied by the results of sampling and analysis performed by the competent authorities of India, to ascertain compliance with Union legislation on microbiological criteria of Salmonella, for the foodstuff referred to in Article 1(1).</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/4/ledd/2">2. The sampling referred to in paragraph 1 must be performed in accordance with Regulation (EC) No 2073/2005.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/5" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g5">
              <pverdi>Article 5</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Health certificate</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/5/ledd/1">1. The consignments shall also be accompanied by a health certificate in accordance with the model set out in Annex II.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/5/ledd/2">2. The health certificate shall be completed, signed and verified by an authorised representative of the competent authority of India.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/5/ledd/3">3. The health certificate shall be drawn up in the official language, or in one of the official languages, of the Member State where the DPE is located. However, a Member State may consent to health certificates being drawn up in another official language of the Union.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/6" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g6">
              <pverdi>Article 6</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Identification</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/6/ledd/1">Each consignment of the foodstuff referred to in Article 1(1) shall be identified with an identification code which corresponds to the identification code mentioned on the results of the sampling and analysis referred to in Article 4 and the health certificate referred to in Article 5. Each individual bag, or other packaging form, of the consignment shall be identified with that identification code.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/7" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g7">
              <pverdi>Article 7</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Prior notification of consignments</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/7/ledd/1">1. Food business operators or their representatives shall give prior notification of the estimated date and time of physical arrival of consignments of the foodstuff referred to in Article 1(1) to the competent authorities at the DPE and of the nature of the consignment.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/7/ledd/2">2. For the purpose of prior notification, they shall complete Part I of the common entry document (CED) laid down in Article 3(a) to Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 and transmit that document to the competent authority at the DPE, at least one working day prior to the physical arrival of the consignment.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/7/ledd/3">3. For the completion of the CED in application of this Regulation, food business operators shall take into account for the foodstuff referred to in Article 1(1), the notes for guidance for the CED laid down in Annex II to Regulation (EC) No 669/2009.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g8">
              <pverdi>Article 8</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Official controls</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/1">1. The competent authority at the DPE shall carry out documentary checks on each consignment of the foodstuff referred to in Article 1(1) to ascertain compliance with the requirements laid down in Articles 4 and 5.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/2">2. The identity and physical checks on the foodstuff referred to in Article 1(1) of this Regulation shall be carried out in accordance with Articles 8, 9 and 19 of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 at the frequency set out in Annex I to this Regulation.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/3">3. After completion of the checks, the competent authorities shall:
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/3/liste/a"><lverdi>(a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/3/liste/a/avsnitt/1">complete the relevant entries of Part II of the CED;</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/3/liste/b"><lverdi>(b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/3/liste/b/avsnitt/1">join the results of sampling and analysis carried out in accordance with paragraph 2 of this Article;</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/3/liste/c"><lverdi>(c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/3/liste/c/avsnitt/1">provide and fill the CED reference number on the CED;</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/3/liste/d"><lverdi>(d)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/3/liste/d/avsnitt/1">stamp and sign the original of the CED;</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/3/liste/e"><lverdi>(e)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/3/liste/e/avsnitt/1">make and retain a copy of the signed and stamped CED.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/8/ledd/4">4. The original of the CED and of the health certificate with the accompanying results of sampling and analysis referred to in Article 4 shall accompany the consignment during its transport until it is released for free circulation. For foodstuff referred to in Article 1(1), in case of authorisation of onward transportation of the consignments pending the results of the physical checks, a certified copy of the original CED shall be issued for that purpose.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/9" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g9">
              <pverdi>Article 9</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Splitting of a consignment</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/9/ledd/1">1. Consignments shall not be split until all official controls have been completed, and the CED has been fully completed by the competent authorities as provided for in Article 8.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/9/ledd/2">2. In the case of subsequent splitting of the consignment, an authenticated copy of the CED shall accompany each part of the consignment during its transport until it is released for free circulation.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/10" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g10">
              <pverdi>Article 10</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Release for free circulation</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/10/ledd/1">The release for free circulation of consignments shall be subject to the presentation (physically or electronically) by the food business operators or their representative to the custom authorities of a CED duly completed by the competent authority once all official controls have been carried out and favourable results from physical checks, where such checks are required, are known. The custom authorities shall only release the consignment for free circulation if a favourable decision by the competent authority is indicated in box II.14 and signed in box II.21 of the CED.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/11" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g11">
              <pverdi>Article 11</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Non-compliance</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/11/ledd/1">If the official controls establish non-compliance with the relevant Union legislation, the competent authority shall complete Part III of the CED and action shall be taken pursuant to Articles 19, 20 and 21 of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/12" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g12">
              <pverdi>Article 12</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Reports</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/12/ledd/1">Member States shall submit to the Commission every three months a report of all analytical results of official controls on consignments of foodstuff pursuant to this Regulation. That report shall be submitted during the month following each quarter.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/12/ledd/2">The report shall include the following information:
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/12/ledd/2/liste/1"><lverdi>-</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/12/ledd/2/liste/1/avsnitt/1">the number of consignments imported,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/12/ledd/2/liste/2"><lverdi>-</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/12/ledd/2/liste/2/avsnitt/1">the number of consignments subjected to sampling for analysis,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/12/ledd/2/liste/3"><lverdi>-</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/12/ledd/2/liste/3/avsnitt/1">the results of the checks as provided for in Article 8(2).</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/13" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g13">
              <pverdi>Article 13</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Costs</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/13/ledd/1">All costs resulting from the official controls including sampling, analysis, storage and any measures taken following noncompliance, shall be borne by the food business operators.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/14" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g14">
              <pverdi>Article 14</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Transitional measures</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/14/ledd/1">By way of derogation from Articles 4(1) and 5(1), Member States shall authorise the imports of consignments of food referred to in Article 1(1) which left the country of origin prior to the entry into force of this Regulation without being accompanied by a health certificate and the results of sampling and analysis.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/15" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g15">
              <pverdi>Article 15</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Amendment of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/15/ledd/1">Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 is amended in accordance with Annex III to this Regulation.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/16" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/g16">
              <pverdi>Article 16</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Entry into force</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/16/ledd/1">This Regulation shall enter into force on the third day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/16/ledd/2">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/16/ledd/3">Done at Brussels, 8 February 2016.
<br/></ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/16/ledd/4">
                <i>For the Commission</i>
              </ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/16/ledd/5">
                <i>The President</i>
                <marg niv="1" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/artikkel/16/ledd/5/marg/1">Jean-Claude JUNCKER</marg>
              </ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/vedlegg/i" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/vi">
              <kverdi/>
              <ktittel align="center"> Vedlegg I til forordning (EU) 2016/166</ktittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/vedlegg/i/ledd/1">Food of non-animal origin subject to the measures provided for in this Regulation:</ledd>
              <table niv="1" frame="1">
                <thgroup cols="6" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
                  <colspec colname="1" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="2" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="3" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="4" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="5" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="6" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <tbody>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">
                        <i>Fôrvarer og næringsmidler (tiltenkt bruk)</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">
                        <i>CN Code</i>
                        <fref id="*">*</fref>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">
                        <i>Norsk varenummer</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="4">
                        <i>Opprinnelsesstat eller avsenderstat</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="5">
                        <i>Risiko</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="6">
                        <i>Hyppighet av fysiske kontroller og identitetskontroller (%)</i>
                      </entry>
                    </row>
                  </tbody>
                </thgroup>
                <tgroup cols="6" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
                  <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="2" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="3" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="4" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="5" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="6" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <tbody>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Betelblader (paanblader) (<i>Piper betle L.) (næringsmidler)</i> </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">ex 1404 90 00 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">ex 14.04.9000 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4">India </entry>
                      <entry colname="5">Salmonella<fref id="**">**</fref> </entry>
                      <entry colname="6">10 </entry>
                    </row>
                  </tbody>
                </tgroup>
              </table>
              <fotnote id="/fotnote/*">* Når bare visse produkter i en underposisjon skal undersøkes, og det ikke finnes noen særskilt varenummer i tolltariffen, står det «ex» foran underposisjonen.</fotnote>
              <fotnote id="/fotnote/**">** Referansemetode EN/ISO 6579 eller annen sertifisert metode som er vurdert mot denne i henhold til artikkel 5 i forordning (EF) nr. 2073/2005 (OJ L 338, 22.12.2005, s. 1).</fotnote>
            </kapittel>
            <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/vedlegg/ii" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/vii">
              <kverdi/>
              <ktittel align="center"> Vedlegg II til forordning (EU) 2016/166</ktittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/vedlegg/ii/ledd/1">For helsesertifikatet for forordning (EU) 2016/166 se pdf-filen nedenfor under avsnittet Forordninger i PDF.</ledd>
            </kapittel>
            <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/vedlegg/iii" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/?1/?2/y2016.166/viii">
              <kverdi/>
              <ktittel align="center"> Vedlegg III til forordning (EU) 2016/166</ktittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2016.166/vedlegg/iii/ledd/1">In Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 669/2009, the following entry is deleted:</ledd>
              <table niv="1" frame="1">
                <thgroup cols="6" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
                  <colspec colname="1" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="2" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="3" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="4" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="5" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="6" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <tbody>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">
                        <i>Fôrvarer og næringsmidler (tiltenkt bruk)</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">
                        <i>CN Code</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">
                        <i>Norsk varenummer</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="4">
                        <i>Opprinnelsesstat eller avsenderstat</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="5">
                        <i>Risiko</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="6">
                        <i>Hyppighet av fysiske kontroller og identitetskontroller (%)</i>
                      </entry>
                    </row>
                  </tbody>
                </thgroup>
                <tgroup cols="6" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
                  <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="2" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="3" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="4" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="5" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="6" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <tbody>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Betelblader (paanblader) (<i>Piper betle L.) (næringsmidler)</i> </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">ex 1404 90 00 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">ex 14.04.9000 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4">India </entry>
                      <entry colname="5">Salmonella<sup>**</sup> </entry>
                      <entry colname="6">50 </entry>
                    </row>
                  </tbody>
                </tgroup>
              </table>
            </kapittel>
          </kapittel>
        </forordning>
      </kapittel>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2016-02-12-149/k3">
      <kverdi/>
      <ktittel> Forordninger i PDF</ktittel>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/3/ledd/1">Nedenfor gjengis forordning (EU) 2016/166.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/3/ledd/2">For å lese forordning (EU) 2016/166, med sertifikatet i vedlegget, på engelsk se her: <lenke url="https://lovdata.no/static//ltavd1/filer/grafikk/32016r0166e.pdf"><img src="/ltavd1/filer/grafikk/pdf.gif" alt="ikon"/></lenke></ledd>
    </kapittel>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
