<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2014-12-12-1798" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-12-12-1798">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2014-12-12-1798</id>
    <dato>12.12.2014 nr. 1798</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2014-12-12</dato>
    <publisert>I 2014 hefte 17 s 2871</publisert>
    <ikraft>12.12.2014</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2014-12-12</ikraft>
    <departement>Utenriksdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="for-2014-08-15-1076-§23">F15.08.2014 nr. 1076 § 23</ref>,</hjemmel>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2014-08-15-1076</endrer>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2014-1326</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Endr. i forskrift om tiltak vedr. Ukrainas integritet mv.</korttittel>
    <korttittel>4 Endr. i forskrift om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet, uavhengighet og stabilitet (Nr. 1798)</korttittel>
    <tittel>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet, uavhengighet og stabilitet</tittel>
    <marg niv="1" id="/marg/1"><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Utenriksdepartementet 12. desember 2014 med hjemmel i forskrift 15. august 2014 nr. 1076 om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet, uavhengighet og stabilitet § 23.</marg>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/i" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-12-12-1798/ki">
      <kverdi>I</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/1">I forskrift 15. august 2014 nr. 1076 om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet, uavhengighet og stabilitet gjøres følgende endringer:
<br/></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2">I vedlegg I gjøres følgende endringer:
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2/marg/1">Følgende fysiske og juridiske personer skal legges til listen:
<br/></marg></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3">
        <i>Persons</i>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/4">
        <i>120. Serhiy KOZYAKOV (aka Sergey Kozyakov)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5">
        <i>Ceргeй Кoзьякoв</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5/marg/1">29.09.1982
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5/marg/2">In his capacity as «Head of the Luhansk Central Election Commission» he is responsible for organising the so called «elections» of 2 November 2014 in the so called «Luhansk People's Republic». These «elections» are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal. In taking on and acting in this capacity, and in organising the illegal «elections», he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5/marg/3">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6">
        <i>121. Oleg AKIMOV (aka Oleh AKIMOV)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7">
        <i>Oлeг Aкимoв</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7/marg/1">Deputy of the «Luhansk Economic Union» in the «National Council» of the «Luhansk People's Republic». Stood as a candidate in the so called «elections», of 2 November 2014 to the post of the «Head» of the so called «Luhansk People's Republic». These «elections» are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal. In taking on and acting in this capacity, and in participating formally as a candidate in the illegal «elections», he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7/marg/2">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/8">
        <i>122. Larisa AIRAPETYAN (aka Larysa Ayrapetyan, Larisa Airapetyan or Larysa Airapetyan)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9">
        <i>Лариcа Aйрапeтян</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/marg/1">«Health Minister» of the so called «Luhansk People's Republic». Stood as a candidate in the so called «elections» of 2 November 2014 to the post of the «Head» of the so called «Luhansk People's Republic». These «elections» are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal. In taking on and acting in this capacity, and in participating formally as a candidate in the illegal «elections», she has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/marg/2">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10">
        <i>123. Yuriy SIVOKONENKO (aka Yuriy Sivokonenko, Yury Sivokonenko, Yury Syvokonenko)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/11">
        <i>ЮрийBиктoрoвич Cивoкoнeнкo</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/11/marg/1">Member of the «Parliament» of the so called «Donetsk People's Republic» and works in the Union of veterans of the Donbass Berkut. Stood as a candidate in the so called «elections» of 2 November 2014 to the post of the Head of the so called «Donetsk People's Republic». These elections are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal. In taking on and acting in this capacity, and in participating formally as a candidate in the illegal «elections», he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/11/marg/2">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/12">
        <i>124. Aleksandr KOFMAN (aka Oleksandr Kofman)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/13">
        <i>Aлeкcандр Игoрeвич Кoфман</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/13/marg/1">«First deputy speaker» of the «Parliament» of the so called «Donetsk People's Republic». Stood as a candidate in the so called illegal «elections» of 2 November 2014 to the post of the Head of the so called «Donetsk People's Republic». These elections are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal. In taking on and acting in this capacity, and in participating formally as a candidate in the illegal «elections», he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/13/marg/2">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/14">
        <i>125. Ravil KHALIKOV</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/15">
        <i>Pавиль Xаликoв</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/15/marg/1">«First Deputy Prime Minister» and previous «Prosecutor- General» of the so called «Donetsk People's Republic». In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/15/marg/2">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/16">
        <i>126. Dmitry SEMYONOV</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/17">
        <i>Дмитрий Ceмeнoв</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/17/marg/1">«Deputy Prime Minster for Finances» of the so called «Luhansk People's Republic». In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/17/marg/2">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18">
        <i>127. Oleg BUGROV</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/marg/1">«Defense Minister» of the so called Luhansk People's Republic. In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/marg/2">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/19">
        <i>128. Lesya LAPTEVA</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/20">
        <i>Лecя Лаптeва</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/20/marg/1">«Minister of Education, Science, Culture and Religion» of the so-called «Luhansk People's Republic». In taking on and acting in this capacity, she has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/20/marg/2">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/21">
        <i>129. Yevgeniy Eduardovich MIKHAYLOV (aka Yevhen Eduardovych Mychaylov)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/22">
        <i>Eвгeний Эдyардoвич Mиxайлoв</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/22/marg/1">17.03.1963, Arkhangelsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/22/marg/2">«Head of the administration for governmental affairs» of the so-called «Donetsk People's Republic». In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/22/marg/3">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/23">
        <i>130. Ihor Vladymyrovych KOSTENOK (aka Igor Vladimirovich Kostenok)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/24">
        <i>Игoрь Bладимирoвич Кocтeнoк</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/24/marg/1">«Minister of Education» of the so-called «Donetsk People's Republic». In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/24/marg/2">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/25">
        <i>131. Yevgeniy Vyacheslavovich ORLOV(aka Yevhen Vyacheslavovych Orlov)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/26">
        <i> Eвгeний Bячecлавoвич Oрлoв</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/26/marg/1">Member of the «National Council» of the so-called «Donetsk's People's Republic». In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/26/marg/2">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/27">
        <i>132. Vladyslav Nykolayevych DEYNEGO (aka Vladislav Nykolayevich Deynego)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/28">
        <i>Bладиcлав Дeйнeгo</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/28/marg/1">«Deputy Head» of the «People's Council» of the so-called «Luhansk People's Republic». In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/28/marg/2">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/29">
        <i>Entities</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/30">
        <i>24. Donetsk Republic (Public organisation)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/31">
        <i>Дoнeцкая рecпyблика</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/31/marg/1">Public «organisation» that presented candidates in the so called «elections» of the so called «Donetsk People's Republic» on 2 November 2014. These «elections» are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal. In participating formally in the illegal «elections» it has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine. Headed by Alexander ZAKHARCHENKO and founded by Andriy PURGIN.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/31/marg/2">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/32">
        <i>25. Peace to Luhansk Region (Russian: Mir Luganschine)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/33">
        <i>Mир Лyганщинe</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/33/marg/1">Public «organisation» that presented candidates in the so called «elections» of the so called «Luhansk People's Republic» 2 November 2014. These «elections» are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal.</marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/34">In participating formally in the illegal «elections» it has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine. Headed by Igor PLOTNITSKY.
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/34/marg/1">29.11.2014
<br/></marg></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/35">
        <i>26. Free Donbass (aka «Free Donbas», «Svobodny Donbass»)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/36">
        <i>Cвoбoдный Дoнбаcc</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/36/marg/1">Public «organisation» that presented candidates in the so called «elections» of the so called «Donetsk People's Republic» 2 November 2014. These elections are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal.</marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/37">In participating formally in the illegal «elections» it has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/37/marg/1">29.11.2014
<br/></marg></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/38">
        <i>27. People's Union (Narodny Soyuz)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/39">
        <i>Hарoдный coюз</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/39/marg/1">Public «organisation» that presented candidates in the so called «elections» of the so called «Luhansk People's Republic» 2 November 2014. These elections are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal. In participating formally in the illegal «elections» it has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/39/marg/2">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/40">
        <i>28. Luhansk Economic Union (Luganskiy Ekonomicheskiy Soyuz)</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/41">
        <i>Лyганcкий экoнoмичecкий coюз</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/41/marg/1">«Social organisation» that presented candidates in the illegal so called «elections» of the so called «Luhansk People's Republic» 2 November 2014. Nominated a candidate, Oleg AKIMOV, to be «Head» of the so called «Luhansk People's Republic». These «elections» are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal.</marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/42">In participating formally in the illegal «elections» it has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and to further destabilise Ukraine.
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/42/marg/1">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/42/marg/2">Følgende endringer gjøres til listeføring nr. 107:
<br/></marg></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/43">
        <i>107. Vladimir Volfovich ZHIRINOVSKY</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/44">
        <i>Bладимир Boльфoвич Жиринoвcкий</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/44/marg/1">Born on 25.4.1946 in Almaty (formerly also known as Alma-Ata), Kazakhstan.</marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/45">Member of the Council of the State Duma; leader of the LDPR party. He actively supported the use of Russian Armed Forces in Ukraine and annexation of Crimea. He has actively called for the split of Ukraine. He signed, on behalf of the LDPR party he chairs, an agreement with the so-called «Donetsk People's Republic».
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/45/marg/1">12.9.2014</marg></ledd>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/ii" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-12-12-1798/kii">
      <kverdi>II</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/ii/ledd/1">Forskriften trer i kraft straks.</ledd>
    </kapittel>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
