<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2015-12-01-1448" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-12-01-1448">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2015-12-01-1448</id>
    <dato>01.12.2015 nr. 1448</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2015-12-01</dato>
    <publisert>I 2015 hefte 14 s 2316</publisert>
    <ikraft>01.12.2015</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2015-12-01</ikraft>
    <departement>Utenriksdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="for-2006-12-15-1405-§6">F15.12.2006 nr. 1405 § 6</ref>, <ref id="lov-1968-06-07-4">L07.06.1968 nr. 4</ref>, <ref id="lov-2001-04-27-14">L27.04.2001 nr. 14</ref></hjemmel>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2006-12-15-145</endrer>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2015-1242</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Endr. i forskrift om sanksjoner mv. mot Nord-Korea</korttittel>
    <korttittel>4 Endr. i forskrift om sanksjoner og restriktive tiltak mot Nord-Korea (Nr. 1448)</korttittel>
    <tittel>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om sanksjoner og restriktive tiltak mot Nord-Korea</tittel>
    <redaksjonell_note><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Utenriksdepartementet 1. desember 2015 med hjemmel i forskrift 15. desember 2006 nr. 1405 om sanksjoner og restriktive tiltak mot Nord-Korea § 6.</redaksjonell_note>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/i" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-12-01-1448/ki">
      <kverdi>I</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/1">I forskrift 15. desember 2006 nr. 1405 om sanksjoner og restriktive tiltak mot Nord-Korea gjøres følgende endringer:
<br/></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2">Gjeldende punkt C i vedlegg V til vedlegg A oppheves. Nytt punkt C i vedlegg V til vedlegg A skal lyde:</ledd>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2/avsnitt/1">C. Natural persons referred to in Article 6(2)(b):</avsnitt>
      <table niv="1" frame="1">
        <thgroup cols="4" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="2*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="34*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1"># </entry>
              <entry colname="2">
                <i>Name (and possible aliases)</i>
              </entry>
              <entry colname="3">
                <i>Identifying information</i>
              </entry>
              <entry colname="4">
                <i>Reasons</i>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </thgroup>
        <tgroup cols="4" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="2*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="34*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">1. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">JON Il-chun </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 24.8.1941 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">In February of 2010 KIM Tong-un was discharged from his office as director of Office 39, which is, among other things, in charge of purchasing goods out of the DPRK diplomatic representations bypassing sanctions. He was replaced by JON Il-chun. JON Il-chun is also said to be one of the leading figures in the State Development Bank. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">2. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">KIM Tong-un </entry>
              <entry colname="3"/>
              <entry colname="4">Former director of 'Office 39' of the Central Committee of the Workers' Party, which is involved in proliferation financing. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">3. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">KIM Tong-Myo'ng
<br/> (alias: Kim Chin-so'k) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Year of birth: 1964
<br/> Nationality: North Korean </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Kim Tong-Myo'ng acts on behalf of Tanchon Commercial Bank (entity designated by the United Nations, 24.4.2009).
<br/> Kim Dong Myong has held various positions within Tanchon since at least 2002 and is currently Tanchon's president. He has also played a role in managing Amroggang's affairs (owned or controlled by Tanchon Commercial Bank) using the alias Kim Chin-so'k. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">4. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">KIM Il-Su </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Rahlstedter Strasse 83 a, 22149 Hamburg
<br/> Date of birth: 2.9.1965
<br/> Place of birth: Pyongyangm DPRK </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Authorised plenipotentiary representative of the EU-designated KNIC GmbH, acting on behalf of KNIC or at its direction. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">5. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">KANG Song-Nam </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Rahlstedter Strasse 83 a, 22149 Hamburg
<br/> Date of birth: 5.7.1972
<br/> Place of birth: Pyongyangm DPRK </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Authorised plenipotentiary representative of the EU-designated KNIC GmbH, acting on behalf of KNIC or at its direction. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">6. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">CHOE Chun-Sik </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Rahlstedter Strasse 83 a, 22149 Hamburg
<br/> Date of birth: 23.12.1963
<br/> Place of birth: Pyongyangm DPRK
<br/> Passport No 745132109 Valid until: 12.2.2020 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Authorised plenipotentiary representative of the EU-designated KNIC GmbH, acting on behalf of KNIC or at its direction. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">7. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">SIN Kyu-Nam </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 12.9.1972 Place of birth: Pyongyangm DPRK
<br/> Passport No: PO472132950 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Head of department of KNIC Headquarters in Pyongyang and former authorised plenipotentiary representative of KNIC GmbH Hamburg. Acting on behalf of KNIC or at its direction. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">8. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">PAK Chun-San </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 18.12.1953
<br/> Place of birth: Pyongyangm DPRK
<br/> Passport No: PS472220097 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Head of department of KNIC Headquarters in Pyongyang and former authorised plenipotentiary representative of KNIC GmbH Hamburg. Acting on behalf of KNIC or at its direction. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">9. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">SO Tong Myong </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 10.9.1956 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Managing Director of KNIC GmbH Hamburg, acting on behalf of KNIC or at its direction. </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <br/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3">Gjeldende punkt D i vedlegg V til vedlegg A oppheves. Nytt punkt D i vedlegg V til vedlegg A skal lyde:</ledd>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/avsnitt/1">D. Legal persons, entities or bodies referred to in Article 6(2)(b):</avsnitt>
      <table niv="1" frame="1">
        <thgroup cols="4" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="2*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="34*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">
                <i>#</i>
              </entry>
              <entry colname="2">
                <i>Name (and possible aliases)</i>
              </entry>
              <entry colname="3">
                <i>Identifying information</i>
              </entry>
              <entry colname="4">
                <i>Reasons</i>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </thgroup>
        <tgroup cols="4" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="2*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="34*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">- </entry>
              <entry colname="2"/>
              <entry colname="3"/>
              <entry colname="4"> </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">3. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Korea Daesong Bank
<br/> (alias: Choson Taesong Unhaeng; Taesong Bank) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Address: Segori-dong, Gyongheung St., Potonggang District, PyongyangPhone: 850 2 381 8221Phone: 850 2 18111 ext. 8221Fax: 850 2 381 4576 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">North Korean financial institution that is directly subordinated to Office 39 and is involved in facilitating North Korea's proliferation financing projects. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">4. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Korea Daesong General Trading Corporation
<br/> (alias: Daesong Trading; Daesong Trading Company; Korea Daesong Trading Company; Korea Daesong Trading Corporation) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Address: Pulgan Gori Dong 1, Potonggang District, PyongyangPhone: 850 2 18111 ext. 8204/8208Phone: 850 2 381 8208/4188 Fax: 850 2 381 4431/4432 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Company that is subordinated to Office 39 and is used to facilitate foreign transactions on behalf of Office 39.
<br/> Office 39's Director of Office, Kim Tong-un is listed in Annex V of Council Regulation (EU) No 329/2007. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">5. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Korea Kwangson Banking Corp. (KKBC)
<br/> (alias: Korea Kwangson Banking Corp; KKBC) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Address: Jungson-dong, Sungri Street, Central District, Pyongyang </entry>
              <entry colname="4">A subordinate acting on behalf of or at the direction of, owned or controlled by the Korea Ryonbong General Corporation (entity designated by the United Nations, 24.4.2009).
<br/> Provides financial services in support of both Tanchon Commercial Bank (entity designated by the United Nations, 24.4.2009) and Korea Hyoksin Trading Corporation (entity designated by the United Nations, 16.7.2009);
<br/> Since 2008, Tanchon Commercial Bank has been utilizing KKBC to facilitate funds transfers likely amounting to millions of dollars, including transfers involving Korea Mining Development Trading Corporation (KOMID) (entity designated by the United Nations, 24.4.2009) related funds from Burma to China in 2009.
<br/> Additionally, Hyoksin, which the UN described as being involved in the development of weapons of mass destruction, sought to use KKBC in connection with a purchase of dual-use equipment in 2008. KKBC has at least one overseas branch in Dandong, China. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">6. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Office 39 of The Korean Workers's Party
<br/> (alias: Office #39; Office No. 39; Bureau 39; Central Committee; Third Floor Division 39.) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Address: Second KWP Government Building (Korean: Ch'o'ngsa), Chungso'ng, Urban Tower (Korean'Dong), Chung Ward, Pyongyang; Chung-Guyok (Central District), Sosong Street, Kyongrim-Dong, Pyongyang; Changgwang Street, Pyongyang. </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Office 39 of the Korean Workers' Party engages in illicit economic activity to support the North Korean government. It has branches throughout the nation that raise and manage funds and is responsible for earning foreign currency for North Korea's Korean Workers' Party senior leadership through illicit activities such as narcotics trafficking. Office 39 controls a number of entities inside North Korea and abroad through which it conducts numerous illicit activities including the production, smuggling, and distribution of narcotics. Office 39 has also been involved in the attempted procurement and transfer to North Korea of luxury goods.
<br/> Office 39 figures among the most important organisations assigned with currency and merchandise acquisition. The entity is said to be directly under the command of KIM Jong-il; it controls several trading companies some of which are active in illicit activites, among them Daesong General Bureau, part of Daesong group, the largest company group of the country. Office 39 according to some sources entertains representation office in Rome, Beijing, Bangkok, Singapore, Hongkong and Dubai. To the outside Office 39 changes name and appearance regularly. The director of Office 39, JON Il-chun is already listed on the EU sanction list.
<br/> Office 39 produced methamphetamine in Sangwon, South Pyongan Province and was also involved in the distribution of methamphetamine to small-scale North Korean smugglers for distribution through China and South Korea. Office 39 also operates poppy farms in North Hamkyo'ng Province and North Pyongan Province and produces opium and heroin in Hamhu'ng and Nachin.
<br/> In 2009, Office 39 was involved in the failed attempt to purchase and export to North Korea - through China - two Italian-made luxury yachts worth more than $15 million. Halted by Italian authorities, the attempted export of the yachts destined for Kim Jong-il was in violation of United Nations sanctions against North Korea under UNSCR 1718, which specifically requireMember States to prevent the supply, sale, or transfer of luxury goods to North Korea.
<br/> Office 39 previously used Banco Delta Asia to launder illicit proceeds. Banco Delta Asia was identified by the Treasury Department in September 2005 as a 'primary money laundering concern' under Section 311 of the USA PATRIOT Act, because it represented an unacceptable risk of money laundering and other financial crimes. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">7. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Korea National Insurance Company (KNIC) GmbH (alias Korea Foreign Insurance Company) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Rahlstedter Strasse 83 a, 22149 Hamburg </entry>
              <entry colname="4">KNIC GmnH, as a subsidiary controlled by KNIC headquarters in Pyongyang (address Haebangsan-dong, Central District, Pyongyang, DPRK), a government entity, is generating substantial foreign exchange revenue which is used to support the regime in North Korea. Those resources could contribute to the DPRK's nuclear-related, ballistic missile-related or other weapons of mass destruction-related programmes.
<br/> Furthermore, the KNIC headquarters Pyongyang is linked to Office 39 of the Korean Worker's Party, a designated entity. </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/ii" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-12-01-1448/kii">
      <kverdi>II</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/ii/ledd/1">Endringene trer i kraft straks.</ledd>
    </kapittel>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
