<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2015-10-02-1158" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-10-02-1158">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2015-10-02-1158</id>
    <dato>02.10.2015 nr. 1158</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2015-10-02</dato>
    <publisert>I 2015 hefte 11 s 1870</publisert>
    <ikraft>02.10.2015</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2015-10-02</ikraft>
    <departement>Utenriksdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="for-2007-02-09-149-§45">F09.02.2007 nr. 149 § 45</ref>, <ref id="lov-1968-06-07-4">L07.06.1968 nr. 4</ref>, <ref id="lov-2001-04-27-14">L27.04.2001 nr. 14</ref></hjemmel>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2007-02-09-149</endrer>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2015-0967</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Endr. i forskrift om sanksjoner og tiltak mot Iran</korttittel>
    <korttittel>4 Endr. i forskrift om sanksjoner og tiltak mot Iran (Nr. 1158)</korttittel>
    <tittel>Forskrift om endringer i forskrift om sanksjoner og tiltak mot Iran</tittel>
    <redaksjonell_note><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Utenriksdepartementet 2. oktober 2015 med hjemmel i forskrift 9. februar 2007 nr. 149 om sanksjoner og tiltak mot Iran § 45.</redaksjonell_note>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/i" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-10-02-1158/ki">
      <kverdi>I</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/1">I forskrift 9. februar 2007 nr. 149 om sanksjoner og tiltak mot Iran gjøres følgende endringer:
<br/></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2">§ 28a skal lyde:</ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3">Forbudene i § 23 nr. 2 og nr. 4 gjelder ikke handlinger og transaksjoner, som utføres med hensyn til enheter som er listet i bilag IX:
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/liste/a/avsnitt/1">som har rettigheter som følger av en opprinnelig tildeling av en produksjonsdelingsavtale, som omtalt i § 39, fra en annen suveren regjering enn den iranske før 27. oktober 2010, som gjelder handlinger og transaksjoner relatert til disse enheters deltakelse i nevnte avtale.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/liste/b/avsnitt/1">så langt nødvendig for oppfyllelse inntil 14. januar 2016 av kontrakter omtalt i § 12 nr. 1 bokstav b), forutsatt at disse handlingene og transaksjonene er forhåndsgodkjent av Utenriksdepartementet.
<br/></avsnitt></liste></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/4">Ny § 43b skal lyde:</ledd>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/4/avsnitt/1">§ 43b.</avsnitt>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5">1. Uten hensyn til de øvrige bestemmelsene i denne forskrift kan Utenriksdepartementet gi tillatelse til levering, salg eller overføring av produkter, materialer, utstyr, varer og teknologi og til yting av tilknyttet faglig bistand, opplæring, finansiell bistand, investeringer, formidlings- eller andre tjenester dersom de anser at dette er direkte forbundet med
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5/liste/a/avsnitt/1">endringen av to kaskader ved Fordow-anlegget til fremstilling av stabile isotoper,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5/liste/b/avsnitt/1">eksport av mer enn 300 kg anriket uran fra Iran i bytte mot naturlig uran, eller</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5/liste/c/avsnitt/1">moderniseringen av Arak-reaktoren basert på det avtalte konstruksjonsutkastet og den etterfølgende og endelige utformingen som er avtalt for denne reaktoren.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6">2. Utenriksdepartementets tillatelse i samsvar med nr. 1, skal påse
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6/liste/a/avsnitt/1">at all virksomhet finner sted i nøye samsvar med den overordnede felles handlingsplanen (Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action) av 14. juli 2015 (heretter kalt «handlingsplanen»),</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6/liste/b/avsnitt/1">at aktuelle krav angitt i punkt 22 bokstav c) i FNs sikkerhetsrådsresolusjon 2231 (2015) er oppfylt, og</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6/liste/c/avsnitt/1">at Utenriksdepartementet har ervervet og er i stand til effektivt å utøve retten til å kontrollere sluttbruken av alle leverte produkter og hvor den skal finne sted.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7">3. Utenriksdepartementet skal underrette
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7/liste/a/avsnitt/1">Sanksjonskomiteen og eventuelt den felles kommisjon, når denne er nedsatt, ti dager før tillatelse gis,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7/liste/b/avsnitt/1">Det internasjonale atomenergibyrået (IAEA) senest ti dager etter levering, salg eller overføring av produkter, materialer, utstyr, varer og teknologi angitt i punkt 22 bokstav e) i sikkerhetsrådsresolusjon 2231 (2015).
<br/></avsnitt></liste></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/8">Ny § 43c skal lyde:</ledd>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/8/avsnitt/1">§ 43c.</avsnitt>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9">1. Uten hensyn til de øvrige bestemmelsene i denne forskrift kan Utenriksdepartementet, i hvert enkelt tilfelle og i den utstrekning det er nødvendig av hensyn til gjennomføringen, gi tillatelse til overføringer og aktiviteter dersom
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/liste/a/avsnitt/1">de er direkte forbundet med gjennomføringen av kjernekraftrelaterte tiltak som angitt i nr. 15.1 til 15.11 i vedlegg V til handlingsplanen,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/liste/b/avsnitt/1">de er nødvendige for å kunne forberede gjennomføringen av handlingsplanen, eller</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/liste/c/avsnitt/1">Sanksjonskomiteen eventuelt har fastslått at de er i samsvar med målene i sikkerhetsrådsresolusjon 2231 (2015).</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10">2. Utenriksdepartementet skal, der det er aktuelt, fremlegge de planlagte tillatelser for Sanksjonskomiteen til godkjenning.
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/marg/1">I vedlegg IX ersattes informasjonen om følgende listeførte:</marg></ledd>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/avsnitt/1">I. Persons and entities involved in nuclear or ballistic missiles activities and persons and entities providing support to the Government of Iran</avsnitt>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/avsnitt/2">A. Persons</avsnitt>
      <table niv="1" frame="1">
        <tgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="10*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">32. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Babak Zanjani </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 12 March 1971 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Babak Zanjani has provided support for the financing of transactions in Iranian crude oil conducted by the Iranian Ministry of Petroleum, which is designated by the EU. In addition, he has assisted the Central Bank of Iran and the National Iranian Oil Company (NIOC), which are also designated by the EU, to evade the EU's restrictive measures.
<br/>He has been a facilitator for Iranian oil transactions and has made transfers of oil-related funds, notably through Naftiran Intertrade Company (NICO) and Hong Kong Intertrade, which are controlled by the Iranian Government and also designated by the EU.
<br/>In addition, he provided essential services to the Iranian Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) by enabling transfers of funds for the benefit of Khatam al-Anbiya, an IRGC-owned company subject to UN and EU sanctions. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">8.11.2014 </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/avsnitt/3">B. Entities</avsnitt>
      <table niv="1" frame="1">
        <tgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="10*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">4 (b). </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Persia International Bank Plc </entry>
              <entry colname="3">6 Lothbury, London Post Code: EC2R 7HH, United Kingdom </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Entity owned by designated entities Bank Mellat and Bank Tejarat. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">16.11.2013 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">6. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Bank Refah Kargaran (a.k.a. Bank Refah) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">40, North Shiraz Street, Mollasadra Ave., Vanak Sq., Tehran, Postal Code 19917, Iran Swift: REF AIRTH </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Entity providing support to the Government of Iran. It is 94 per cent owned by the Iranian Social Security Organisation, which in turn is controlled by the Government of Iran, and it provides banking services to government ministries. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">16.11.2013 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">8. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sina Bank </entry>
              <entry colname="3">No. 187, Avenue Motahhari Ave., Teheran, 1587998411, Iran
<br/>Tel: +9821 88532434-7, +9821 88532434-6
<br/>E-mail: infor@sinabank.ir
<br/>Website: <lenke url="http://www.sinabank.ir/">http://www.sinabank.ir/</lenke> </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Sina Bank is controlled by the Mostazafan Foundation, a major Iranian parastatal entity directly controlled by the Supreme Leader, and which has an 84 % shareholding in Sina Bank. It provides financial services to the Mostazafan Foundation and its group of subsidiary units and companies. Accordingly, Sina Bank provides financial support to the Government of Iran through the Mostazafan Foundation. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">26.7.2010 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">11. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Export Development Bank of Iran (EDBI) (including all branches and subsidiaries) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Export Development Building, 21st floor, Tose'e tower, 15th St, Ahmad Qasir Ave, Tehran - Iran, 15138-35711 next to the 15th Alley, Bokharest Street, Argentina Square, Tehran, Iran; Tose'e Tower, corner of 15th St, Ahmad Qasir Ave., Argentine Square, Tehran, Iran; No 129, 21's Khaled Eslamboli, No 1 Building, Tehran, Iran; C.R. No 86936 (Iran) </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Government-owned company which provides financial support to the Government of Iran. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">16.11.2013 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">21. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Iran Insurance Company (a.k.a. Bimeh Iran) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">121 Fatemi Ave., P.O. Box 14155-6363 Tehran, Iran P.O. Box 14155-6363, 107 Fatemi Ave., Tehran, Iran </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Government-owned company which provides financial support to the Government of Iran. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">16.11.2013 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">27. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Power Plants' Equipment Manufacturing Company (Saakhte Tajhizate Niroogahi) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">No. 10, Jahanara Alley, after Hemmat Bridge, Abbaspour St. (previously called Tavanir), Tehran, Post Code 1435733161, Iran </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Subordinate to AEOI and Novin Energy (both designated under UNSCR 1737). Involved in the development of nuclear reactors. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">26.7.2010 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">34. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Post Bank of Iran (a.k.a. Post Bank Iran, Post Bank) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">237, Motahari Ave., Tehran, Iran 1587618118 Website:
<lenke url="http://www.postbank.ir">www.postbank.ir</lenke> </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Company which is majority owned by the Government of Iran and provides financial support to the Government of Iran. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">16.11.2013 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">44. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Onerbank ZAO (a.k.a. Onerbank ZAT, Eftekhar Bank, Honor Bank, Honorbank, North European Bank) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Ulitsa Klary Tsetkin 51- 1, 220004, Minsk, Belarus </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Belarus-based bank owned by Bank Refah Kargaran, Bank Saderat and Bank Toseeh Saderat Iran </entry>
              <entry colname="5">23.5.2011 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">85. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Iranian Offshore Engineering &amp; Construction Co. (IOEC) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">18 Shahid Dehghani Street, Qarani Street, Tehran 19395-5999 Or: No 52 North Kheradmand Avenue (Corner of 6th Alley) Tehran, IRAN Web:
<lenke url="http://www.ioec.com/">http://www.ioec.com/</lenke> </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Important entity in the energy sector which provides substantial revenues to the Government of Iran. As such, IOEC provides financial and logistical support to the Government of Iran. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">16.11.2013 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">118. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">North Drilling Company (NDC) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">No 8 35th St., Alvand St., Argentine Sq.,Tehran, Iran, Tel. (+ 98) 2188785083-8 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">North Drilling provides financial support to the Government of Iran through being indirectly owned by the Mostazafan Foundation, a major Iranian parastatal entity controlled by the Government of Iran. North Drilling is an important entity in the energy sector which provides substantial revenues to the Government of Iran. Additionally, North Drilling has imported key equipment for the oil and gas industry, including prohibited goods. Therefore, North Drilling provides support for Iran's proliferation-sensitive nuclear activities. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">23.4.2014 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">132. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Naftiran Intertrade Company (a.k.a. Naftiran Trade Company) (NICO) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">(a) 5th Floor, Petropars Building, No. 35 Farhang Boulevard, Snadat Abad Avenue, Tehran, Iran
<br/> Tel: +98 21 22372486; +98 21 22374681; +98 21 22374678;
<br/> Fax: +98 21 22374678; +98 21 22372481
<br/> Email: info@naftiran.com
<br/> (b) Suite 17, Burlington House, St. Saviours Road, St. Helier, Jersey, UK </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Subsidiary (100 %) of the National Iranian Oil Company (NIOC). </entry>
              <entry colname="5">16.10.2012 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">133 </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Naftiran Intertrade Company Srl </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Avenue de la Tour-Haldimand, 6, 1009 Pully, Switzerland
<br/> Tel: +41 21 3106565
<br/> Fax: +41 21 3106566/67/72
<br/> Email: nico.finance@naftiran.ch </entry>
              <entry colname="4"><br/> Subsidiary (100 %) of the Naftiran Intertrade Company Ltd. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">16.10.2012 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">140. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">National Iranian Tanker Company (NITC) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">35 East Shahid Atefi Street, Africa Ave., 19177 Tehran, P.O. Box: 19395-4833, Tel: +98 21 23801, Email: info@nitc- tankers.com; all offices worldwide </entry>
              <entry colname="4">The National Iranian Tanker Company provides financial support to the Government of Iran through its shareholders the Iranian State Retirement Fund, the Iranian Social Security Organization, and the Oil Industry Employees Retirement and Savings Fund, which are State-controlled entities. Moreover, NITC is one of the largest operators of crude oil carriers in the world and one of the main transporters of Iranian crude oil. Accordingly, NITC provides logistical support to the Government of Iran through the transport of Iranian oil. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">16.10.2012 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">154. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sorinet Commercial Trust Bankers Ltd. (SCT) (a.k.a.: SCT Bankers; SCT Bankers Kish Company (PJS); SCT Bankers Company Branch; Sorinet Commercial Trust) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Sorinet Commercial Trust Bankers, Sadaf Tower, 3rd Floor, Suite No. 301, Kish Island, Iran Sorinet Commercial Trust Bankers, No.1808, 18th Floor, Grosvenor House Commercial Tower, Sheikh Zayed Road, Dubai, UAE, P.O. Box 31988
<br/>Tehran branch: Reahi Aiiey, First of Karaj, Maksous Road 9, Tehran, Iran. SWIFT codes: SCERIRTH KSH (Kish Island branch), SCTSAEA1 (Dubai branch), SCERIRTH (Tehran branch)
<br/> Alternative address for Kish Island branch: Kish Banking Fin Activities Centre, No 42, 4th floor, VC25
<br/> Alternative addresses for Dubai branch: (1) SCT Bankers Kish Company (PJS), Head Office, Kish Island, Sadaf Tower, 3rd floor, Suite 301, P.O. Box 87. (2) Sheykh Admad, Sheykh Zayed Road, 31988, Dubai, Port, Kish Island.
<br/> Tels: 09347695504 (Kish Island branch)
<br/> 09347695504/97-143257022-99 (Dubai branch)
<br/> 09347695504 (Tehran branch)
<br/> Emails: info@sctbankers.com
<br/> zanjani@sctbankers.com </entry>
              <entry colname="4"><br/> Sorinet Commercial Trust Bankers Ltd. is controlled by Babak Zanjani, who is designated for providing financial support to the Government of Iran by facilitating oil payments on its behalf. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">8.11.2014 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">155. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">HK Intertrade Company Ltd. </entry>
              <entry colname="3">HK Intertrade Company, 21<sup>st</sup>Floor, Tai Yau Building, 181 Johnston Road, Wanchai, Hong Kong </entry>
              <entry colname="4">HK Intertrade Company Ltd. (HKICO) is assisting designated entities to violate the provisions of the EU regulation on Iran and is providing financial support to the government of Iran. HKICO is a front company controlled by EU-designated National Iranian Oil Company (NIOC). In mid-2012 HKICO was scheduled to receive millions of dollars from NIOC oil sales. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">22.12.2012 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">159. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sharif University of Technology </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Azadi Ave/Street, PO Box 11365-11155, Tehran, Iran, Tel: +98 21 66 161, Email: info@sharif.ir </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Sharif University of Technology (SUT) has a number of cooperation agreements with Iranian Government organisations which are designated by the UN and/or the EU and which operate in military or military-related fields, particularly in the field of ballistic missile production and procurement. This includes: an agreement with the EU-designated Aerospace Industries Organisation for inter alia the production of satellites; cooperating with the Iranian Ministry of Defence and the Iranian Revolutionary Guards Corps (IRGC) on smart boat competitions; a broader agreement with the IRGC Air Force which covers developing and strengthening the University's relations, organisational and strategic cooperation;
<br/> SUT is part of a 6-university agreement which supports the Government of Iran through defence-related research; and SUT teaches graduate courses in unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) engineering which were designed by the Ministry of Science among others. Taken together, these show a significant record of engagement with the Government of Iran in military or military-related fields that constitutes support to the Government of Iran. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">8.11.2014 </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/avsnitt/4">III. Islamic Republic of Iran Shipping Lines (IRISL)</avsnitt>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/avsnitt/5">A. Persons</avsnitt>
      <table niv="1" frame="1">
        <tgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="10*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">3. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Naser Bateni </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Born on 16 December 1962, Iranian. </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Naser Bateni acts on behalf of IRISL. He was a director of IRISL until 2008 and he was subsequently Managing Director of IRISL Europe GmbH. He is the managing director of Hanseatic Trade and Trust Shipping GmbH (HTTS) which as their general agent provides essential services to the Safiran Payam Darya Shipping Lines (SAPID) and to Hafize Darya Shipping Lines (HDS Lines), both of which are designated entities acting on behalf of IRISL. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">16.11.2013 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">8. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Gholam Hossein Golparvar </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Born on 23 January 1957, Iranian. ID Card No 4207 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Mr Golparvar acts on behalf of IRISL and companies associated with it. He has been commercial director of IRISL, as well as Managing Director and shareholder of the SAPID Shipping Company, non-executive director and shareholder of HDSL, and shareholder of Rhabaran Omid Darya Ship Management Company, which are designated by the EU as acting on behalf of IRISL. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">1.12.2011 </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/avsnitt/6">B. Entities</avsnitt>
      <table niv="1" frame="1">
        <tgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="10*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">1 c). </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Hanseatic Trade Trust &amp; Shipping (HTTS) GmbH </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Postal address: Schottweg 7, 22087 Hamburg, Germany; Alternative address: Opp 7th Alley, Zarafshan St, Eivanak St, Qods Township. </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Hanseatic Trade and Trust Shipping GmbH (HTTS) is the general agent for and as such provides essential services to Safiran Payam Darya Shipping Lines (SAPID) and to Hafize Darya Shipping Lines (HDS Lines), both of which are entities designated as acting on behalf of IRISL. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">16.11.2013 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">43. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Good Luck Shipping Company LLC (a.k.a. Good Luck Shipping Company) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">P.O. Box 5562, Dubai; or P.O. Box 8486, Dubai, United Arab Emirates </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Good Luck Shipping Company LLC as the agent for Hafize Darya Shipping Lines (HDS Lines) in the United Arab Emirates provides essential services to HDS Lines which is a designated entity acting on behalf of IRISL. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">16.11.2013 </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <br/>
      <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/marg/1+">I vedlegg IX skal følgende personer og enheter slettes:</marg>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/avsnitt/7">I. Persons and entities involved in nuclear or ballistic missiles activities and persons and entities providing support to the Government of Iran</avsnitt>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/avsnitt/8">A. Persons</avsnitt>
      <table niv="1" frame="1">
        <tgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="10*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">8. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Fereydoun MAHMOUDIAN </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Born on 07/11/1943 in Iran. Passport No. 05HK31387 issued on 01/01/2002 in Iran, valid until 07/08/2010. Acquired French nationality on 07/05/2008 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Director of Fulmen (see Part B, No. 13) </entry>
              <entry colname="5">26.7.2010 </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/avsnitt/9">B. Entities</avsnitt>
      <table niv="1" frame="1">
        <tgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="10*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">13. </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Fulmen </entry>
              <entry colname="3">167 Darya boulevard - Shahrak Ghods, 14669-8356 Tehran. </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Fulmen was involved in the installation of electrical equipment on the Qom/Fordoo site before its existence had been revealed. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">26.7.2010 </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(a) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Arya Niroo Nik </entry>
              <entry colname="3"/>
              <entry colname="4">Arya Niroo Nik is a front company used by Fulmen for some of its operations. </entry>
              <entry colname="5">26.7.2010 </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/ii" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-10-02-1158/kii">
      <kverdi>II</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/ii/ledd/1">Endringene trer i kraft straks.</ledd>
    </kapittel>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
