<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2015-05-07-487" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-05-07-487">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2015-05-07-487</id>
    <dato>07.05.2015 nr. 487</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2015-05-07</dato>
    <publisert>I 2015 hefte 5 s 730</publisert>
    <ikraft>07.05.2015</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2015-05-07</ikraft>
    <departement>Utenriksdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="lov-2001-04-27-14-§1">L27.04.2001 nr. 14 § 1</ref>,</hjemmel>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2011-09-02-902</endrer>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2015-0380</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Endr. i forskrift om restriktive tiltak mot Syria</korttittel>
    <korttittel>4 Endr. i forskrift om restriktive tiltak mot Syria (Nr. 487)</korttittel>
    <tittel>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om restriktive tiltak mot Syria</tittel>
    <redaksjonell_note><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Utenriksdepartementet 7. mai 2015 med hjemmel i lov 27. april 2001 nr. 14 om om iverksetjing av internasjonale, ikkje-militære tiltak i form av avbrot eller avgrensing av økonomisk eller anna samkvem med tredjestatar eller rørsler § 1 og forskrift 2. september 2011 nr. 902 om restriktive tiltak mot Syria § 5.</redaksjonell_note>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/i" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-05-07-487/ki">
      <kverdi>I</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/1">I forskrift 2. september 2011 nr. 902 om restriktive tiltak mot Syria gjøres følgende endringer:
<br/></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2">§ 2 første ledd skal lyde:</ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3">(1) EUs vedlagte forordning (EU) nr. 36/2012 om visse spesifikke restriktive tiltak mot visse personer og enheter i lys av situasjonen i Syria (som endret av forordning (EU) nr. 55/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 168/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 266/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 509/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 544/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 545/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 673/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 867/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 944/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 1117/2012, forordning (EU) nr. 325/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 363/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 517/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 697/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 1332/2013, forordning (EU) nr. 124/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 578/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 693/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 793/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 1013/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 1105/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 1323/2014, forordning (EU) 2015/108 og forordning (EU) 2015/375) gjelder som forskrift med de tilpasninger som følger av denne bestemmelsen.
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/marg/1">I vedlegg A gjøres følgende endringer i rådsforordning (EU) nr. 36/2012:
<br/></marg></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/4">Ny artikkel 7a skal lyde:</ledd>
      <artikkel type="forordning" id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-05-07-487/ki/g7a">
        <pverdi>Artikkel 7a</pverdi>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/1">1. Det er forbudt
<liste id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/1/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/1/liste/a/avsnitt/1">å selge, levere, overføre eller eksportere, direkte eller indirekte, jetdrivstoff og drivstofftilsetninger oppført i vedlegg Va til personer, enheter eller organer i Syria eller til bruk i Syria,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/1/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/1/liste/b/avsnitt/1">å yte finansiering eller finansiell bistand, herunder finansielle derivater, samt forsikring og gjenforsikring i tilknytning til salg, levering, overføring eller eksport av jetdrivstoff og drivstofftilsetninger oppført i vedlegg Va til personer, enheter eller organer i Syria eller til bruk i Syria,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/1/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/1/liste/c/avsnitt/1">å yte formidlingstjenester i tilknytning til salg, levering, overføring eller eksport av jetdrivstoff og drivstofftilsetninger oppført i vedlegg Va til personer, enheter eller organer i Syria eller til bruk i Syria.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/2">2. Vedlegg Va omfatter jetdrivstoff og drivstofftilsetninger.</ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/3">3. Som unntak fra bestemmelsene i nr. 1 kan medlemsstatenes kompetente myndigheter, som angitt på nettsidene oppført i vedlegg III, på de vilkår de finner hensiktsmessige, gi tillatelse til salg, levering, overføring eller eksport av jetdrivstoff og drivstofftilsetninger og yting av finansiering eller finansiell bistand, herunder finansielle derivater, samt forsikring og gjenforsikring og formidlingstjenester i tilknytning til salg, levering, overføring eller eksport av jetdrivstoff og drivstofftilsetninger oppført i vedlegg Vb til personer, enheter eller organer i Syria eller til bruk i Syria når det er fastslått at FN, eller organer som opptrer på FNs vegne, har behov for jetdrivstoffet og drivstofftilsetningene til humanitære formål, som å yte eller legge til rette for yting av bistand, herunder medisinsk utstyr, matvarer eller transport av humanitære hjelpearbeidere og tilhørende bistand, eller til evakuering fra eller inne i Syria.</ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/4">4. Vedkommende medlemsstater skal innen fire uker underrette de øvrige medlemsstatene og Kommisjonen om enhver tillatelse som gis i henhold til denne artikkel.</ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/5">5. Forbudet fastsatt i nr. 1 gjelder ikke
<liste id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/5/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/5/liste/a/avsnitt/1">jetdrivstoff og drivstofftilsetninger oppført i vedlegg Vb som utelukkende brukes av ikke-syriske sivile luftfartøyer som lander i Syria, forutsatt at de er beregnet på og benyttes kun til å fortsette flygningen med luftfartøyet de er lastet inn i,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/5/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/5/liste/b/avsnitt/1">jetdrivstoff og drivstofftilsetninger oppført i vedlegg Vb som utelukkende brukes av et syrisk luftfartsselskap som er oppført i vedlegg II eller IIa og benyttes til evakuering fra Syria i samsvar med artikkel 16 bokstav h),</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/5/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/5/liste/c/avsnitt/1">jetdrivstoff og drivstofftilsetninger oppført i vedlegg Vb som utelukkende brukes av et ikke-listeført syrisk luftfartsselskap som benyttes til evakuering fra eller inne i Syria.
<br/></avsnitt></liste></ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/7a/ledd/6">Artikkel 27 skal lyde:</ledd>
      </artikkel>
      <artikkel type="forordning" id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-05-07-487/ki/g27">
        <pverdi>Artikkel 27</pverdi>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27/ledd/1">1. Ingen krav skal imøtekommes i tilknytning til kontrakter eller transaksjoner der oppfyllelse eller gjennomføring er påvirket, direkte eller indirekte, helt eller delvis, av tiltakene som pålegges gjennom denne forordning, herunder erstatningskrav eller andre krav av denne typen, som krav om kompensasjon eller krav i henhold til en garanti, særlig krav om forlengelse eller innfrielse av en obligasjon, en garanti eller motgaranti, særlig finansielle garantier eller motgarantier, uansett form, dersom kravene fremsettes av
<liste id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27/ledd/1/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27/ledd/1/liste/a/avsnitt/1">personer, enheter eller organer som er oppført i vedlegg II eller IIa,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27/ledd/1/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27/ledd/1/liste/b/avsnitt/1">andre syriske personer, enheter eller organer, herunder den syriske regjeringen,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27/ledd/1/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27/ledd/1/liste/c/avsnitt/1">personer, enheter eller organer som handler gjennom eller på vegne av personer, enheter eller organer omtalt i bokstav a) eller b).</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27/ledd/2">2. Ved en eventuell rettssak om tvangsfullbyrdelse av krav skal personen som søker å få kravet tvangsfullbyrdet, bære bevisbyrden for at innfrielsen av kravet ikke er forbudt i henhold til nr. 1.</ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27/ledd/3">3. Denne artikkel berører ikke den rett personer, enheter og organer omtalt i nr. 1 har til ved domstolene å få prøvet lovligheten av manglende oppfyllelse av kontraktsmessige forpliktelser i samsvar med denne forordning.
<br/></ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27/ledd/4">Ny artikkel 27a skal lyde:</ledd>
      </artikkel>
      <artikkel type="forordning" id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-05-07-487/ki/g27a">
        <pverdi>Artikkel 27a</pverdi>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/1">Det er forbudt forsettlig å delta i aktiviteter som har som formål eller virkning å omgå bestemmelsene i artikkel 2a, 3, 3a, 4, 5, 6, 7a, 8, 9, 11, 11a, 11b, 11c, 12, 13, 14, 24, 25, 26 og 26a.
<br/></ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/2">I vedlegg II gjøres følgende endringer:
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/2/marg/1">Følgende fysiske person fjernes fra listen:</marg>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/2/marg/2">118. Dr. Mohammad Nidal Al-Shaar.
<br/></marg></ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/3">Informasjonen om følgende fysiske og juridiske personer erstattes med følgende:
<br/></ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/4">
          <i>A. Persons</i>
        </ledd>
        <table niv="1" frame="1">
          <thgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
            <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="5*"/>
            <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="30*"/>
            <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="11*"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">
                  <i>Name</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="3">
                  <i>Identifying information</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="4">
                  <i>Reasons</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="5">
                  <i>Date of listing</i>
                </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </thgroup>
          <tgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
            <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="5*"/>
            <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="30*"/>
            <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="11*"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">6. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Muhammad Dib Zaytun (a.k.a. Mohammed Dib Zeitoun) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 20 May 1951;
<br/>Place of birth: Damascus;
<br/>diplomatic passport No D000001300 </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Head of General Security Directorate; involved in violence against demonstrators. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">18. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Mohammed Hamcho </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 20 May 1966.
<br/>Passport No 002954347 </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Prominent Syrian businessman, owner of Hamcho International, close to key figures of the Syrian regime, including President Bashar al-Assad and Maher al-Assad.
<br/>Since March 2014, he has held the position of Chairman for China of the Bilateral Business Councils following his appointment by the Minister of Economy, Khodr Orfali.
<br/>Mohammed Hamcho benefits from and provides support to the Syrian regime and is associated with persons benefiting from and supporting the regime. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">27.1.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">28. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Khalid (a.k.a. Khaled) Qaddur (a.k.a. Qadour, Qaddour, Kaddour) </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Prominent Syrian businessman, close to Maher al-Assad, a key figure of the Syrian regime. Khalid Qaddur benefits from and provides support to the Syrian regime and is associated with persons benefiting from and supporting the regime. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">27.1.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">33. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Ayman Jabir (a.k.a. Aiman Jaber) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Place of birth: Latakia </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Prominent Syrian businessman, close to key figures of the Syrian regime such as Maher al-Assad and Rami Makhlouf.
<br/>He has also provided support to the regime by facilitating the importation of oil from Overseas Petroleum Trading to Syria through his company El Jazireh.
<br/>Ayman Jabir benefits from and provides support to the regime and is associated with persons benefiting from and supporting the regime. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">27.1.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">48. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Samir Hassan </entry>
                <entry colname="3"/>
                <entry colname="4">Samir Hassan is a prominent businessman, close to key figures of the Syrian regime, such as Rami Makhlouf and Issam Anbouba; since March 2014, he has held the position of Vice Chairman for Russia of the Bilateral Business Councils following his appointment by Minister of Economy, Khodr Orfali. Additionally, he supports the regime's war effort with cash donations. Accordingly, Samir Hassan is associated with persons benefitting from or supporting the regime and provides support to and benefits from the Syrian regime. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">27.9.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">50. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Tarif Akhras (a.k.a. Al Akhras) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 2 June 1951;
<br/>Place of birth: Homs, Syria;
<br/>Syrian passport nr. 0000092405 </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Prominent businessman benefiting from and supporting the regime. Founder of the Akhras Group (commodities, trading, processing and logistics) and former Chairman of the Homs Chamber of Commerce. Close business relations with President Al-Assad's family. Member of the Board of the Federation of Syrian Chambers of Commerce. Provided logistical support for the regime (buses and tank loaders). </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
        <br/>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/5">
          <i>B. Entities</i>
        </ledd>
        <table niv="1" frame="1">
          <thgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
            <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="5*"/>
            <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="30*"/>
            <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="11*"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">
                  <i>Name</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="3">
                  <i>Identifying information</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="4">
                  <i>Reasons</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="5">
                  <i>Date of listing</i>
                </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </thgroup>
          <tgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
            <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="5*"/>
            <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="30*"/>
            <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="11*"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">3. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Hamcho International (a.k.a. Hamsho International Group) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Baghdad Street, PO Box 8254 Damascus
<br/>Tel. +963 112316675
<br/>Fax +963 112318875
<br/>Website: <lenke url="http://www.hamshointl.com">www.hamshointl.com </lenke>
<br/>E-mail: info@hamshointl.com and hamshogroup@yahoo.com </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Hamcho International is a large Syrian holding company owned by Mohammed Hamcho.
<br/>Hamcho International benefits from and provides support to the regime and is associated with a person benefiting from and supporting the regime. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">27.1.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">17. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Souruh Company (a.k.a. SOROH Al Cham Company) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Address: Adra Free Zone Area Damascus - Syria;
<br/>Tel: +963-11-5327266;
<br/>Mobile: +963-933-526812; +963-932-878282;
<br/>Fax:+963-11-5316396
<br/>Email: sorohco@gmail.com
<br/>Website: http://sites.google.com/site/sorohco </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Majority of the shares of the company are owned directly or indirectly by Rami Makhlouf. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/5/marg/1">Følgende fysiske og juridiske personer legges til listen:
<br/></marg>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/6">
          <i>A. Persons</i>
        </ledd>
        <table niv="1" frame="1">
          <thgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
            <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="5*"/>
            <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="30*"/>
            <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="11*"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">
                  <i>Name</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="3">
                  <i>Identifying information</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="4">
                  <i>Reasons</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="5">
                  <i>Date of listing</i>
                </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </thgroup>
          <tgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
            <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="5*"/>
            <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="30*"/>
            <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="11*"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">192. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Hashim Anwar al-Aqqad a.k.a. Hashem Aqqad, Hashem Akkad, Hashim Akkad </entry>
                <entry colname="3">d.o.b. 1961 Mohagirine, Syria. </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Prominent businessman, chairman of the Akkad Group of companies that operate in multiple sectors of the Syrian economy, including oil and gas. Provides support to and benefits from the Syrian regime. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">23.7.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">193. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Colonel Suhayl Hasan a.k.a. Colonel Suhayl al-Hasan, 'al-Nimir'/'The Tiger', Sohail Hassan, Sohail al-Hassan, Suhail Hassan, Lieutenant Colonel Suhayl Hassan, Brigadier General Suhayl Hasan </entry>
                <entry colname="3"/>
                <entry colname="4">Military commander for the Syrian regime, responsible for violent repression of the civilian population; supports the regime. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">23.7.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">194. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Amr Armanazi a.k.a. Amr Muhammad Najib Al-Armanazi, Amr Najib Armanazi, Amrou Al-Armanazy </entry>
                <entry colname="3">d.o.b. 7 February 1944. </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Director General of the Syrian Scientific Studies and Research Centre (SSRC), responsible for providing support to the Syrian army for the acquisition of equipment used directly for the surveillance and repression of demonstrators. Responsible for the violent repression of the civilian population; supports the regime. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">23.7.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">195. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Houmam Jaza'iri (a.k.a. Humam al-Jazaeri) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 1977 </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Minister of Economy and Foreign Trade since 27.8.2014. As Government Minister shares responsibility for the regime's violent repression against the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">196. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Mohamad Amer Mardini (a.k.a. Mohammad Amer Mardini) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 1959.
<br/>Place of birth: Damascus </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Minister of Higher Education since 27.8.2014. As Government Minister shares responsibility for the regime's violent repression against the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">197. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Mohamad Ghazi Jalali (a.k.a. Mohammad Ghazi al-Jalali) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 1969
<br/>Place of birth: Damascus </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Minister of Communications and Technology since 27.8.2014. As Government Minister shares responsibility for the regime's violent repression against the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">198. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Kamal Cheikha (a.k.a. Kamal al-Sheikha) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 1961.
<br/>Place of birth: Damascus </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Minister of Water Resources since 27.8.2014. As Government Minister shares responsibility for the regime's violent repression against the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">199. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Hassan Nouri (a.k.a. Hassan al-Nouri) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 9.2.1960 </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Minister of Administrative Development since 27.8.2014. As Government Minister shares responsibility for the regime's violent repression against the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">200. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Mohammad Walid Ghazal </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 1951.
<br/>Place of birth: Aleppo. </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Minister of Housing and Urban Development since 27.8.2014. As Government Minister shares responsibility for the regime's violent repression against the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">201. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Khalaf Souleymane Abdallah (a.k.a. Khalaf Sleiman al-Abdullah) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 1960.
<br/>Place of birth: Deir Ezzor </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Minister of Labour since 27.8.2014. As Government Minister shares responsibility for the regime's violent repression against the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">202. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Nizar Wahbeh Yazaji (a.k.a. Nizar Wehbe Yazigi) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 1961
<br/>Place of birth: Damascus </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Minister of Health since 27.8.2014. As Government Minister shares responsibility for the regime's violent repression against the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">203. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Hassan Safiyeh (a.k.a. Hassan Safiye) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 1949
<br/>Place of birth: Latakia </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Minister of Internal Trade and Consumer Protection since 27.8.2014. As Government Minister shares responsibility for the regime's violent repression against the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">204. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Issam Khalil </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 1965
<br/>Place of birth: Banias </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Minister of Culture since 27.8.2014. As Government Minister shares responsibility for the regime's violent repression against the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">205. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Mohammad Mouti' Mouayyad (a.k.a. Mohammad Muti'a Moayyad) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 1968
<br/>Place of birth: Ariha (Idlib) </entry>
                <entry colname="4">State Minister since 27.8.2014. As Government Minister shares responsibility for the regime's violent repression against the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">206. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Ghazwan Kheir Bek (a.k.a. Ghazqan Kheir Bek) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Date of birth: 1961.
<br/>Place of birth: Latakia </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Minister of transport since 27.8.2014. As Government Minister shares responsibility for the regime's violent repression against the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">207. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Major General Ghassan Ahmed Ghannan
<br/> (a.k.a. Major General Ghassan Ghannan, a.k.a. Brigadier General Ghassan Ahmad Ghanem) </entry>
                <entry colname="3"/>
                <entry colname="4">As commander of the 155 Missile Brigade, he is supporting the Syrian regime and he is responsible for the violent repression against the civilian population. Responsible for firing at least 25 Scud Missiles at various civilian sites between January and March 2013. Associated with Maher al-Assad. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">208. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Colonel Mohammed Bilal (a.k.a. Lieutenant Colonel Muhammad Bilal) </entry>
                <entry colname="3"/>
                <entry colname="4">As a senior officer in the Air Force Intelligence Service of Syria, he supports the Syrian regime and he is responsible for the violent repression against the civilian population. He is also associated with the listed Scientific Studies Research Centre (SSRC). </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">209. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Mohamed Farahat (a.k.a. Muhammad Farahat) </entry>
                <entry colname="3"/>
                <entry colname="4">Vice-President of Finance and Administration at Tri-Ocean Energy, which has been listed by the Council for benefiting from and supporting the Syrian regime, he is therefore associated with a listed entity.
<br/>In view of his senior position in Tri-Ocean Energy, he is responsible for the activities of the entity in supplying oil to the regime. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">210. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Abdelhamid Khamis Abdullah
<br/> (a.k.a. Abdulhamid Khamis Abdullah a.k.a. Hamid Khamis a.k.a Abdelhamid Khamis Ahmad Adballa) </entry>
                <entry colname="3"/>
                <entry colname="4">Chairman of Overseas Petroleum Trading Company (OPT) which has been listed by the Council for benefiting from and supporting the Syrian regime. He coordinated shipments of oil to the Syrian regime with listed Syrian state oil company Sytrol. Therefore, he is benefitting from and providing support to the Syrian regime.
<br/>In view of his position as the most senior person in the entity he is responsible for its activities </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">211. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Bayan Bitar (a.k.a. Dr Bayan Al-Bitar) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Address: PO Box 11037 Damascus, Syria </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Managing Director of the Organisation for Technological Industries (OTI), and the Syrian Company for Information Technology (SCIT), which are both subsidiaries of the Syrian Ministry of Defence, which has been designated by the Council.
<br/>OTI assists in the production of chemical weapons for the Syrian regime.
<br/>As Managing Director of OTI and the SCIT Bayan Bitar provides support to the Syrian regime. Due to his role in the production of chemical weapons, he also shares responsibility for the violent repression against the Syrian population.
<br/>In view of his senior position in these entities, he is also associated with the designated entities OTI and SCIT. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">7.3.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">212. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Brigadier General Ghassan Abbas </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Address: CERS, Centre d'Etude et de Recherche Scientifique; (a.k.a. SSRC, Scientific Studies and Research Center; Centre de Recherche de Kaboun Barzeh Street, PO Box 4470, Damascus) </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Manager of the branch of the designated Syrian Scientific Studies and Research Centre (SSRC/CERS) near Jumraya/Jmraiya.
<br/>He has been involved in the proliferation of chemical weapons and the organisation of chemical weapons attacks, including in Ghouta in August 2013. He therefore shares responsibility for the violent repression against the Syrian population.
<br/>As manager of the SSRC/CERS branch near Jumraya/Jmraiya, Ghassan Abbas provides support to the Syrian regime.
<br/>As a result of his senior position in the SSRC, he is also associated with the designated entity SSRC. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">7.3.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">213. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Wael Abdulkarim (a.k.a. Wael Al Karim) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Address: Pangates International Corp Ltd., PO Box Sharjah Airport International Free Zone, United Arab Emirates
<br/>Al Karim for Trade and Industry, PO Box 111, 5797 Damascus Syria
<br/>Morgan Additives Office No 2206, 22nd Floor, Jafza View 19, Besides Jafza View 18, Sheikh Zayed Road, Jebel Ali Free Zone Authority Dubai, UAE </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Managing Director of the designated entity Pangates International Corp Ltd., which acts as an intermediary in the supply of oil to the Syrian regime.
<br/>As Managing Director of Pangates, Wael Abdulkarim provides support to, and benefits from, the Syrian regime. He also holds a senior position in the designated entity Al Karim Group, which is Pangates' parent company.
<br/>As a result of his senior positions in Pangates and Al Karim Group, he is also associated with these designated entities. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">7.3.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">214. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Ahmad Barqawi (a.k.a. Ahmed Barqawi) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Address: Pangates International Corp Ltd., PO Box Sharjah Airport International Free Zone, United Arab Emirates. Al Karim for Trade and Industry, PO Box 111, 5797 Damascus Syria.
<br/>Morgan Additives Office No 2206, 22nd Floor, Jafza View 19, Besides Jafza View 18, Sheikh Zayed Road, Jebel Ali Free Zone Authority Dubai, UAE </entry>
                <entry colname="4">General Manager of Pangates International Corp Ltd., which acts as an intermediary in the supply of oil to the Syrian regime, and manager of Al Karim Group. Both Pangates International and Al Karim Group have been designated by the Council.
<br/>As General Manager of Pangates and a manager of Pangates' parent company, Al Karim Group, Ahmad Barqawi provides support to, and benefits from the Syrian regime. Given his senior position in Pangates and Al Karim Group, he is also associated with the designated entities Pangates International and Al Karim Group. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">7.3.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">215. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">George Haswani (a.k.a. Heswani; Hasawani; Al Hasawani) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Address: Damascus Province, Yabroud, Al Jalaa St, Syria </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Prominent Syrian businessman, co-owner of HESCO Engineering and Construction Company, a major engineering and construction company in Syria. He has close ties to the Syrian regime.
<br/>George Haswani provides support and benefits from the regime through his role as a middleman in deals for the purchase of oil from ISIL by the Syrian regime.
<br/>He also benefits from the regime through favourable treatment including the award of a contract (as a subcontractor) with Stroytransgaz, a major Russian oil company. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">7.3.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">216. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Emad Hamsho (a.k.a. Imad Hmisho; Hamchu; Hamcho; Hamisho; Hmeisho; Hemasho) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Hamsho Building 31 Baghdad Street Damascus, Syria </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Occupies a senior management position in Hamsho Trading.
<br/>As a result of his senior position in Hamsho Trading, a subsidiary of Hamsho International, which has been designated by the Council, he provides support to the Syrian regime. He is also associated with a designated entity, Hamsho International.
<br/>Emad Hamsho funds Shabiha militias who in turn collect steel from the areas destroyed by the Syrian regime armed forces and militias and melt it down in local Syria Steel (Hmisho Steel) factories. He is also vice-president of the Syrian Council of Iron and Steel alongside designated regime businessmen such as Ayman Jaber. He is also an associate of Bashar Al-Assad. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">7.3.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">217. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Samir Hamsho (a.k.a. Samer; Sameer; Hmisho; Hamchu; Hamcho; Hamisho; Hmeisho; Hemasho) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Hamsho Building 31 Baghdad Street Damascus, Syria </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Samir Hamsho is a prominent Syrian businessman benefiting from and supporting the regime. He is the owner and chairman of Al Buroj and Syria Steel/Hmisho Steel, subsidiaries of Hamsho Trading, a subsidiary of Hamsho International, which has been designated by the Council.
<br/>Appointed to the Homs Chamber of Commerce in March 2014 by the Minister of Industry.
<br/>Therefore, he provides support to the Syrian regime and benefits from his connections with the regime.
<br/>He is also associated with the designated entities Hamsho International, Syria Steel SA and Al Buroj Trading. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">7.3.2015 </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
        <br/>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/7">
          <i>B. Entities</i>
        </ledd>
        <table niv="1" frame="1">
          <thgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
            <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="5*"/>
            <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="30*"/>
            <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="11*"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">
                  <i>Name</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="3">
                  <i>Identifying information</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="4">
                  <i>Reasons</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="5">
                  <i>Date of listing</i>
                </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </thgroup>
          <tgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
            <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="5*"/>
            <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="30*"/>
            <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="11*"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">54. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Overseas Petroleum Trading a.k.a. «Overseas Petroleum Trading SAL (Off-Shore)» a.k.a. «Overseas Petroleum Company» </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Dunant Street, Snoubra Sector, Beirut, Lebanon. </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Providing support to the Syrian regime and benefitting from the regime by organising covert shipments of oil to the Syrian regime. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">23.7.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">55. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Tri Ocean Trading a.k.a. Tri-Ocean Energy </entry>
                <entry colname="3">35b Saray El Maadi Tower, Corniche El Nile, Cairo, Egypt, Postal Code 11431 P.O. Box: 1313 Maadi </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Providing support to the Syrian regime and benefitting from the regime by organising covert shipments of oil to the Syrian regime. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">23.7.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">56. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">The Baniyas Refinery Company a.k.a. Banias, Banyas. </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Banias Refinery Building, 26 Latkia Main Road, Tartous, P.O. Box 26, Syria. </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Subsidiary of the General Corporation for Refining and Distribution of Petroleum Products (GCRDPP), a section of the Ministry of Petroleum and Mineral Resources. As such it provides financial support to the Syrian regime. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">23.7.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">57. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">The Homs Refinery Company. a.k.a Hims, General Company for Homs Refinery. </entry>
                <entry colname="3">General Company for Homs Refinery Building, 352 Tripoli Street, Homs, P.O. Box 352, Syria. </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Subsidiary of the General Corporation for Refining and Distribution of Petroleum Products (GCRDPP), a section of the Ministry of Petroleum and Mineral Resources. As such is provides financial support to the Syrian regime. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">23.7.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">58. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Army Supply Bureau </entry>
                <entry colname="3">PO Box 3361, Damascus </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Involved in the procurement of military equipment in support of the regime, and therefore responsible for the violent repression of the civilian population in Syria. Branch of Syrian Ministry of Defence. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">23.7.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">59. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Industrial Establishment of Defence. a.k.a. Industrial Establishment of Defense (IED), Industrial Establishment for Defence, Defence Factories Establishment, Establissements Industriels de la Defense (EID), Establissement Industrial de la Defence (ETINDE), Coefficient Defense Foundation. </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Al Thawraa Street, P.O. Box 2330 Damascas, or Al-Hameh, Damascas Countryside, P.O. Box 2230. </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Involved in the procurement of military equipment for the regime, and therefore responsible for the violent repression of the civilian population in Syria. Branch of Syrian Ministry of Defence. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">23.7.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">60. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Higher Institute for Applied Sciences and Technology (HISAT) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">P.O. Box 31983, Barzeh </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Affiliated to and a subsidiary of the Syrian Scientific Studies and Research Centre (SSRC) which is already designated. It provides training and support to the SSRC and is therefore responsible for the violent repression of the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">23.7.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">61. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">National Standards &amp; Calibration Laboratory (NSCL) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">P.O. Box 4470 Damascus </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Affiliated to and a subsidiary of the Syrian Scientific Studies and Research Centre (SSRC) which is already designated. It provides training and support to the SSRC and is therefore responsible for the violent repression of the civilian population. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">23.7.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">62. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">El Jazireh a.k.a. Al Jazerra </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Shaheen Building, 2nd floor, Sami el Solh, Beyrouth; sector of hydrocarbons </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Owned or controlled by Ayman Jaber, therefore associated with a designated person. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">23.7.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">63. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Pangates International Corp Ltd. (a.k.a. Pangates) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">PO Box 8177 Sharjah Airport International Free Zone United Arab Emirates </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Pangates acts as an intermediary in the supply of oil to the Syrian regime. Therefore, it is providing support to and benefiting from the Syrian regime. It is also associated with listed Syrian oil company Sytrol. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">64. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Abdulkarim Group (a.k.a. Al Karim for Trade and Industry/Al Karim Group) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">5797 Damascus Syria </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Parent company of Pangates with operational control of it. As such it is providing support to and benefiting from the Syrian regime. It is also associated with listed Syrian oil company Sytrol. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">21.10.2014 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">65. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Organisation for Technological Industries (a.k.a. Technical Industries Corporation (TIC)) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Address: PO Box 11037 Damascus, Syria </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Subsidiary of the Syrian Ministry of Defence, which has been designated by the Council.
<br/>OTI is involved in the production of chemical weapons for the Syrian regime.
<br/>It is therefore responsible for the violent repression against the Syrian population.
<br/> As a subsidiary of the Ministry of Defence, it is also associated with a designated entity. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">7.3.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">66. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Syrian Company for Information Technology (SCIT) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Address: PO Box 11037 Damascus, Syria </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Subsidiary of the Organisation for Technological Industries (OTI) and therefore the Syrian Ministry of Defence, which have been designated by the Council. It also works with the Central Bank of Syria which has been designated by the Council.
<br/>As a subsidiary of OTI and the Ministry of Defence, SCIT is associated with these designated entities. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">7.3.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">67. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Hamsho Trading (a.k.a. Hamsho Group; Hmisho Trading Group; Hmisho Economic Group) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Hamsho Building 31 Baghdad Street Damascus, Syria </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Subsidiary of Hamsho International, which has been designated by the Council.
<br/>As such, Hamsho Trading is associated with a designated entity, Hamsho International.
<br/>Supports the Syrian regime through its subsidiaries, including Syria Steel. Through its subsidiaries it is associated with groups such as the pro-regime Shabiha militias. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">7.3.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">68. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Syria Steel SA (a.k.a. Syria Steel Co; Syria Steel Rolling Mill; Hmisho Steel) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Hamsho Building 31 Baghdad Street Damascus, Syria </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Subsidiary of Hamsho Trading and therefore ultimately a subsidiary of Hamsho International, which has been designated by the Council. As such, Syria Steel SA is associated with a designated entity. Syria Steel also supports the Syrian regime through its work with Shabiha militias and producing armaments. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">7.3.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">69. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Al Buroj Trading (a.k.a. Borouj Trading Company) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Hamsho Building 31 Baghdad Street Damascus, Syria </entry>
                <entry colname="4">Subsidiary of Hamsho Trading and therefore ultimately of Hamsho International, which has been designated by the Council.
<br/>As such, Al Buroj Trading is associated with a designated entity, Hamsho International. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">7.3.2015 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">70. </entry>
                <entry colname="2">DK Group (a.k.a. DK Group Sarl; DK Middle-East &amp; Africa Regional Office) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">Addresses: DK Middle-East &amp; Africa Regional Office, Peres Lazaristes Center, No. 3, 5th Floor, Emir Bachir Street, Beirut Central District, Bachoura Sector, Beirut, Lebanon.
<br/>Azarieh Building - Block 03, 5th Floor
<br/>Azarieh Street - Solidere - Downtown, PO Box 11-503, Beirut, Lebanon </entry>
                <entry colname="4">DK Group supplies new banknotes to the Central Bank of Syria.
<br/>DK Group therefore provides support to the regime. Due to this supply relationship, it is also associated with a designated entity, the Central Bank of Syria. </entry>
                <entry colname="5">7.3.2015 </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
        <br/>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/8">Nytt vedlegg Va skal lyde:</ledd>
        <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/8/avsnitt/1">Vedlegg Va.
<br/>Annex Va: Jet fuel and fuel additives as referred to in article 7a(1)</avsnitt>
        <table niv="1" frame="1">
          <thgroup cols="3" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
            <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
            <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="55*"/>
            <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">
                  <i>No.</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="2">
                  <i>Description</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="3">
                  <i>CN Code</i>
                </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </thgroup>
          <tgroup cols="3" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
            <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
            <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="55*"/>
            <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(1) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Jet fuel (other than kerosene): </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Spirit type jet fuel (light oils) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">2710 12 70 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Other than kerosene (medium oils) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">2710 19 29 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(2) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Kerosene type jet fuel (medium oils) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">2710 19 21 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(3) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Kerosene type jet fuel blended with biodiesel<fref id="/kapittel/i/fotnote/1">1</fref> </entry>
                <entry colname="3">2710 20 90 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(4) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Oxidation inhibitors </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Oxidation inhibitors used in additives for lubricating oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- oxidation inhibitors containing petroleum oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 21 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- other oxidation inhibitors: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 29 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Oxidation inhibitors used for other liquids used for the same purpose as mineral oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 90 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(5) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Static dissipater additives </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Static dissipater additives for lubricating oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- containing petroleum oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 21 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- other: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 29 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Static dissipater additives for other liquids used for the same purpose as mineral oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 90 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(6) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Corrosion inhibitors </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Corrosion inhibitors for lubricating oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- containing petroleum oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 21 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- other: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 29 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Corrosion inhibitors for other liquids used for the same purpose as mineral oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 90 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(7) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Fuel system icing inhibitors (anti-icing additives) </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Fuel system icing inhibitors for lubricating oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- containing petroleum oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 21 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- other: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 29 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Fuel system icing inhibitors for other liquids used for the same purpose as mineral oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 90 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(8) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Metal de-activators </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Metal de-activators for lubricating oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- containing petroleum oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 21 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- other: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 29 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Metal de-activator for other liquids used for the same purpose as mineral oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 90 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(9) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Biocide additives </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Biocide additives for lubricating oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- containing petroleum oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 21 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- other: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 29 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Biocide additives for other liquids used for the same purpose as mineral oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 90 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(10) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Thermal stability improver additives </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Thermal stability improver for lubricating oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- containing petroleum oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 21 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- other: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 29 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Thermal stability improver for other liquids used for the same purpose as mineral oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 90 00 </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
        <fotnote id="/kapittel/i/fotnote/1">1 Provided it still contains 70 % or more by weight of petroleum oils or bituminous mineral oils.
<br/></fotnote>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/9">Nytt vedlegg Vb skal lyde:</ledd>
        <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/artikkel/27a/ledd/9/avsnitt/1">Vedlegg Vb.
<br/>Annex Vb: Jet fuel and fuel additives as referred to in article 7a(3)</avsnitt>
        <table niv="1" frame="1">
          <thgroup cols="3" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
            <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
            <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="55*"/>
            <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">
                  <i>No.</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="2">
                  <i>Description</i>
                </entry>
                <entry colname="3">
                  <i>CN Code</i>
                </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </thgroup>
          <tgroup cols="3" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
            <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
            <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="55*"/>
            <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(1) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Jet fuel (other than kerosene): </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Spirit type jet fuel (light oils) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">2710 12 70 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Other than kerosene (medium oils) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">2710 19 29 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(2) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Kerosene type jet fuel (medium oils) </entry>
                <entry colname="3">2710 19 21 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(3) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Kerosene type jet fuel blended with biodiesel<fref id="1">1</fref> </entry>
                <entry colname="3">2710 20 90 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(4) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Oxidation inhibitors </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Oxidation inhibitors used in additives for lubricating oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- oxidation inhibitors containing petroleum oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 21 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- other oxidation inhibitors: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 29 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Oxidation inhibitors used for other liquids used for the same purpose as mineral oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 90 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(5) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Static dissipater additives </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Static dissipater additives for lubricating oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- containing petroleum oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 21 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- other: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 29 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Static dissipater additives for other liquids used for the same purpose as mineral oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 90 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(6) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Metal de-activators </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Metal de-activators for lubricating oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- containing petroleum oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 21 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- other: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 29 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Metal de-activator for other liquids used for the same purpose as mineral oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 90 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(7) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Biocide additives </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Biocide additives for lubricating oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- containing petroleum oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 21 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- other: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 29 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Biocide additives for other liquids used for the same purpose as mineral oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 90 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1">(8) </entry>
                <entry colname="2">Thermal stability improver additives </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Thermal stability improver for lubricating oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3"> </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- containing petroleum oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 21 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">- other: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 29 00 </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry colname="1"/>
                <entry colname="2">Thermal stability improver for other liquids used for the same purpose as mineral oils: </entry>
                <entry colname="3">3811 90 00 </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
        <fotnote id="/kapittel/i/fotnote/1+">1 Provided it still contains 70 % or more by weight of petroleum oils or bituminous mineral oils.</fotnote>
      </artikkel>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/ii" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-05-07-487/kii">
      <kverdi>II</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/ii/ledd/1">Endringene trer i kraft straks.</ledd>
    </kapittel>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
