<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2015-06-19-714" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2015-06-19-714</id>
    <dato>19.06.2015 nr. 714</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2015-06-19</dato>
    <publisert>I 2015 hefte 7 s 1128</publisert>
    <ikraft>19.06.2015</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2015-06-19</ikraft>
    <departement>Helse- og omsorgsdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§23">L19.12.2003 nr. 124 § 23</ref>, <ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§16">§ 16</ref></hjemmel>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2008-12-22-1621</endrer>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2015-0608</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Forskrift om forbud mot import av bønner fra Nigeria</korttittel>
    <korttittel>3 Forskrift om forbud mot import av tørkede bønner fra Nigeria (Nr. 714)</korttittel>
    <tittel>Forskrift om forbud mot import av tørkede bønner fra Nigeria</tittel>
    <redaksjonell_note><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Mattilsynet 19. juni 2015 med hjemmel i lov 19. desember 2003 nr. 124 om matproduksjon og mattrygghet mv. (matloven) § 23 tredje ledd, jf. § 16.
<br/><b>EØS-henvisninger:</b> EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kap. I del 7.1 nr. 13 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2015/943).</redaksjonell_note>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714/p1">
      <pverdi>§ 1.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Virkeområde</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/1/ledd/1">Forskriften gjelder et forbud mot import av tørkede bønner til konsum med opprinnelse i Nigeria, med varenummer 07.13.3900, der Norge er først mottaksstat innen EØS-området.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714/p2">
      <pverdi>§ 2.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Forbud mot import av tørkede bønner fra Nigeria</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/2/ledd/1">EØS-avtalens vedlegg I kapittel I del 7.1 nr. 13 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2015/943) om strakstiltak som suspenderer importen av tørkede bønner fra Nigeria og endring av vedlegg I til forordning (EF) nr. 669/2009 gjelder som forskrift med de tilpasninger som følger av vedlegg I og II, protokoll 1 til avtalen og avtalen for øvrig.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714/p3">
      <pverdi>§ 3.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Tilsyn og vedtak</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/3/ledd/1">Mattilsynet fører tilsyn og kan fatte nødvendige enkeltvedtak, jf. matloven § 23, for å oppnå etterlevelse av bestemmelser gitt i eller i medhold av denne forskriften. Mattilsynet kan også fatte enkeltvedtak i henhold til matloven § 24 til § 26.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714/p4">
      <pverdi>§ 4.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Straff</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/4/ledd/1">Overtredelse av bestemmelser gitt i denne forskriften eller enkeltvedtak gitt i medhold av forskriften, er straffbart i henhold til matloven § 28.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/5" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714/p5">
      <pverdi>§ 5.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Ikrafttredelse</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/5/ledd/1">Denne forskrift trer i kraft straks.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <vedlegg type="" id=".vedlegg">
      <kapittel id="/overskrift/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714/?1">
        <kverdi/>
        <ktittel> Forordninger <br/></ktittel>
        <ledd id="/overskrift/1/ledd/1">
          <b>I</b>
        </ledd>
        <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714/?1/?2">
          <kverdi/>
          <ktittel> Forordning (EU) 2015/943</ktittel>
          <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/ledd/1">Nedenfor gjengis til informasjon EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kapittel I del 7.1 nr. 13 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2015/943) med de endringer og tillegg som følger av EØS-tilpasningen av rettsakten i samsvar med vedlegg I og protokoll 1 til EØS-avtalen.</ledd>
        </kapittel>
      </kapittel>
      <forordning>
        <kapittel id="/tittel/2015.943" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714/y2015.943">
          <kverdi/>
          <ktittel align="center"> COMMISSION IMPLEMENTING REGULATION (EU) 2015.943 <br/> of 18 June 2015 <br/> on emergency measures suspending imports of dried beans from Nigeria and amending Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 <br/> (Text with EEA relevance) <br/></ktittel>
          <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/1">THE EUROPEAN COMMISSION,</ledd>
          <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/2">Having regard to the Treaty on the Functioning of the European Union,</ledd>
          <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/3">Having regard to Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 28 January 2002 laying down the general principles and requirements of food law, establishing the European Food Safety Authority and laying down procedures in matters of food safety,<fref id="/fotnote/1">1</fref> and in particular Article 53(1) thereof,</ledd>
          <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/4">Having regard to Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 29 April 2004 on official controls performed to ensure the verification of compliance with feed and food law, animal health and animal welfare rules,<fref id="2">2</fref> and in particular Article 15(5) thereof,</ledd>
          <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5">Whereas:
<liste id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/1"><lverdi>(1)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/1/avsnitt/1">Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 lays down the general principles governing food in general, and food safety in particular, at Union and national level. It provides for emergency measures to be taken by the Commission, where there is evidence that food imported from a third country is likely to constitute a serious risk to human health.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/2"><lverdi>(2)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/2/avsnitt/1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 669/2009<fref id="3">3</fref> provides for an increased level of official controls on imports of certain feed and food of non-animal origin listed in Annex I to that Regulation. Concerning dried beans from Nigeria such an increased level is provided for since 1 July 2013, as regards the presence of pesticide residues.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/3"><lverdi>(3)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/3/avsnitt/1">The results of the official controls carried out by the Member States in the framework of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 on dried beans from Nigeria show a continuous high frequency of non-compliance with food law requirements as regards pesticide residues. No improvement of the situation could be observed after more than one year of increased frequency of controls at Union borders.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/4"><lverdi>(4)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/4/avsnitt/1">Since January 2013, more than 50 notifications have been issued to the Rapid Alert System for Food and Feed in relation to dried beans originating from Nigeria, nearly all of them reporting the presence of the unauthorised active substance dichlorvos at levels largely exceeding the acute reference dose tentatively established by the European Food Safety Authority.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/5"><lverdi>(5)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/5/avsnitt/1">These results provide evidence that the import of this food presents a serious risk for human health and that such risk cannot be contained satisfactorily by means of measures taken by the Member States concerned. It is therefore appropriate to suspend the import into the Union of dried beans from Nigeria, until the Nigerian authorities can provide substantial guarantees that they have put in place an adequate official control system to ensure that the products concerned comply with the relevant food law requirements.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/6"><lverdi>(6)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/6/avsnitt/1">As a consequence of that suspension, no increased level of official controls on the import of dried beans originating from Nigeria should be required. It is therefore necessary to amend Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 accordingly.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/7"><lverdi>(7)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/7/avsnitt/1">In order to allow the time necessary for Nigeria to provide feedback and to consider the appropriate risk management measures, the suspension of imports of dried beans should apply until 30 June 2016.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/8"><lverdi>(8)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/5/liste/8/avsnitt/1">The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on Plants, Animals, Food and Feed,
<fotnote id="/fotnote/1">1 OJ L 31, 1.2.2002, p. 1.</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/2">2 OJ L 165, 30.4.2004, p. 1.</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/3">3 Commission Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 implementing Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council as regards the increased level of official controls on imports of certain feed and food off non-animal origin and amending Decision 2006/504/EC (OJ L 194, 25.7.2009, p. 11).
<br/></fotnote></avsnitt></liste></ledd>
          <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/ledd/6">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</ledd>
          <artikkel type="forordning" id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714/y2015.943/g1">
            <pverdi>Article 1</pverdi>
            <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/1/ledd/1">This Regulation shall apply to all dried beans originating from Nigeria declared under CN code 0713 39 00.</ledd>
          </artikkel>
          <artikkel type="forordning" id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714/y2015.943/g2">
            <pverdi>Article 2</pverdi>
            <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/2/ledd/1">The importation into the Union of the foodstuffs referred to in Article 1 is prohibited.</ledd>
          </artikkel>
          <artikkel type="forordning" id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714/y2015.943/g3">
            <pverdi>Article 3</pverdi>
            <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/3/ledd/1">All expenditure incurred in the application of this Regulation shall be charged to the consignee or his agent.</ledd>
          </artikkel>
          <artikkel type="forordning" id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714/y2015.943/g4">
            <pverdi>Article 4</pverdi>
            <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/4/ledd/1">In Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 669/2009, the following entry is deleted:</ledd>
            <table niv="1" frame="1">
              <tgroup cols="6" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
                <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="16*"/>
                <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                <colspec colname="5" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                <colspec colname="6" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                <tbody>
                  <row>
                    <entry colname="1">Dried beans (Food) </entry>
                    <entry colname="2">0713 39 00 </entry>
                    <entry colname="3"/>
                    <entry colname="4">Nigeria (NG) </entry>
                    <entry colname="5">Pesticide residues<sup>2</sup> </entry>
                    <entry colname="6">50 </entry>
                  </row>
                </tbody>
              </tgroup>
            </table>
          </artikkel>
          <artikkel type="forordning" id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/5" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-19-714/y2015.943/g5">
            <pverdi>Article 5</pverdi>
            <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/5/ledd/1">This Regulation shall enter into force on the day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.</ledd>
            <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/5/ledd/2">It shall apply until 30 June 2016.</ledd>
            <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/5/ledd/3">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</ledd>
            <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/5/ledd/4">Done at Brussels, 18 June 2015.
<br/></ledd>
            <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/5/ledd/5">
              <i>For the Commission</i>
              <br/>
            </ledd>
            <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/5/ledd/6">
              <i>The President</i>
              <br/>
              <marg niv="1" id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/5/ledd/6/marg/1">Jean-Claude JUNCKER</marg>
            </ledd>
          </artikkel>
        </kapittel>
      </forordning>
      <br/>
      <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/5/ledd/1+">
        <b>II</b>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/5/ledd/2+">I forskrift 22. desember 2008 nr. 1621 om offentlig kontroll med etterlevelse av regelverk om fôrvarer, næringsmidler og helse og velferd hos dyr (kontrollforskriften) gjøres følgende endringer i den konsoliderte versjonen av forordning (EF) nr. 669/2009:
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/tittel/2015.943/artikkel/5/ledd/2/marg/1">Raden om tørkede bønner fra Nigeria i vedlegg I slettes.</marg></ledd>
    </vedlegg>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
