<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2015-12-03-1389" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-12-03-1389">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2015-12-03-1389</id>
    <dato>03.12.2015 nr. 1389</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2015-12-03</dato>
    <publisert>I 2015 hefte 13 s 2123</publisert>
    <ikraft>03.12.2015</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2015-12-03</ikraft>
    <departement>Utenriksdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="lov-2001-04-27-14-§1">L27.04.2001 nr. 14 § 1</ref>,</hjemmel>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2014-08-15-1076</endrer>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2015-1167</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Endr. i forskrift om tiltak vedr. Ukrainas integritet mv.</korttittel>
    <korttittel>4 Endr. i forskrift om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet, uavhengighet og stabilitet (Nr. 1389)</korttittel>
    <tittel>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet, uavhengighet og stabilitet</tittel>
    <marg niv="1" id="/marg/1"><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Utenriksdepartementet 3. desember 2015 med hjemmel i lov 27. april 2001 nr. 14 om iverksetjing av internasjonale, ikkje-militære tiltak i form av avbrot eller avgrensing av økonomisk eller anna samkvem med tredjestatar eller rørsler § 1 og forskrift 15. august 2014 nr. 1076 om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet, uavhengighet og stabilitet § 23.</marg>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/i" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-12-03-1389/ki">
      <kverdi>I</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/1">I forskrift 15. august 2014 nr. 1076 om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet, uavhengighet og stabilitet gjøres følgende endringer:
<br/></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2">§ 18 andre ledd skal lyde:</ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3">Forbudene i første ledd berører ikke oppfyllelse av kontrakter som er inngått før 16. august 2014, eller tilknyttede kontrakter som er nødvendige for å oppfylle slike kontrakter, eller yting av bistand som er nødvendig for å opprettholde og sikre eksisterende kapasiteter i Norge. Forbudene i § 18 første ledd bokstav a) og b) får ikke anvendelse på direkte eller indirekte yting av faglig bistand, finansiering eller finansiell bistand knyttet til følgende operasjoner:
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/liste/a/avsnitt/1">salg, levering, overføring eller eksport samt import, kjøp eller transport av hydrazin (CAS 302 01 2) i konsentrasjoner på minst 70 prosent, forutsatt at den faglige bistanden, finansieringen eller finansielle bistanden omhandler en mengde hydrazin som er beregnet i samsvar med oppskytningen eller oppskytningene eller satellittene stoffet er framstilt for, og som ikke overstiger en samlet mengde på 800 kg for hver enkelt oppskytning eller satellitt,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/liste/b/avsnitt/1">import, kjøp eller transport av usymmetrisk dimetylhydrazin (CAS 57 14 7),</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/liste/c/avsnitt/1">salg, levering, overføring eller eksport samt import, kjøp eller transport av monometylhydrazin (CAS 60 34 4), forutsatt at den faglige bistanden, finansieringen eller finansielle bistanden omhandler en mengde monometylhydrazin som er beregnet i samsvar med oppskytningen eller oppskytningene eller satellittene stoffet er framstilt for, i den utstrekning stoffene nevnt i bokstav a), b) og c) i dette ledd er beregnet på bruk i oppskytningsutstyr som benyttes av europeiske leverandører av oppskytningstjenester, ved oppskytninger knyttet til europeiske romprogrammer eller som drivstoff til satellitter framstilt av europeiske produsenter. Direkte eller indirekte yting av faglig bistand, finansiering eller finansiell bistand knyttet til operasjonene nevnt i dette ledd bokstav a), b) og c) krever forhåndstillatelse fra Utenriksdepartementet. De som søker om forhåndstillatelse, skal gi Utenriksdepartementet alle relevante opplysninger som er nødvendige.
<br/></avsnitt></liste></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/4">I vedlegg I gjøres følgende endringer:
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/4/marg/1">Følgende person slettes fra listen:
<br/></marg>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/4/marg/2">72. Oleksiy Borisovych MOZGOVY
<br/></marg></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5">Informasjonen om nedenstående listeførte personer erstattes med følgende:
<br/></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6">
        <i>1. Sergey Valeryevich AKSYONOV, Sergei Valerievich AKSENOV (Ceргeй Bалeрьeвич AKCëHOB), Serhiy Valeriyovych AKSYONOV (Ceргiй Bалeрiйoвич Aкcьoнoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6/marg/1">DOB: 26.11.1972.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6/marg/2">POB: Beltsy (Bălţi), now Republic of Moldova
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6/marg/3">Aksyonov was elected 'Prime Minister of Crimea' in the Crimean Verkhovna Rada on 27 February 2014 in the presence of pro-Russian gunmen. His 'election' was decreed unconstitutional by Oleksandr Turchynov on 1 March 2014. He actively lobbied for the 'referendum' of 16 March 2014. As of 9 October 2014, the 'Head' of the so-called 'Republic of Crimea'. Member of the Presidium of the Russia State Council.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7">
        <i>2. Vladimir Andreevich Konstantinov (Bладимир Aндрeeвич Кoнcтантинoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7/marg/1">DOB: 19.11.1956
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7/marg/2">POB: Vladimirovka (a.k.a Vladimirovca), Slobozia Region, Moldavian SSR (now Republic of Moldova) or Bogomol, Moldavian SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7/marg/3">As speaker of the Supreme Council of the Autonomous Republic of Crimea, Konstantinov played a relevant role in the decisions taken by the Verkhovna Rada concerning the 'referendum' against territorial integrity of Ukraine and called on voters to cast their votes in favour of Crimean Independence.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/8">
        <i>3. Rustam Ilmirovich Temirgaliev (Pycтам Ильмирoвич Teмиргалиeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/8/marg/1">DOB: 15.8.1976
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/8/marg/2">POB: Ulan-Ude, Buryat ASSR (Russian SFSR)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/8/marg/3">As former Deputy Chairman of the Council of Ministers of Crimea, Temirgaliev played a relevant role in the decisions taken by the Verkhovna Rada concerning the 'referendum' against territorial integrity of Ukraine. He lobbied actively for the integration of Crimea into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/8/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9">
        <i>4. Denis Valentinovich Berezovskiy (Дeниc Bалeнтинoвич Бeрeзoвcкий)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/marg/1">DOB: 15.7.1974
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/marg/2">POB: Kharkiv, Ukrainian SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/marg/3">Berezovskiy was appointed commander of the Ukrainian Navy on 1 March 2014 but thereafter swore an oath to the Crimean armed forces, thereby breaking his oath to the Ukrainian Navy. He was then appointed Deputy Commander of the Black Sea Fleet of the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10">
        <i>5. Aleksei Mikhailovich Chaliy (Aлeкceй Mиxайлoвич Чалый)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/marg/1">DOB: 13.6.1961
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/marg/2">POB: Moscow or Sevastopol
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/marg/3">Chaliy became 'Mayor of Sevastopol' by popular acclamation on 23 February 2014 and accepted this 'vote'. He actively campaigned for Sevastopol to become a separate entity of the Russian Federation following a referendum on 16 March 2014. He signed the Treaty on the adoption of the Republic of Crimea by Russia. Chairman of the Legislative Assembly of the City of Sevastopol.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/11">
        <i>6. Pyotr Anatoliyovych Zima (Пëтр Aнатoльeвич Зима)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/11/marg/1">DOB: 29.3.1965
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/11/marg/2">Zima was appointed as the new head of the Crimean Security Service (SBU) on 3 March 2014 by 'Prime Minister' Aksyonov and accepted this appointment. He has given relevant information including a database to the Russian Intelligence Service (SBU). This included information on Euro-Maidan activists and human rights defenders of Crimea. He played a relevant role in preventing Ukraine's authorities from controlling the territory of Crimea. On 11 March 2014 the formation of an independent Security Service of Crimea was proclaimed by former SBU officers of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/11/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/12">
        <i>7. Yuriy Gennadyevich Zherebtsov (Юрий Гeннадиeвич Жeрeбцoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/12/marg/1">DOB: 19.11.1969
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/12/marg/2">POB: Izmail, Odessa Region, Ukrainian SSR or Odessa
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/12/marg/3">Counsellor of the Speaker of the Verkhovna Rada of Crimea, one of the leading organisers of the 16 March 2014'referendum' against Ukraine's territorial integrity. Member of the Civic Chamber of the so-called 'Republic of Crimea'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/12/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/13">
        <i>8. Sergey Pavlovych Tsekov (Ceргeй Павлoвич Цeкoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/13/marg/1">DOB: 29.9.1953 or 23.9.1953,
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/13/marg/2">POB: Simferopol
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/13/marg/3">Vice Speaker of the Verkhovna Rada; Tsekov initiated, together with Sergey Aksyonov, the unlawful dismissal of the government of the Autonomous Republic of Crimea (ARC). He drew Vladimir Konstantinov into this endeavour, threatening him with dismissal. He publicly recognized that the MPs from Crimea were the initiators of inviting Russian soldiers to take over the Verkhovna Rada of Crimea. He was one of the first Crimean Leaders to ask in public for the annexation of Crimea to Russia. Member of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation from the so-called 'Republic of Crimea'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/13/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/14">
        <i>9. Ozerov, Viktor Alekseevich (Bиктoр Aлeкceeвич Oзeрoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/14/marg/1">DOB: 5.1.1958
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/14/marg/2">POB: Abakan, Khakassia
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/14/marg/3">Chairman of the Security and Defense Committee of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Ozerov, on behalf of the Security and Defense Committee of the Federation Council, publicly supported, in the Federation Council, the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/14/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/15">
        <i>10. Dzhabarov, Vladimir Michailovich (Bладимир Mиxайлoвич Джабарoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/15/marg/1">DOB: 29.9.1952
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/15/marg/2">First Deputy-Chairman of the International Affairs Committee of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Dzhabarov, on behalf of the International Affairs Committee of the Federation Council, publicly supported, in the Federation Council, the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/15/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/16">
        <i>11. Klishas, Andrei Aleksandrovich (Aндрeй Aлeкcандрoвич Клишаc)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/16/marg/1">DOB: 9.11.1972
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/16/marg/2">POB: Sverdlovsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/16/marg/3">Chairman of the Committee on Constitutional Law of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Klishas publicly supported, in the Federation Council, the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine. In public statements Klishas sought to justify a Russian military intervention in Ukraine by claiming that 'the Ukrainian President supports the appeal of the Crimean authorities to the President of the Russian Federation on landing an all-encompassing assistance in defense of the citizens of Crimea'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/16/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/17">
        <i>12. Ryzhkov, Nikolai Ivanovich (Hикoлай Иванoвич Pыжкoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/17/marg/1">DOB: 28.9.1929
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/17/marg/2">POB: Dyleevka, Donetsk region, Ukrainian SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/17/marg/3">Member of the Committee for federal issues, regional politics and the North of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Ryzhkov publicly supported, in the Federation Council, the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/17/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18">
        <i>13. Bushmin, Evgeni Viktorovich (Eвгeний Bиктoрoвич Бyшмин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/marg/1">DOB: 4.10.1958
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/marg/2">POB: Lopatino, Sergachiisky region, RSFSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/marg/3">Deputy Speaker of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Bushmin publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/19">
        <i>14. Totoonov, Aleksandr Borisovich (Aлeкcандр Бoриcoвич Toтooнoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/19/marg/1">DOB: 3.4.1957
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/19/marg/2">POB: Ordzhonikidze, North Ossetia
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/19/marg/3">Member of the Committee on culture, science, and information of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Totoonov publicly supported, in the Federation Council, the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/19/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/20">
        <i>15. Panteleev, Oleg Evgenevich (Oлeг Eвгeньeвич Пантeлeeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/20/marg/1">DOB: 21.7.1952
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/20/marg/2">POB: Zhitnikovskoe, Kurgan region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/20/marg/3">Former First Deputy Chairman of the Committee on Parliamentary Issues of the Federation Council. On 1 March 2014 Panteleev publicly supported, in the Federation Council, the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/20/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/21">
        <i>16. Mironov, Sergei Mikhailovich (Ceргeй Mиxайлoвич Mирoнoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/21/marg/1">DOB: 14.2.1953
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/21/marg/2">POB: Pushkin, Leningrad region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/21/marg/3">Member of the Council of the State Duma; Leader of Fair Russia faction in the Duma of the Russian Federation. Initiator of the bill allowing Russian Federation to admit in its composition, under the pretext of protection of Russian citizens, territories of a foreign country without the consent of that country or an international treaty.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/21/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/22">
        <i>17. Zheleznyak, Sergei Vladimirovich (Ceргeй Bладимирoвич Жeлeзняк)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/22/marg/1">DOB: 30.7.1970
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/22/marg/2">POB: St. Petersburg (former Leningrad)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/22/marg/3">Deputy Speaker of the State Duma of the Russian Federation. Actively supporting use of Russian Armed Forces in Ukraine and annexation of Crimea. He led personally the demonstration in support of the use of Russian Armed Forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/22/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/23">
        <i>18. Slutski, Leonid Eduardovich (Лeoнид Эдyардoвич Cлyцкий)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/23/marg/1">DOB: 4.1.1968
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/23/marg/2">POB: Moscow
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/23/marg/3">Chairman of the Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS) Committee of the State Duma of the Russian Federation (member of the LDPR). Actively supporting use of Russian Armed Forces in Ukraine and the annexation of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/23/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/24">
        <i>19. Vitko, Aleksandr Viktorovich (Aлeкcандр Bиктoрoвич Bиткo)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/24/marg/1">DOB: 13.9.1961
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/24/marg/2">POB: Vitebsk (Belarusian SSR)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/24/marg/3">Commander of the Black Sea Fleet, Vice-Admiral. Responsible for commanding Russian forces that have occupied Ukrainian sovereign territory.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/24/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/25">
        <i>20. Sidorov, Anatoliy Alekseevich (Aнатoлий Aлeкceeвич Cидoрoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/25/marg/1">DOB: 2.7.1958
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/25/marg/2">POB: Siva, Perm region, USSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/25/marg/3">Commander, Russia's Western Military District, units of which are deployed in Crimea. He is responsible for part of the Russian military presence in Crimea which is undermining the sovereignty of the Ukraine and assisted the Crimean authorities in preventing public demonstrations against moves towards a referendum and incorporation into Russia.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/25/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/26">
        <i>21. Galkin, Viktorovich Aleksandr (Aлeкcандр Bиктoрoвич Галкин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/26/marg/1">DOB: 22.3.1958
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/26/marg/2">POB: Ordzhonikidze, North Ossetian ASSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/26/marg/3">Russia's Southern Military District, forces of which are in Crimea; the Black Sea Fleet comes under Galkin's command; much of the force movement into Crimea has come through the Southern Military District. Commander of Russia's Southern Military District ('SMD'). SMD forces are deployed in Crimea. He is responsible for part of the Russian military presence in Crimea which is undermining the sovereignty of the Ukraine and assisted the Crimean authorities in preventing public demonstrations against moves towards a referendum and incorporation into Russia. Additionally the Black Sea Fleet falls within the District's control.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/26/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/27">
        <i>22. Rogozin, Dmitry Olegovich (Дмитрий Oлeгoвич Poгoзин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/27/marg/1">DOB: 21.12.1963
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/27/marg/2">POB: Moscow
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/27/marg/3">Deputy Prime Minister of the Russian Federation. Publicly called for the annexation of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/27/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/28">
        <i>23. Glazyev, Yurievich Sergey (Ceргeй Юрьeвич Глазьeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/28/marg/1">DOB: 1.1.1961
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/28/marg/2">POB: Zaporozhye, (Ukrainian SSR)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/28/marg/3">Adviser to the President of the Russian Federation. Publicly called for the annexation of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/28/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/29">
        <i>24. Matviyenko, Valentina Ivanova (born Tyutina) (Bалeнтина Иванoвна Mатвиeнкo (born Tютина))</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/29/marg/1">DOB: 7.4.1949
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/29/marg/2">POB: Shepetovka, Khmelnitsky (Kamenets-Podolsky) region (Ukrainian SSR)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/29/marg/3">Speaker of the Federation Council. On 1 March 2014, publicly supported, in the Federation Council, the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/29/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/30">
        <i>25. Naryshkin, Sergei Evgenevich (Ceргeй Eвгeньeвич Hарышкин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/30/marg/1">DOB: 27.10.1954
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/30/marg/2">POB: St Petersburg (former Leningrad)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/30/marg/3">Speaker of the State Duma. Publicly supported the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine. Publicly supported the Russia-Crimea reunification treaty and the related federal constitutional law.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/30/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/31">
        <i>26. Dmitry Konstantinovich KISELYOV, Dmitrii Konstantinovich KISELEV (Дмитрий Кoнcтантинoвич Киceлëв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/31/marg/1">DOB: 26.4.1954
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/31/marg/2">POB: Moscow
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/31/marg/3">Appointed by Presidential Decree on 9 December 2013 Head of the Russian Federal State news agency 'Rossiya Segodnya'. Central figure of the government propaganda supporting the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/31/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/32">
        <i>27. Nosatov, Alexander Mihailovich (Aлeкcандр Mиxайлoвич Hocатoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/32/marg/1">DOB: 27.3.1963
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/32/marg/2">POB: Sevastopol, (Ukrainian SSR)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/32/marg/3">Deputy-Commander of the Black Sea Fleet, Rear-Admiral. Responsible for commanding Russian forces that have occupied Ukrainian sovereign territory.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/32/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/33">
        <i>28. Kulikov, Valery Vladimirovich (Bалeрий Bладимирoвич Кyликoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/33/marg/1">DOB: 1.9.1956
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/33/marg/2">POB: Zaporozhye, (Ukrainian SSR)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/33/marg/3">Deputy-Commander of the Black Sea Fleet, Rear Admiral. Responsible for commanding Russian forces that have occupied Ukrainian sovereign territory.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/33/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/34">
        <i>29. Surkov, Vladislav Yurievich (Bладиcлав Юрьeвич Cyркoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/34/marg/1">DOB: 21.9.1964
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/34/marg/2">POB: Solntsevo, Lipetsk region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/34/marg/3">Aide to the President of the Russian Federation. He was an organiser of the process in Crimea by which local Crimean communities were mobilised to stage actions undermining the Ukrainian authorities in Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/34/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/35">
        <i>30. Mikhail Grigorievich Malyshev (Mиxаил Григoрьeвич Mалышeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/35/marg/1">DOB: 10.10.1955
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/35/marg/2">POB: Simferopol, Crimea
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/35/marg/3">Chair of the Crimea Electoral Commission. Responsible for administering the Crimean referendum. Responsible under the Russian system for signing referendum results.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/35/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/36">
        <i>31. Valery Kirillovich Medvedev (Bалeрий Кириллoвич Meдвeдeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/36/marg/1">DOB: 21.8.1946
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/36/marg/2">POB: Shmakovka, Primorsky region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/36/marg/3">Chair of Sevastopol Electoral Commission. Responsible for administering the Crimean referendum. Responsible under the Russian system for signing referendum results.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/36/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/37">
        <i>32. LTL. Gen. Igor Nikolaevich (Mykolayovich) Turchenyuk (Игoрь Hикoлаeвич Tyрчeнюк)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/37/marg/1">DOB: 5.12.1959
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/37/marg/2">POB: Osh, Kyrgyz SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/37/marg/3">The de facto Commander of Russian troops deployed on the ground in Crimea (whom Russia continues to refer to officially as 'local self-defence militias'). Deputy Commander of the Southern Military District.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/37/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/38">
        <i>33. Elena Borisovna Mizulina (born Dmitriyeva) (Eлeна Бoриcoвна Mизyлина (born Дмитриeва)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/38/marg/1">DOB: 9.12.1954
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/38/marg/2">POB: Bui, Kostroma region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/38/marg/3">Deputy in the State Duma. Originator and co-sponsor of recent legislative proposals in Russia that would have allowed regions of other countries to join Russia without their central authorities' prior agreement.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/38/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/39">
        <i>34. Dmitry Nikolayevich Kozak (Дмитрий Hикoлаeвич Кoзак)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/39/marg/1">DOB: 7.11.1958
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/39/marg/2">POB: Bandurovo, Kirovograd region, Ukrainian SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/39/marg/3">Deputy Prime Minister. Responsible for overseeing the integration of the annexed Autonomous Republic of Crimea into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/39/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/40">
        <i>35. Oleg Yevgenyvich Belaventsev (Oлeг Eвгeньeвич Бeлавeнцeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/40/marg/1">DOB: 15.9.1949
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/40/marg/2">POB: Moscow
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/40/marg/3">Plenipotentiary Representative of the President of the Russian Federation into the so-called 'Crimean Federal District', Non-permanent member of the Russian Security Council. Responsible for the implementation of the constitutional prerogatives of the Russian Head of State on the territory of the annexed Autonomous Republic of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/40/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/41">
        <i>36. Oleg Genrikhovich Savelyev (Oлeг Гeнриxoвич Cавeльeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/41/marg/1">DOB: 27.10.1965
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/41/marg/2">POB: Leningrad
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/41/marg/3">Minister for Crimean Affairs. Responsible for the integration of the annexed Autonomous Republic of Crimea into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/41/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/42">
        <i>37. Sergei Ivanovich Menyailo (Ceргeй Иванoвич Meняйлo)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/42/marg/1">DOB: 22.8.1960
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/42/marg/2">POB: Alagir, North- Ossetian
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/42/marg/3">Autonomous SSR, RSFSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/42/marg/4">Governor of the Ukrainian annexed city of Sevastopol.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/42/marg/5">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/43">
        <i>38. Olga Fedorovna Kovitidi (Oльга Фëдoрoвна Кoвитиди)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/43/marg/1">DOB: 7.5.1962
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/43/marg/2">POB: Simferopol, Ukrainian SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/43/marg/3">Member of the Russian Federation Council from the annexed Autonomous Republic of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/43/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/44">
        <i>40. Sergei Ivanovich Neverov (Ceргeй Иванoвич Heвeрoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/44/marg/1">DOB: 21.12.1961
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/44/marg/2">POB: Tashtagol, USSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/44/marg/3">Deputy Chairman of State Duma, United Russia. Responsible for initiating legislation to integrate the annexed Autonomous Republic of Crimea into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/44/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/45">
        <i>41. Igor Dmitrievich SERGUN (Игoрь Дмитриeвич Ceргyн)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/45/marg/1">DOB: 28.3.1957
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/45/marg/2">POB: Podolsk, Moscow Oblast
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/45/marg/3">Director of GRU (Main Intelligence Directorate), Deputy Chief of the General Staff of the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation, Lieutenant-General. Responsible for the activity of GRU officers in Eastern Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/45/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/46">
        <i>42. Valery Vasilevich Gerasimov (Bалeрий Bаcильeвич Гeраcимoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/46/marg/1">DOB: 8.9.1955
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/46/marg/2">POB: Kazan
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/46/marg/3">Chief of the General Staff of the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation, First Deputy Minister of Defence of the Russian Federation, General of the Army. Responsible for the massive deployment of Russian troops along the border with Ukraine and lack of de-escalation of the situation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/46/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/47">
        <i>43. German Prokopiv</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/47/marg/1">Active leader of the 'Lugansk Guard'. Took part in the seizure of the building of the Lugansk regional office of the Security Service. Close links with the 'Army of the South-East'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/47/marg/2">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/48">
        <i>44. Valeriy Dmitrievich Bolotov (Bалeрий Дмитриeвич Бoлoтoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/48/marg/1">DOB: 13.2.1970
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/48/marg/2">POB: Luhansk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/48/marg/3">One of the leaders of the separatist group 'Army of the South-East' which occupied the building of the Security Service in the Lugansk region. Retired officer. Before seizing the building he and other accomplices possessed arms apparently supplied illegally from Russia and from local criminal groups.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/48/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/49">
        <i>45. Andriy Yevgenovych PURGIN (Aндрiй Eвгeнoвич Пyргiн), Andrei Evgenevich PURGIN (Aндрeй Eвгeньeвич Пyргин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/49/marg/1">DOB: 26.1.1972
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/49/marg/2">POB: Donetsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/49/marg/3">Former Head of the 'Donetsk People's Republic', active participant and organiser of separatist actions, coordinator of actions of the 'Russian tourists' in Donetsk. Co-founder of a 'Civic Initiative of Donbass for the Eurasian Union'. So-called 'Chairman' of the 'People's Council of the Donetsk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/49/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/50">
        <i>46. Denys Volodymyrovych PUSHYLIN (Дeниc Boлoдимирoвич Пyшилiн), Denis Vladimirovich PUSHILIN (Дeниc Bладимирoвич Пyшилин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/50/marg/1">DOB: 9.5.1981 or 9.5.1982
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/50/marg/2">POB: Makiivka (Donetsk oblast)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/50/marg/3">One of the leaders of the 'Donetsk People's Republic'. Participated in the seizure and occupation of the regional administration. Active spokesperson for the separatists. So-called Deputy Chairman of the 'People's Council' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/50/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/51">
        <i>47. Tsyplakov Sergey Gennadevich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/51/marg/1">DOB: 1.5.1983
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/51/marg/2">POB: Khartsyzsk, Donetsk Oblast
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/51/marg/3">One of the leaders of ideologically radical organization People's Militia of Donbas. He took active part in the seizure of a number of state buildings in Donetsk region.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/51/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/52">
        <i>48. Igor Vsevolodovich Girkin (Игoрь Bceвoлoдoвич Гиркин) a.k.a. Igor Strelkov (Ihor Strielkov)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/52/marg/1">DOB: 17.12.1970
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/52/marg/2">POB: Moscow
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/52/marg/3">Identified as staff of Main Intelligence Directorate of the General Staff of the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation (GRU). He was involved in incidents in Sloviansk. He is an assistant on security issues to Sergey Aksionov, self-proclaimed prime minister of Crimea. Head of 'Novorossia' public movement.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/52/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/53">
        <i>49. Vyacheslav Viktorovich Volodin (Bячecлав Bиктoрoвич Boлoдин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/53/marg/1">DOB: 4.2.1964
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/53/marg/2">POB: Alekseevka, Saratov region.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/53/marg/3">First Deputy Chief of Staff of the Presidential Administration of Russia. Responsible for overseeing the political integration of the annexed Ukrainian region of Crimea into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/53/marg/4">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/54">
        <i>50. Vladimir Anatolievich Shamanov (Bладимир Aнатoльeвич Шаманoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/54/marg/1">DOB: 15.2.1957
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/54/marg/2">POB: Barnaul.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/54/marg/3">Commander of the Russian Airborne Troops, Colonel-General. In his senior position, holds responsibility for the deployment of Russian airborne forces in Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/54/marg/4">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/55">
        <i>51. Vladimir Nikolaevich Pligin (Bладимир Hикoлаeвич Плигин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/55/marg/1">DOB: 19.5.1960
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/55/marg/2">POB: Ignatovo,
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/55/marg/3">Vologodsk Oblast, USSR.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/55/marg/4">Chair of the Duma Constitutional Law Committee. Responsible for facilitating the adoption of legislation on the annexation of Crimea and Sevastopol into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/55/marg/5">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/56">
        <i>52. Petr Grigorievich JAROSH (Пeтр Григoрьeвич Ярoш)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/56/marg/1">DOB: 30.1.1971 or 16.3.1966
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/56/marg/2">POB: Skvortsovo village, Simferopol region, Crimea
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/56/marg/3">Head of the Federal Migration Service office for Crimea. Responsible for the systematic and expedited issuance of Russian passports for the residents of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/56/marg/4">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/57">
        <i>53. Oleg Grigorievich Kozyura (Oлeг Григoрьeвич Кoзюра)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/57/marg/1">DOB: 19.12.1962
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/57/marg/2">POB: Zaporozhye
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/57/marg/3">Head of the Federal Migration Service office for Sevastopol. Responsible for the systematic and expedited issuance of Russian passports for the residents of Sevastopol.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/57/marg/4">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/58">
        <i>54. Viacheslav PONOMARIOV, Vyacheslav Volodymyrovich PONOMARYOV (B'ячecлав Boлoдимирoвич Пoнoмарьoв), Viacheslav Vladimirovich PONOMAREV (Bячecлав Bладимирoвич Пoнoмарëв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/58/marg/1">DOB: 2.5.1965
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/58/marg/2">POB: Sloviansk (Donetsk oblast)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/58/marg/3">Former self-declared mayor of Slaviansk. Ponomariov called on Vladimir Putin to send in Russian troops to protect the city and later asked him to supply weapons. Ponomariov's men are involved in kidnappings (they captured Irma Krat and Simon Ostrovsky, a reporter for Vice News, both were later released, they detained military observers under the OSCE Vienna Document). Remains active in supporting separatist actions and policies.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/58/marg/4">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/59">
        <i>55. Igor Nikolaevich Bezler (Игoрь Hикoлаeвич Бeзлeр) a.k.a. Bes (devil)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/59/marg/1">DOB: 30.12.1965
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/59/marg/2">POB: Simferopol,Crimea
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/59/marg/3">One of the leaders of the self-proclaimed militia of Horlivka. He took control of the Security Service of Ukraine's Office in Donetsk region building and afterwards seized the Ministry of Internal Affairs' district station in the town of Horlivka. He has links to Ihor Strielkov under whose command he was involved in the murder of the Peoples' Deputy of the Horlivka's Municipal Council Volodymyr Rybak according to the SBU.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/59/marg/4">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/60">
        <i>57. Oleg TSARIOV, Oleh Anatoliyovych TSAROV (Oлeг Aнатoлтoвич Царьoв), Oleg Anatolevich TSAREV (Oлeг Aнатoльeвич Цаpëв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/60/marg/1">DOB: 2.6.1970
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/60/marg/2">POB: Dnepropetrovsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/60/marg/3">Former Member of the Rada, as such publicly called for the creation of the so-called 'Federal Republic of Novorossiya', composed of south-eastern Ukrainian regions. Remains active in supporting separatist actions or policies.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/60/marg/4">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/61">
        <i>58. Roman Viktorovich Lyagin (Poман Bиктoрoвич Лягин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/61/marg/1">DOB: 30.5.1980,
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/61/marg/2">POB: Donetsk, Ukraine
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/61/marg/3">Head of the 'Donetsk People's Republic' Central Electoral Commission. Actively organised the referendum on 11 May 2014 on the self-determination of the 'Donetsk People's Republic'. Former 'Minister of Labour and Social Policy'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/61/marg/4">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/62">
        <i>59. Aleksandr Sergeevich MALYKHIN, Alexander Sergeevich MALYHIN (Aлeкcандр Ceргeeвич Mалнxин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/62/marg/1">DOB: 12.1.1981
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/62/marg/2">Head of the 'Lugansk People's Republic' Central Electoral Commission. Actively organised the referendum on 11 May 2014 on the self-determination of the 'Lugansk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/62/marg/3">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/63">
        <i>60. Natalia Vladimirovna Poklonskaya (Hаталья Bладимирoвна Пoклoнcкая)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/63/marg/1">DOB: 18.3.1980
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/63/marg/2">POB: Mikhailovka, Voroshilovgrad region, Ukrainian SSR or Yevpatoria, Ukrainian SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/63/marg/3">Prosecutor of Crimea. Actively implementing Russia's annexation of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/63/marg/4">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/64">
        <i>61. Igor Sergeievich Shevchenko (Игoрь Ceргeeвич Шeвчeнкo)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/64/marg/1">POB: Sevastopol, Crimea
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/64/marg/2">Prosecutor of Sevastopol. Actively implementing Russia's annexation of Sevastopol.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/64/marg/3">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/65">
        <i>62. Aleksandr Yurevich BORODAI (Aлeкcандр Юрьeвич Бoрoдай)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/65/marg/1">DOB: 25.7.1972
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/65/marg/2">POB: Moscow
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/65/marg/3">Former so-called 'Prime Minister of the Donetsk People's Republic', as such responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so-called 'government of the Donetsk People's Republic' (e.g. on 8 July 2014 stated 'our military is conducting a special operation against the Ukrainian «fascists»'), signatory of the Memorandum of Understanding on 'Novorossiya union'. Remains active in supporting separatist actions or policies.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/65/marg/4">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/66">
        <i>63. Alexander KHODAKOVSKY, Oleksandr Serhiyovych KHODAKOVSKIY (Oлeкcандр Ceргiйoвич Xoдакoвcький), Aleksandr Sergeevich KHODAKOVSKII (Aлeкcандр Ceргeeвич Xoдакoвcкий)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/66/marg/1">DOB: 18.12.1972
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/66/marg/2">POB: Donetsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/66/marg/3">Former so-called 'Minister of Security of the Donetsk People's Republic', as such responsible for the separatist security activities of the so-called 'government of the Donetsk People's Republic'. Remains active in supporting separatist actions or policies.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/66/marg/4">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/67">
        <i>64. Alexandr Aleksandrovich KALYUSSKY, (Aлeкcандр Aлeкcандрoвич Калюccкий)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/67/marg/1">DOB: 9.10.1975
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/67/marg/2">So-called 'de facto Deputy Prime Minister for Social Affairs of the Donetsk People's Republic'. Responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so-called 'government of the Donetsk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/67/marg/3">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/68">
        <i>65. Alexander KHRYAKOV, Aleksandr Vitalievich KHRYAKOV (Aлeкcандр Bитальeвич Xрякoв), Oleksandr Vitaliyovych KHRYAKOV (Oлeкcандр BiTалiйoвич Xрякoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/68/marg/1">DOB: 6.11.1958
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/68/marg/2">POB: Donetsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/68/marg/3">Former so-called 'Information and Mass Communications Minister of the Donetsk People's Republic'. Responsible for the pro-separatist propaganda activities of the so-called 'government of the Donetsk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/68/marg/4">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/69">
        <i>66. Marat Faatovich BASHIROV (Mарат Фаатoвич Баширoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/69/marg/1">DOB: 20.1.1964
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/69/marg/2">POB: Izhevsk, Russian Federation
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/69/marg/3">Former so-called 'Prime Minister of the Council of Ministers of the Lugansk People's Republic', confirmed on 8 July 2014. Responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so-called 'government of the Lugansk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/69/marg/4">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/70">
        <i>67. Vasyl NIKITIN, Vasilii Aleksandrovich NIKITIN (Bаcилий Aлeкcандрoвич Hикитин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/70/marg/1">DOB: 25.11.1971
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/70/marg/2">POB: Shargun (Uzbekistan)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/70/marg/3">So-called 'Vice Prime Minister of the Council of Ministers of the Lugansk People's Republic', (used to be the so-called 'Prime Minister of the Lugansk People's Republic', and former spokesman of the 'Army of the Southeast').
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/70/marg/4">Responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so-called 'government of the Lugansk People's Republic'. Responsible for the statement of the Army of the Southeast that the Ukrainian presidential elections in the 'Lugansk People's Republic' cannot take place due to the 'new' status of the region.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/70/marg/5">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/71">
        <i>68. Aleksey Vyacheslavovich KARYAKIN (Aлeкceй Bячecлавoвич Карякин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/71/marg/1">DOB: 7.4.1980 or 7.4.1979
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/71/marg/2">POB: Stakhanov (Lugansk oblast)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/71/marg/3">So-called 'Supreme Council Chair of the Lugansk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/71/marg/4">Responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the 'Supreme Council', responsible for asking the Russian Federation to recognize the independence of the 'Lugansk People's Republic'. Signatory of the Memorandum of Understanding on the 'Novorossiya union'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/71/marg/5">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/72">
        <i>69. Yuriy Volodymyrovych IVAKIN (Юрiй Boлoдимирoвич Iвакiн), Iurii Vladimirovich IVAKIN (Юрий Bладимирoвич Ивакин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/72/marg/1">DOB: 13.8.1954
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/72/marg/2">POB: Perevalsk (Lugansk oblast)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/72/marg/3">Former so-called 'Minister of Internal Affairs of the Lugansk People's Republic', as such responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so-called 'government of the Lugansk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/72/marg/4">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/73">
        <i>70. Igor PLOTNITSKY, Igor Venediktovich PLOTNITSKII (Игoрь Beнeдиктoвич Плoтницкий)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/73/marg/1">DOB: 24.6.1964 or 25.6.1964 or 26.6.1964
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/73/marg/2">POB: Lugansk (possibly in Kelmentsi, Chernivtsi oblast)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/73/marg/3">Former so-called 'Defence Minister' and currently so-called 'Head' of the 'Lugansk People's Republic'. Responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so-called 'government of the Lugansk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/73/marg/4">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/74">
        <i>71. Nikolay KOZITSYN</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/74/marg/1">DOB: 20.6.1956
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/74/marg/2">POB: Donetsk region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/74/marg/3">Commander of Cossack forces. Responsible for commanding separatists in Eastern Ukraine fighting against the Ukrainian government forces.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/74/marg/4">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/75">
        <i>73. Mikhail Efimovich FRADKOV (Mиxаил Eфимoвич Фрадкoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/75/marg/1">DOB: 1.9.1950
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/75/marg/2">POB: Kurumoch, Kuibyshev region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/75/marg/3">Permanent member of the Security Council of the Russian Federation; Director of the Foreign Intelligence Service of the Russian Federation. As a member of the Security Council, which provides advice on and coordinates national security affairs, he was involved in shaping the policy of the Russian Government threatening the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/75/marg/4">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/76">
        <i>74. Nikolai Platonovich PATRUSHEV (Hикoлай Платoнoвич Патрyшeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/76/marg/1">DOB 11.7.1951
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/76/marg/2">POB: Leningrad (St Petersburg)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/76/marg/3">Permanent member and Secretary of the Security Council of the Russian Federation. As a member of the Security Council, which provides advice on and coordinates national security affairs, he was involved in shaping the policy of the Russian Government threatening the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/76/marg/4">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/77">
        <i>75. Aleksandr Vasilievich BORTNIKOV (Aлeкcандр Bаcильeвич Бoртникoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/77/marg/1">DOB: 15.11.1951
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/77/marg/2">POB: Perm
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/77/marg/3">Permanent member of the Security Council of the Russian Federation; Director of the Federal Security Service (FSB). As a member of the Security Council, which provides advice on and coordinates national security affairs, he was involved in shaping the policy of the Russian Government threatening the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/77/marg/4">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/78">
        <i>76. Rashid Gumarovich NURGALIEV (Pашид Гyмарoвич Hyргалиeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/78/marg/1">DOB: 8.10.1956
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/78/marg/2">POB: Zhetikara, Kazakh Soviet Socialist Republic
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/78/marg/3">Permanent member and Deputy Secretary of the Security Council of the Russian Federation. As a member of the Security Council, which provides advice on and coordinates national security affairs, he was involved in shaping the policy of the Russian Government threatening the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/78/marg/4">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/79">
        <i>77. Boris Vyacheslavovich GRYZLOV (Бoриc Bячecлавoвич Грызлoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/79/marg/1">DOB 15.12.1950
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/79/marg/2">POB: Vladivostok
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/79/marg/3">Permanent member of the Security Council of the Russian Federation. As a member of the Security Council, which provides advice on and coordinates national security affairs, he was involved in shaping the policy of the Russian Government threatening the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/79/marg/4">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/80">
        <i>78. Sergei Orestovoch BESEDA (Ceргeй Oрecтoвич Бeceда)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/80/marg/1">DOB: 17.5.1954
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/80/marg/2">Commander of the Fifth Service of the FSB, Federal Security Service of the Russian Federation. As a senior FSB officer, he heads a service responsible for overseeing intelligence operations and international activity.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/80/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/81">
        <i>79. Mikhail Vladimirovich DEGTYAREV (Mиxаил Bладимирoвич Дeгтярëв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/81/marg/1">DOB 10.7.1981
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/81/marg/2">POB: Kuibyshev (Samara)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/81/marg/3">Member of the State Duma. On 23.5.2014 he announced the inauguration of the 'de facto embassy' of the unrecognized, so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic' in Moscow, he contributes to undermining or threatening the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/81/marg/4">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/82">
        <i>80. Ramzan Akhmadovitch KADYROV (Pамзан Axматoвич Кадырoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/82/marg/1">DOB: 5.10.1976
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/82/marg/2">POB: Tsentaroy.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/82/marg/3">President of the Republic of Chechnya. Kadyrov made statements in support of the illegal annexation of Crimea and in support of the armed insurgency in Ukraine. He stated, inter alia, on 14 June 2014 that he 'will do anything to help revive Crimea'. In that context, he was awarded the medal for 'the liberation of Crimea' by the Acting Head of the Autonomous Republic of Crimea for the support he provided to the unlawful annexation of Crimea. In addition, on 1 June 2014 he expressed his readiness to send 74 000 Chechen volunteers to Ukraine if requested to do so.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/82/marg/4">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/83">
        <i>81. Alexander Nikolayevich TKACHYOV (Aлeкcандр Hикoлаeвич Tкачëв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/83/marg/1">DOB: 23.12.1960
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/83/marg/2">POB: Vyselki, Krasnodar region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/83/marg/3">Former Governor of the Krasnodar Krai.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/83/marg/4">He was awarded the medal 'for the liberation of Crimea' by the Acting head of the Autonomous Republic of Crimea for the support he provided to the unlawful annexation of Crimea. On that occasion, the Acting Head of the Autonomous Republic of Crimea said that Tkachyov was one of the first to express his support to the new 'leadership' of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/83/marg/5">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/84">
        <i>82. Pavel GUBAREV (Павeл Юрьeвич Гyбарeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/84/marg/1">DOB: 10.2.1983
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/84/marg/2">POB: Sievierodonetsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/84/marg/3">One of the self-described leaders of the so-called 'people' Republic of Donetsk'. He requested Russian intervention in eastern Ukraine, including through the deployment of Russian peacekeeping forces. He is associated with Igor Strelkov/Girkin who is responsible for actions which undermine or threaten the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. Gubarev is responsible for recruiting people for armed forces of separatists. Responsible for taking over the regional government building in Donetsk with pro-Russian forces and proclaimed himself the 'people's governor'. Despite being arrested for threatening the territorial integrity of Ukraine, and subsequently released, he has continued to play a prominent role in separatist activities, thus undermining the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/84/marg/4">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/85">
        <i>83. Ekaterina Iurievna GUBAREVA (Eкатeрина Юрьeвна Гyбарeва), Katerina Yuriyovna GUBARIEVA (Катeрина Юрiйoвнa Гyбарeва)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/85/marg/1">DOB: 5.7.1983
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/85/marg/2">POB: Kakhovka (Kherson oblast)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/85/marg/3">In her capacity of former so-called 'Minister of Foreign Affairs' she was responsible for defending the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic', thus undermining the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. In addition, her bank account is used to finance illegal separatist groups. In taking on and acting in this capacity she has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. Remains active in supporting separatist actions and policies.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/85/marg/4">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/86">
        <i>84. Fedor Dmitrievich BEREZIN (Фëдoр Дмитриeвич Бeрeзин), Fedir Dmitrovych BEREZIN (Фeдiр Дмитрoвич Бeрeзiн)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/86/marg/1">DOB: 7.2.1960
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/86/marg/2">POB: Donetsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/86/marg/3">Former so-called 'deputy defence minister' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. He is associated with Igor Strelkov/Girkin, who is responsible for actions which undermine or threaten the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. In taking on and acting in this capacity Berezin has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. Remains active in supporting separatist actions and policies.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/86/marg/4">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/87">
        <i>85. Valery Vladimirovich KAUROV Bалeрий Bладимирoвич Каyрoв</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/87/marg/1">DOB: 2.4.1956
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/87/marg/2">POB: Odessa
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/87/marg/3">The self-described 'president' of the so-called 'Republic of Novorossiya' who has called on Russia to deploy troops to Ukraine. In taking on and acting in this capacity he has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/87/marg/4">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/88">
        <i>86. Serhii Anatoliyovych ZDRILIUK Ceргeй Aнатoльeвич Здрнлюкv</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/88/marg/1">DOB: 23.6.1972
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/88/marg/2">POB: Vinnytsia region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/88/marg/3">Senior aid to Igor Strelkov/Girkin who is responsible for actions which undermine or threaten the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. In taking on and acting in this capacity, Zdriliuk has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/88/marg/4">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/89">
        <i>87. Vladimir ANTYUFEYEV Bладимир Aнтюфeeв</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/89/marg/1">(aka Vladimir SHEVTSOV, Vladimir Iurievici ANTIUFEEV, Vladimir Gheorghievici ALEXANDROV, Vadim Gheorghievici SHEVTSOV)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/89/marg/2">DOB: 19.2.1951
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/89/marg/3">POB: Novosibirsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/89/marg/4">Former 'Minister of State Security' in the separatist region of Transnistria. Former vice-prime minister of Donetsk People's Republic, responsible for security and law enforcement. In his capacity, he is responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so-called 'government of the Donetsk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/89/marg/5">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/90">
        <i>88. Alexey Alexeyevich GROMOV (Aлeкceй Aлeкceeвич Грoмoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/90/marg/1">DOB: 31.5.1960
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/90/marg/2">POB: Zagorsk (Sergiev Posad)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/90/marg/3">As first Deputy Chief of Staff of the Presidential Administration, he is responsible for instructing Russian media outlets to take a line favourable with the separatists in Ukraine and the annexation of Crimea, therefore supporting the destabilisation of Eastern Ukraine and the annexation of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/90/marg/4">30.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/91">
        <i>90. Boris Alekseevich LITVINOV (Бoриc Aлeкceeвич Литвинoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/91/marg/1">DOB: 13.1.1954
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/91/marg/2">POB: Dzerzhynsk (Donetsk oblast)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/91/marg/3">Member of the so-called 'People's Council' and former chairman of the so-called 'Supreme Council' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic' who was at the source of policies and the organisation of the illegal 'referendum' leading to the proclamation of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic', which constituted a breach of the territorial integrity, sovereignty and unity of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/91/marg/4">30.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/92">
        <i>91. Sergey Vadimovich ABISOV (Ceргeй Bадимoвич Aбиcoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/92/marg/1">DOB 27.11.1967
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/92/marg/2">POB: Simferopol, Crimea
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/92/marg/3">By accepting his appointment as so-called 'Minister of Interior of the Republic of Crimea' by the President of Russia (decree No 301) on 5 May 2014 and by his actions as so-called 'Minister of Interior' he has undermined the territorial integrity, sovereignty and unity of Ukraine
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/92/marg/4">30.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/93">
        <i>92. Arkady Romanovich ROTENBERG, Arkadii Romanovich ROTENBERG (Aркадий Poманoвич Poтeнбeрг)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/93/marg/1">DOB: 15.12.1951
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/93/marg/2">POB: Leningrad (Saint Petersburg).
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/93/marg/3">Mr Rotenberg is a long-time acquaintance of President Putin and his former judo sparring partner. He developed his fortune during President Putin's tenure. His level of economic success is attributable to the influence of key decision makers favouring him, notably in the award of public contracts.He has benefited from his close personal relationship with Russian decision-makers as he was awarded important contracts by the Russian State or by State-owned enterprises. His companies were, notably awarded several highly lucrative contracts for the preparations for the Sochi Olympic Games. He is also the owner of the company Stroygazmontazh which has been awarded a State contract for the construction of a bridge from Russia to the illegally annexed Autonomous Republic of Crimea, therefore consolidating its integration into the Russian Federation which in turn further undermines the territorial integrity of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/93/marg/4">He is the chairman of the board of directors of publishing house Prosvescheniye, which has notably implemented the project 'To the Children of Russia: Address - Crimea', a public relations campaign that was designed to persuade Crimean children that they are now Russian citizens living in Russia and thereby supporting the Russian Government's policy to integrate Crimea into Russia.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/93/marg/5">30.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/94">
        <i>93. Konstantin Valerevich MALOFEEV (Кoнcтантин Bалeрьeвич Mалoфeeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/94/marg/1">DOB: 3.7.1974
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/94/marg/2">POB: Puschino
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/94/marg/3">Mr Malofeev is closely linked to Ukrainian separatists in Eastern Ulkraine and Crimea. He is a former employer of Mr Borodai, so-called Prime Minister of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic' and met with Mr Aksyonov, so-called Prime Minister of the so-called 'Republic of Crimea', during the period of the Crimean annexation process. The Ukrainian Government has opened a criminal investigation into his alleged material and financial support to separatists. In addition, he gave a number of public statements supporting the annexation of Crimea and the incorporation of Ukraine into Russia and notably stated in June 2014 that 'You can't incorporate the whole of Ukraine into Russia. The East (of Ukraine) maybe'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/94/marg/4">Therefore Mr Malofeev is acting in support of the destabilisation of Eastern Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/94/marg/5">30.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/95">
        <i>94. Yuriy Valentinovich KOVALCHUK (Юрий Bалeнтинoвич Кoвальчyк)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/95/marg/1">DOB 25.7.1951
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/95/marg/2">POB: Leningrad (St Petersburg)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/95/marg/3">Mr Kovalchuk is a long-time acquaintance of President Putin. He is a co-founder of the so-called Ozero Dacha, a cooperative society bringing together an influential group of individuals around President Putin. He is benefiting from his links with Russian decision-makers. He is the chairman and largest shareholder of Bank Rossiya, of which he owned around 38 % in 2013, and which is considered the personal bank of Senior Officials of the Russian Federation. Since the illegal annexation of Crimea, Bank Rossiya has opened branches across Crimea and Sevastopol, thereby consolidating their integration into the Russian Federation. Furthermore, Bank Rossiya has important stakes in the National Media Group which in turn controls television stations which actively support the Russian government's policies of destabilisation of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/95/marg/4">30.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/96">
        <i>95. Nikolay Terentievich SHAMALOV (Hикoлай Teрeнтьeвич Шамалoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/96/marg/1">DOB: 24.1.1950
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/96/marg/2">POB: Belarus
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/96/marg/3">Mr Shamalov is a long-time acquaintance of President Putin. He is a co-founder of the so-called Ozero Dacha, a cooperative society bringing together an influential group of individuals around President Putin. He benefits from his links with Russian decision-makers. He is the second largest shareholder of Bank Rossiya, of which he owned around 10 % in 2013, and which is considered the personal bank of Senior Officials of the Russian Federation. Since the illegal annexation of Crimea, Bank Rossiya has opened branches across Crimea and Sevastopol, thereby consolidating their integration into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/96/marg/4">Furthermore, Bank Rossiya has important stakes in the National Media Group which, in turn, controls television stations which actively support the Russian government's policies of destabilisation of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/96/marg/5">30.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/97">
        <i>96. Alexander Vladimirovich ZAKHARCHENKO (Aлeкcандр Bладимирoвич Заxарчeнкo)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/97/marg/1">DOB: 26.6.1976
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/97/marg/2">POB: Donetsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/97/marg/3">As of 7 August 2014, he replaced Alexander Borodai as the so-called 'Prime minister' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. In taking on and acting in this capacity, Zakharchenko has supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/97/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/98">
        <i>97. Vladimir KONONOV/aka 'Tsar' (Bладимир Пeтрoвнч Кoнoнoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/98/marg/1">DOB: 14.10.1974
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/98/marg/2">POB: Gorsky
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/98/marg/3">As of 14 August, he replaced Igor Strelkov/Girkin, as the so-called 'Defence minister' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. He has reportedly commanded a division of separatist fighters in Donetsk since April and has promised to solve the strategic task of repelling Ukraine's military aggression. Konokov has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/98/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/99">
        <i>98. Miroslav Vladimirovich RUDENKO (Mирocлав Bладимирoвич Pyдeнкo)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/99/marg/1">DOB: 21.1.1983
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/99/marg/2">POB: Debalcevo
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/99/marg/3">Associated with the 'Donbass People's Militia'. He has, inter alia, stated that they will continue their fighting in the rest of the country. Rudenko has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. So-called 'People's Deputy' in the so-called 'Parliament of the Donetsk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/99/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/100">
        <i>99. Gennadiy Nikolaiovych TSYPKALOV, Gennadii Nikolaevich TSYPKALOV (Гeннадий Hикoлаeвич ЦыПлакoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/100/marg/1">DOB: 21.6.1973
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/100/marg/2">POB: Rostov oblast (Russia)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/100/marg/3">Replaced Marat Bashirov as so-called 'Prime Minister' of the so-called 'Lugansk People's Republic'. Previously active in the militia Army of the Southeast. Tsyplakov has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/100/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/101">
        <i>100. Andrey Yurevich Pinchuk (Aндрeи Юрьeвич Пинчyк)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/101/marg/1">Possible date of birth: 27.12.1977
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/101/marg/2">Former 'State security minister' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. Associated with Vladimir Antyufeyev, who is responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so-called 'government of the Donetsk People's Republic'. He has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. Remains active in supporting separatist actions or policies.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/101/marg/3">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/102">
        <i>101. Oleg Vladimirovich BEREZA (Oлeг Bладимирoвич Бeрëза)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/102/marg/1">DOB: 1.3.1977
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/102/marg/2">'Internal affairs minister' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. Associated with Vladimir Antyufeyev, who is responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so-called 'Government of the Donetsk People's Republic'. He has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/102/marg/3">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/103">
        <i>102. Andrei Nikolaevich RODKIN (Aндрeй Hикoлаeвич Poдкин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/103/marg/1">DOB: 23.9.1976
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/103/marg/2">POB: Moscow
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/103/marg/3">Moscow Representative of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. In his statements he has, inter alia, talked about the militias' readiness to conduct a guerrilla war and their seizure of weapon systems from the Ukrainian armed forces. He has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/103/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/104">
        <i>103. Aleksandr Akimovich KARAMAN (Aлeкcандр Aкимoвич Караман), Alexandru CARAMAN</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/104/marg/1">DOB: 26.7.1956 or 26.6.1956
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/104/marg/2">POB Cioburciu, Slobozia district, now Republic of Moldova
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/104/marg/3">'Deputy Prime Minister for Social Issues' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. Associated with Vladimir Antyufeyev, who is responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so-called 'Government of the Donetsk People's Republic'. He has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. Protégé of Russia's Deputy Prime Minister Dmitry Rogozin. Head of the Administration of the Council of Ministers of the so-called 'Donetsk Peoples Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/104/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/105">
        <i>104. Georgiy L'vovich MURADOV (Гeoргий Львoвич Myрадoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/105/marg/1">DOB: 19.11.1954
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/105/marg/2">POB: Kochmes, Komi ASSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/105/marg/3">So-called 'Deputy Prime Minister' of Crimea and Plenipotentiary Representative of Crimea to President Putin. Muradov has played an important role in consolidating Russian institutional control over Crimea since the illegal annexation. He has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/105/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/106">
        <i>105. Mikhail Sergeyevich SHEREMET (Mиxаил Ceргeeвич Шeрeмeт)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/106/marg/1">DOB 23.5.1971
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/106/marg/2">POB: Dzhankoy
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/106/marg/3">So-called 'First Deputy Prime Minister' of Crimea. Sheremet played a key role in the organization and implementation of the 16 March referendum in Crimea on unification with Russia. At the time of the referendum, Sheremet reportedly commanded the pro-Moscow 'self- defense forces' in Crimea. He has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/106/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/107">
        <i>106. Yuri Leonidovich VOROBIOV (Юрий Лeoнидoвич Boрoбьeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/107/marg/1">DOB 2.2.1948
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/107/marg/2">POB: Krasnoyarsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/107/marg/3">Deputy Speaker of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Vorobiov publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine. He subsequently voted in favour of the related decree.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/107/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/108">
        <i>107. Vladimir Volfovich ZHIRINOVSKY (Bладимир Boльфoвич Жиринoвcки)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/108/marg/1">DOB: 25.4.1946
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/108/marg/2">POB: Alma-Ata, Kazakh SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/108/marg/3">Member of the Council of the State Duma; leader of the LDPR party. He actively supported the use of Russian Armed Forces in Ukraine and annexation of Crimea. He has actively called for the split of Ukraine. He signed, on behalf of the LDPR party he chairs, an agreement with the so-called, 'Donetsk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/108/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/109">
        <i>108. Vladimir Abdualiyevich VASILYEV (Bаcильeв Bладимир Aбдyалиeвич)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/109/marg/1">DOB: 11.8.1949
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/109/marg/2">POB: Klin
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/109/marg/3">Deputy Speaker of the State Duma. On 20 March 2014 he voted in favour of the draft Federal Constitutional Law 'on the acceptance into the Russian Federation of the Republic of Crimea and the formation within the Russian Federation of new federal subjects - the republic of Crimea and the City of Federal Status Sevastopol'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/109/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/110">
        <i>109. Viktor Petrovich VODOLATSKY (Bиктoр Пeтрoвич Boдoлацкий)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/110/marg/1">DOB 19.8.1957
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/110/marg/2">POB: Stefanidin Dar, Rostov region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/110/marg/3">Chairman ('ataman') of the Union of the Russian and Foreign Cossack Forces, and deputy of the State Duma. He supported the annexation of Crimea and admitted that Russian Cossacks were actively engaged in the Ukrainian conflict on the side of the Moscow-backed separatists. On 20 March 2014 he voted in favour of the draft Federal Constitutional Law 'on the acceptance into the Russian Federation of the Republic of Crimea and the formation within the Russian Federation of new federal subjects - the republic of Crimea and the City of Federal Status Sevastopol'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/110/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/111">
        <i>110. Leonid Ivanovich KALASHNIKOV (Лeoнид Иванoвич Калашникoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/111/marg/1">DOB: 6.8.1960
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/111/marg/2">POB: Stepnoy Dvorets
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/111/marg/3">First deputy Chairman of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the State Duma. On 20 March 2014 he voted in favour of the draft Federal Constitutional Law 'on the acceptance into the Russian Federation of the Republic of Crimea and the formation within the Russian Federation of new federal subjects - the republic of Crimea and the City of Federal Status Sevastopol'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/111/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/112">
        <i>111. Vladimir Stepanovich NIKITIN (Bладимир Cтeпанoвич Hикитин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/112/marg/1">DOB 5.4.1948
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/112/marg/2">POB: Opochka
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/112/marg/3">Former First Deputy Chairman of the Committee on Relations with CIS Countries, Eurasian Integration and Links with Compatriots of the State Duma. On 20 March 2014 he voted in favour of the draft Federal Constitutional Law 'on the acceptance into the Russian Federation of the Republic of Crimea and the formation within the Russian Federation of new federal subjects - the republic of Crimea and the City of Federal Status Sevastopol'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/112/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/113">
        <i>112. Oleg Vladimirovich LEBEDEV (Oлeг Bладимирoвич Лeбeдeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/113/marg/1">DOB 21.3.1964
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/113/marg/2">POB: Rudny, Kostanai region, Kazakh SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/113/marg/3">First Deputy Chairman of the Committee on Relations with CIS Countries, Eurasian Integration and Links with Compatriots of the State Duma. On 20 March 2014 he voted in favour of the draft Federal Constitutional Law 'on the acceptance into the Russian Federation of the Republic of Crimea and the formation within the Russian Federation of new federal subjects - the republic of Crimea and the City of Federal Status Sevastopol'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/113/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/114">
        <i>113. Ivan Ivanovich MELNIKOV (Иван Иванoвич Meльникoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/114/marg/1">DOB: 7.8.1950
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/114/marg/2">POB: Bogoroditsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/114/marg/3">First Deputy Speaker, State Duma. On 20 March 2014 he voted in favour of the draft Federal Constitutional Law 'on the acceptance into the Russian Federation of the Republic of Crimea and the formation within the Russian Federation of new federal subjects - the republic of Crimea and the City of Federal Status Sevastopol'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/114/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/115">
        <i>114. Igor Vladimirovich LEBEDEV (Игoрь Bладимирoвич Лeбeдeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/115/marg/1">DOB: 27.9.1972
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/115/marg/2">POB: Moscow
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/115/marg/3">Deputy Speaker, State Duma. On 20 March 2014 he voted in favour of the draft Federal Constitutional Law 'on the acceptance into the Russian Federation of the Republic of Crimea and the formation within the Russian Federation of new federal subjects - the republic of Crimea and the City of Federal Status Sevastopol'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/115/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/116">
        <i>115. Nikolai Vladimirovich LEVICHEV (Hикoлай Bладимирoвич Лeвичeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/116/marg/1">DOB: 28.5.1953
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/116/marg/2">POB: Pushkin
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/116/marg/3">Deputy Speaker, State Duma. On 20 March 2014 he voted in favour of the draft Federal Constitutional Law 'on the acceptance into the Russian Federation of the Republic of Crimea and the formation within the Russian Federation of new federal subjects - the republic of Crimea and the City of Federal Status Sevastopol'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/116/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/117">
        <i>116. Svetlana Sergeevna ZHUROVA (Cвeтлана Ceргeeвна Жyрoва)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/117/marg/1">DOB 7.1.1972
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/117/marg/2">POB: Pavlov-on-the-Neva
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/117/marg/3">First Deputy Chairman of the Committee on Foreign Affairs, State Duma. On 20 March 2014 he voted in favour of the draft Federal Constitutional Law 'on the acceptance into the Russian Federation of the Republic of Crimea and the formation within the Russian Federation of new federal subjects - the republic of Crimea and the City of Federal Status Sevastopol'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/117/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/118">
        <i>117. Aleksey Vasilevich NAUMETS (Aлeкceй Bаcильeвич Hayмeц)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/118/marg/1">DOB: 11.2.1968
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/118/marg/2">Major-general of the Russian Army. He is the commander of the 76th airborne division which has been involved in the Russian military presence on the territory of Ukraine, notably during the illegal annexation of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/118/marg/3">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/119">
        <i>118. Sergey Viktorovich CHEMEZOV (Ceргeй Bиктoрoвич Чeмeзoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/119/marg/1">DOB: 20.8.1952
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/119/marg/2">POB: Cheremkhovo
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/119/marg/3">Sergei Chemezov is one of President Putin's known close associates, both were KGB officers posted in Dresden and he is a member of the Supreme Council of 'United Russia'. He is benefiting from his links with the Russian President by being promoted to senior positions in State-controlled firms. He chairs the Rostec conglomerate, the leading Russian state-controlled defence and industrial manufacturing corporation. Further to a decision of the Russian government, Technopromexport, a subsidiary of Rostec, is planning to build energy plants in Crimea thereby supporting its integration into the Russian Federation. Furthermore, Rosoboronexport, a subsidiary of Rostec, has supported the integration of Crimean defence companies into Russia's defence industry, thereby consolidating the illegal annexation of Crimea into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/119/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/120">
        <i>119. Alexander Mikhailovich BABAKOV (Aлeкcандр Mиxайлoвич Бабакoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/120/marg/1">DOB: 8.2.1963
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/120/marg/2">POB: Chisinau
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/120/marg/3">State Duma Deputy, Chair of the State Duma Commission on Legislative Provisions for Development of the Military-Industrial Complex of the Russian Federation. He is a prominent member of 'United Russia' and a businessman with heavy investments in Ukraine and in Crimea. On the 20 March 2014 he voted in favour of the draft Federal Constitutional Law 'on the acceptance into the Russian Federation of the Republic of Crimea and the formation within the Russian Federation of new federal subjects - the Republic of Crimea and the city of federal status of Sevastopol'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/120/marg/4">12.9.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/121">
        <i>120. Serhiy KOZYAKOV (aka Sergey Kozyakov) Ceргeй Кoзьякoв</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/121/marg/1">DOB: 29.9.1982
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/121/marg/2">In his capacity as 'Head of the Luhansk Central Election Commission' he is responsible for organising the so-called 'elections' of 2 November 2014 in the so-called 'Luhansk People's Republic'. These 'elections' are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal. In taking on and acting in this capacity, and in organising the illegal 'elections', he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/121/marg/3">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/122">
        <i>121. Oleg Konstantinovich AKIMOV a.k.a. Oleh AKIMOV (Oлeг Кoнcтантинoвич Aкимoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/122/marg/1">DOB: 15.9.1981
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/122/marg/2">POB: Lugansk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/122/marg/3">Deputy of the 'Lugansk Economic Union' in the 'National Council' of the 'Lugansk People's Republic'. Stood as a candidate in the so-called 'elections', of 2 November 2014 to the post of 'Head' of the so-called 'Lugansk People's Republic'. These 'elections' are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal. In taking on and acting in this capacity, and in participating formally as a candidate in the illegal 'elections', he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/122/marg/4">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/123">
        <i>122. Larisa Leonidovna AIRAPETYAN a.k.a. Larysa AYRAPETYAN, Larisa AIRAPETYAN or Larysa AIRAPETYAN (Лариcа Лeoнидoвна Aйрапeтян)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/123/marg/1">DOB: 21.2.1970
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/123/marg/2">'Health Minister' of the so-called 'Lugansk People's Republic'. Stood as a candidate in the so-called 'elections' of 2 November 2014 to the post of the 'Head' of the so-called 'Lugansk People's Republic'. These 'elections' are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal. In taking on and acting in this capacity, and in participating formally as a candidate in the illegal 'elections', she has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/123/marg/3">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/124">
        <i>123. Yuriy Viktorovich SIVOKONENKO a.k.a. Yuriy SIVOKONENKO, Yury SIVOKONENKO, Yury SYVOKONENKO (Юрий Bиктoрoвич Cивoкoнeнкo)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/124/marg/1">DOB: 7.8.1957
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/124/marg/2">POB: Donetsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/124/marg/3">Member of the 'Parliament' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic' and works in the Union of veterans of the Donbass Berkut. Stood as a candidate in the so-called 'elections' of 2 November 2014 to the post of the Head of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. These elections are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal. In taking on and acting in this capacity, and in participating formally as a candidate in the illegal 'elections', he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/124/marg/4">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/125">
        <i>124. Aleksandr Igorevich KOFMAN a.k.a. Oleksandr KOFMAN (Aлeкcандр Игoрeвич Кoфман)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/125/marg/1">DOB: 30.8.1977
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/125/marg/2">POB: Makiivka (Donetsk oblast)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/125/marg/3">So-called 'Foreign Minister' and so-called 'First deputy speaker' of the 'Parliament' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. Stood as a candidate in the so-called illegal 'elections' of 2 November 2014 to the post of Head of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. These elections are in breach of Ukrainian law and therefore illegal. In taking part and acting in this capacity, and in participating formally as a candidate in the illegal 'elections', he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/125/marg/4">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/126">
        <i>125. Ravil Zakarievich KHALIKOV (Pавиль Закариeвич Xаликoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/126/marg/1">DOB: 23.2.1969
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/126/marg/2">POB: Belozere village, Romodanovskiy rayon, USSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/126/marg/3">'First Deputy Prime Minister' and previous 'Prosecutor-General' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/126/marg/4">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/127">
        <i>126. Dmitry Aleksandrovich SEMYONOV, Dmitrii Aleksandrovich SEMENOV (Дмитрий Aлeкcандрoвич Ceмeнoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/127/marg/1">DOB: 3.2.1963
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/127/marg/2">POB: Moscow
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/127/marg/3">'Deputy Prime Minster for Finances' of the so-called 'Lugansk People's Republic'. In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/127/marg/4">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/128">
        <i>127. Oleg BUGROV (Oлeг Бyгрoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/128/marg/1">DOB: 29.8.1969
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/128/marg/2">Former 'Defense Minister' of the so-called 'Lugansk People's Republic'. In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/128/marg/3">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/129">
        <i>128. Lesya LAPTEVA (Лecя Лаптeва)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/129/marg/1">Former 'Minister of Education, Science, Culture and Religion' of the so-called 'Luhansk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/129/marg/2">In taking on and acting in this capacity, she has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/129/marg/3">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/130">
        <i>129. Yevgeniy Eduardovich MIKHAYLOV (aka Yevhen Eduardovych Mychaylov) (Eвгeний Здyардoвич Mиxайлoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/130/marg/1">DOB: 17.3.1963
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/130/marg/2">POB: Arkhangelsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/130/marg/3">'Head of the administration for governmental affairs' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/130/marg/4">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/131">
        <i>132. Vladyslav Nykolayevych DEYNEGO a.k.a. Vladislav Nykolayevich DEYNEGO (Bладиcлав Hикoлаeвич Дeйнeгo)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/131/marg/1">DOB: 12.3.1964
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/131/marg/2">'Deputy Head' of the 'People's Council' of the so-called 'Lugansk People's Republic'. In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/131/marg/3">29.11.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/132">
        <i>133. Pavel DREMOV a.k.a. Batya (Павeл Лeoнидoвич ДPËMOB), Pavlo Leonidovych DRYOMOV (Павлo Лeoнщoвич Дрьoмoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/132/marg/1">DOB: 22.11.1976
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/132/marg/2">POB: Stakhanov
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/132/marg/3">Commander of the 'First Cossack Regiment', an armed separatist group involved in the fighting in eastern Ukraine. In this capacity, he has actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/132/marg/4">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/133">
        <i>134. Alexey MILCHAKOVa.k.a. Fritz, Serbian (Aлeкceй MИЛЬЧAКOB)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/133/marg/1">DOB: 30.4. 1991 or on 30.1.1991
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/133/marg/2">POB: St. Petersburg
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/133/marg/3">Commander of the 'Rusich' unit, an armed separatist group involved in the fighting in eastern Ukraine. In this capacity, he has actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/133/marg/4">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/134">
        <i>135. Arseny PAVLOVa.k.a. Motorola ApcéHий Ceргeeвич ПÁBЛOB (aka Moтoрoла)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/134/marg/1">DOB: 2.2.1983
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/134/marg/2">POB: Ukhta, Komi
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/134/marg/3">Commander of the 'Sparta Battalion', an armed separatist group involved in the fighting in eastern Ukraine. In this capacity, he has actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/134/marg/4">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/135">
        <i>136. Mikhail Sergeevich TOLSTYKH a.k.a. Givi (Mиxаил Ceргeeвич Toлcтыx)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/135/marg/1">DOB: 19.7.1980
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/135/marg/2">POB: Ilovaisk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/135/marg/3">Commander of the 'Somali' battalion, an armed separatist group involved in the fighting in eastern Ukraine. In this capacity, he has actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/135/marg/4">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/136">
        <i>137. Eduard Aleksandrovich BASURIN (Здyард Aлeкcандрoвич Баcyрин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/136/marg/1">DOB: 27.6.1966 or 21.6.1966
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/136/marg/2">POB: Donetsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/136/marg/3">So-called 'Deputy Commander' of the Ministry of Defense of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/136/marg/4">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/137">
        <i>138. Alexandr SHUBIN Aлeкcандр Bаcильeвич ШУБИH</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/137/marg/1">DOB: 20.5.1972 or 30.5.1972
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/137/marg/2">POB: Luhansk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/137/marg/3">So-called 'Minister of Justice', of the illegal so-called 'Luhansk People's Republic'. In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised the country.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/137/marg/4">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/138">
        <i>139. Sergey Anatolievich LITVIN (Ceргeй Aнатoльeвич Литвин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/138/marg/1">DOB: 2.7.1973
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/138/marg/2">So-called 'Deputy Chairman' of the Council of Ministers of the so-called 'Lugansk People's Republic'. In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/138/marg/3">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/139">
        <i>141. Ekaterina FILIPPOVA Eкатeрина Bладимирoвна ФИЛИППOBA</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/139/marg/1">DOB: 20.11.1988
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/139/marg/2">POB: Krasnoarmëisk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/139/marg/3">So-called 'Minister of Justice' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/139/marg/4">In taking on and acting in this capacity, she has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/139/marg/5">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/140">
        <i>142. Aleksandr TIMOFEEV Aлeкcандр TИMOФEEB</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/140/marg/1">DOB: 27.1.1974
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/140/marg/2">So-called 'Minister of Budget' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/140/marg/3">In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised the country.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/140/marg/4">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/141">
        <i>143. Evgeny Vladimirovich MANUILOV (Eвгeний Bладимирoвич Mанyйлoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/141/marg/1">DOB: 5.1.1967
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/141/marg/2">So-called 'Minister of Budget' of the so-called 'Lugansk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/141/marg/3">In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/141/marg/4">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/142">
        <i>144. Viktor YATSENKO (Bиктoр ЯЦEHКO)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/142/marg/1">DOB: 22.4.1985
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/142/marg/2">POB: Kherson
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/142/marg/3">So-called 'Minister of Communications' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/142/marg/4">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/143">
        <i>146. Zaur ISMAILOV (Заyр Иcмаилoв Pаyфoвич)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/143/marg/1">DOB: 25.7.1978 (or 23.3.1975)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/143/marg/2">POB: Krasny Luch, Voroshilovgrad Lugansk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/143/marg/3">So-called 'General Prosecutor' of the so-called 'Lugansk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/143/marg/4">In taking on and acting in this capacity, he has therefore actively supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/143/marg/5">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/144">
        <i>147. Anatoly Ivanovich ANTONOV (Aнатoлий Иванoвич Aнтoнoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/144/marg/1">DOB 15.5.1955
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/144/marg/2">POB: Omsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/144/marg/3">Deputy Minister of Defence and, in that capacity, involved in supporting the deployment of Russian troops in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/144/marg/4">According to the present Russian Ministry of Defence structure, in that capacity he participates in shaping and implementing the policy of the Russian Government. These policies threaten the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/144/marg/5">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/145">
        <i>148. Arkady Viktorovich BAKHIN (Aркадий Bиктoрoвич Баxин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/145/marg/1">DOB: 8.5.1956
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/145/marg/2">POB: Kaunas, Lithuania
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/145/marg/3">First Deputy Minister of Defence and, in that capacity, involved in supporting the deployment of Russian troops in Ukraine. According to the present Russian Ministry of Defence structure, in that capacity he participates in shaping and implementing the policy of the Russian Government. These policies threaten the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/145/marg/4">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/146">
        <i>149. Andrei Valeryevich KARTAPOLOV (Aндрeй Bалeрьeвич Картaпoлoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/146/marg/1">DOB: 9.11.1963
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/146/marg/2">POB: GDR (DDR)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/146/marg/3">Director of the Main Operations Department and deputy chief of the General Staff of the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation. In both capacities he is actively involved in shaping and implementing the military campaign of the Russian forces in Ukraine. According to the stated activities of the general staff, by exercising operational control over the armed forces, he is actively involved in shaping and implementing the Russian government policy threatening the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/146/marg/4">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/147">
        <i>150. Iosif (Joseph) Davydovich KOBZON (Иocиф Дaвьιдoвич Кoбзoн)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/147/marg/1">DOB: 11.9.1937
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/147/marg/2">POB: Tchassov Yar, Ukraine
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/147/marg/3">Member of the State Duma. He visited the so-called Donetsk People's Republic and during his visit made statements supporting separatists. He was also appointed Honorary Consul of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic' in the Russian Federation. On 20 March 2014 he voted in favour of the draft Federal Constitutional Law 'on the acceptance into the Russian Federation of the Republic of Crimea and the formation within the Russian Federation of new federal subjects - the republic of Crimea and the City of Federal Status Sevastopol'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/147/marg/4">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/148">
        <i>151. Valery Fedorovich RASHKIN (Bалeрий Фëдoрoвич Pашкин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/148/marg/1">DOB: 14.3.1955
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/148/marg/2">POB: Zhilino, Kaliningrad region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/148/marg/3">First Deputy Chairman of the State Duma Committee on Ethnicity issues. He is the founder of the civil movement 'Krassnaya Moskva - Red Moscow - Patriotic Front Aid' which organised public demonstrations supporting separatists, thereby supporting policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. On 20 March 2014 he voted in favour of the draft Federal Constitutional Law 'on the acceptance into the Russian Federation of the Republic of Crimea and the formation within the Russian Federation of new federal subjects - the republic of Crimea and the City of Federal Status Sevastopol'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/148/marg/4">16.2.2015
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/149">Informasjonen om nedenstående listeførte enhet erstattes med følgende:
<br/></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/150">
        <i>33. Prizrak brigade ('Бригада 'Призрак')</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/150/marg/1">Armed separatist which has actively supported actions which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine, and further destabilised Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/150/marg/2">16.2.2015</marg>
      </ledd>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/ii" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-12-03-1389/kii">
      <kverdi>II</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/ii/ledd/1">Endringene trer i kraft straks.</ledd>
    </kapittel>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
