<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2015-02-25-161" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2015-02-25-161</id>
    <dato>25.02.2015 nr. 161</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2015-02-25</dato>
    <publisert>I 2015 hefte 2 s 239</publisert>
    <ikraft>25.02.2015</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2015-02-25</ikraft>
    <departement>Helse- og omsorgsdepartementet</departement>
    <departement>Landbruks- og matdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§23">L19.12.2003 nr. 124 § 23</ref>, <ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§16">§ 16</ref>, <ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§17">§ 17</ref></hjemmel>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2008-05-27-508</endrer>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2015-0144</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Guarkjernemelforskriften</korttittel>
    <korttittel>3 Forskrift om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av guarkjernemel fra India (guarkjernemelforskriften) (Nr. 161)</korttittel>
    <tittel>Forskrift om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av guarkjernemel fra India (guarkjernemelforskriften)</tittel>
    <marg niv="1" id="/marg/1"><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Mattilsynet 25. februar 2015 med hjemmel i lov 19. desember 2003 nr. 124 om matproduksjon og mattrygghet mv. (matloven) § 23 tredje ledd, jf. § 16 og § 17.
<br/><b>EØS-henvisning:</b> EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kap. I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2015/175).</marg>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/p1">
      <pverdi>§ 1.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Virkeområde</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/1/ledd/1">Forskriften gjelder kontroll ved import av guarkjernemel med opprinnelse i eller sendt fra India, med varenummer ex 13.02.3200, til bruk som næringsmiddel eller fôrvare når Norge er innførselssted i EØS-området.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/1/ledd/2">Forskriften gjelder også import av produkter som inneholder mer enn 20 % av guarkjernemel, som nevnt i første ledd.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/1/ledd/3">Forskriften omfatter ikke personlige forsendelser med næringsmidler eller fôrvarer beregnet på privat bruk.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/1/ledd/4">Ved konflikt mellom forordningens bestemmelser og denne bestemmelse, går alltid forordningens bestemmelser foran.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/p2">
      <pverdi>§ 2.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Importbetingelser for guarkjernemel fra India</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/2/ledd/1">EØS-avtalens vedlegg I kapittel I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2015/175) om særlige importbetingelser ved import av guarkjernemel med opprinnelse i eller sendt fra India som følge av risiko for forurensing av pentaklorfenol og dioksiner gjelder som forskrift med de tilpasninger som følger av vedlegg I og II, protokoll 1 til avtalen og avtalen for øvrig.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/p3">
      <pverdi>§ 3.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Utpekte importsteder</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/3/ledd/1">Mattilsynets grensekontrollstasjoner ved Oslo lufthavn, Oslo havn, Borg havn og Larvik havn utpekes som innførselssteder i henhold til forordning (EU) 2015/175 artikkel 3.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/3/ledd/2">Driftsansvarlig for næringsmiddel- eller fôrforetaket eller dennes representant skal fremstille forsendelsen for kontroll ved ett av disse importstedene.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/p4">
      <pverdi>§ 4.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Gebyr</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/4/ledd/1">Driftsansvarlig for næringsmiddel- eller fôrforetaket eller dennes representant skal betale gebyr for den offentlige kontrollen ved import av forsendelser av næringsmidler og fôrvarer.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2">For import av forsendelser av næringsmidler og fôrvarer skal det betales:
<liste id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/a/avsnitt/1">kr 1440,- per forsendelse for dokumentkontroll,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/b/avsnitt/1">kr 720,- per time eller kr 360,- per påbegynt halvtime når det gjennomføres identitetskontroll og fysisk kontroll av forsendelsen, og</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/c/avsnitt/1">kostnadene for analyseprøvene for forsendelsen.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/5" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/p5">
      <pverdi>§ 5.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Tilsyn og vedtak</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/5/ledd/1">Mattilsynet fører tilsyn og kan fatte nødvendige enkeltvedtak, jf. matloven § 23, for å oppnå etterlevelse av bestemmelser gitt i eller i medhold av denne forskriften. Mattilsynet kan også fatte enkeltvedtak i henhold til matloven § 24 til § 26.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/6" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/p6">
      <pverdi>§ 6.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Straff</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/6/ledd/1">Overtredelse av bestemmelser gitt i denne forskriften eller enkeltvedtak gitt i medhold av forskriften, er straffbart i henhold til matloven § 28.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/7" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/p7">
      <pverdi>§ 7.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Ikrafttredelse</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/7/ledd/1">Denne forskriften trer i kraft straks. Samtidig oppheves forskrift 27. mai 2008 nr. 508 om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av guarkjernemel fra India.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/k1">
      <kverdi/>
      <ktittel> Forordninger</ktittel>
      <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/1/overskrift/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/k1/?2">
        <kverdi/>
        <ktittel> Forordning (EU) 2015/175</ktittel>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/1/overskrift/2/ledd/1">Nedenfor gjengis til informasjon EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kapittel I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2015/175) med de endringer og tillegg som følger av EØS-tilpasningen av rettsakten i samsvar med vedlegg I og II, og protokoll I til EØS-avtalen.</ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/1/overskrift/2/ledd/2">Helsesertifikatet nevnt i artikkel 5 finnes under vedlegget i pdf-filen nedenfor.</ledd>
        <forordning>
          <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175">
            <kverdi/>
            <ktittel align="center"> COMMISSION IMPLEMENTING REGULATION (EU) 2015.175 <br/> of 5 February 2015 <br/> laying down special conditions applicable to the import of guar gum originating in or consigned from India due to contamination risks by pentachlorophenol and dioxins <br/> (Text with EEA relevance) <br/></ktittel>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/1">THE EUROPEAN COMMISSION,</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/2">Having regard to the Treaty on the Functioning of the European Union,</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/3">Having regard to Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 28 January 2002 laying down the general principles and requirements of food law, establishing the European Food Safety Authority and laying down procedures in matters of food safety,<fref id="/fotnote/1">1</fref> and in particular Article 53(1)(b)(ii) thereof,
<br/></ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/4">Whereas:</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/5">(1) Article 53(1) of Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 provides for the possibility to adopt appropriate Union emergency measures for feed and food imported from a third country in order to protect human health, animal health and the environment, where the risk cannot be contained satisfactorily by means of measures taken by the Member States individually.</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/6">(2) In July 2007, high levels of pentachlorophenol (PCP) and dioxins have been found in the Union in certain batches of guar gum originating in or consigned from India. Such contamination constitutes a threat to public health within the Union if no measures are taken to avoid the presence of pentachlorophenol and dioxins in guar gum.</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/7">(3) Therefore special conditions on the imports of guar gum originating in or consigned from India were established by Commission Decision 2008/352/EC,<fref id="2">2</fref> later replaced by Commission Regulation (EU) No 258/2010,<fref id="3">3</fref> due to contamination risks by pentachlorophenol and dioxins.</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/8">(4) As follow-up to the audits of the Food and Veterinary Office of the European Commission (FVO) in 2007 and 2009, another audit took place in October 2011 in order to assess the systems in place to control PCP and dioxin contamination in guar gum originating in or consigned from India and intended for export to the Union.</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/9">(5) During the audit of October 2011 the FVO observed that the competent authority of India has put in place a procedure to ensure that sampling is undertaken by one of two designated sampling bodies, in line with Union sampling provisions provided for in Commission Directive 2002/63/EC<fref id="4">4</fref> and that all exported lots are accompanied by a certificate and by an analytical report from a laboratory accredited in accordance with EN ISO/IEC 17025 for the analysis of PCP in feed and food. The FVO noted that due to that procedure contaminated lots are not exported to the Union.</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/10">(6) The European Union Reference Laboratory for Dioxins and PCBs in Feed and Food has carried out a study on the correlation between PCP and dioxins in contaminated guar gum from India. From this study it can be concluded that guar gum containing a level of PCP below the Maximum Residue Limit (MRL) of 0,01 mg/kg does not contain unacceptable levels of dioxins. Therefore compliance with the MRL on PCP, ensures in this specific case also a high level of human health protection as regards dioxins</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/11">(7) The laboratory is still finding high levels of PCP in guar gum powder for export for use in food. As the legal status of PCP for industrial use remains unclear in India and as there is no evidence of the source of contamination, and no investigations on the source of contamination of non-compliant lots are undertaken, the potential for contaminated lots remains.</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/12">(8) Those findings indicate that the contamination of guar gum with PCP cannot be regarded as an isolated incident and that only the effective analysis by the approved laboratory has prevented contaminated product from being further exported to the Union.</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/13">(9) As the source of contamination is not yet eliminated it is appropriate to maintain special conditions for import. However, it is appropriate to bring the control measures at import in line with existing control measures at import applicable to certain food and feed of non-animal origin. Given that such alignment entails several changes, it is appropriate to repeal Regulation (EU) No 258/2010 and replace it by a new Implementing Regulation.</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/14">(10) The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on Plants, Animals, Food and Feed,
<fotnote id="/fotnote/1">1 OJ L 31, 1.2.2002, p. 1.</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/2">2 Commission Decision 2008/352/EC of 29 April 2008 imposing special conditions governing guar gum originating in or consigned from India due to contamination risks of those products by pentachlorophenol and dioxins (OJ L 117, 1.5.2008, p. 42).</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/3">3 Commission Regulation (EU) No 258/2010 of 25 March 2010 imposing special conditions on the imports of guar gum originating in or consigned from India due to contamination risks of those products by pentachlorophenol and dioxins and repealing Decision 2008/352/EC (OJ L 80, 26.3.2010, p. 28).</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/4">4 Commission Directive 2002/63/EC of 11 July 2002 establishing Community methods of sampling for the official control of pesticides residues in and on products of plant and animal origin and repealing Directive 79/700/EEC (OJ L 187, 16.7.2002, p. 30).
<br/></fotnote></ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/ledd/15">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</ledd>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g1">
              <pverdi>Article 1</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Scope</ptittel>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/1/ledd/1/liste/1">
                <lverdi>1.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/1/ledd/1/liste/1/avsnitt/1">This Regulation shall apply to consignments of guar gum falling within CN code ex 1302 32 90, TARIC subdivision 10 and 19, originating in or consigned from India and intended for animal or human consumption.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/1/ledd/1/liste/2">
                <lverdi>2.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/1/ledd/1/liste/2/avsnitt/1">This Regulation shall also apply to consignments of compound feed and food containing guar gum referred to in paragraph 1 in a quantity above 20 %.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/1/ledd/1/liste/3">
                <lverdi>3.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/1/ledd/1/liste/3/avsnitt/1">This Regulation shall not apply to consignments referred to in paragraphs 1 and 2 which are destined to a private person for personal consumption and use only. In case of doubt on the destination of the consignment, the burden of proof lies with the recipient of the consignment.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/1/ledd/1/liste/4">
                <lverdi>4.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/1/ledd/1/liste/4/avsnitt/1">This Regulation shall be without prejudice to the provisions of Council Regulation (EEC) No 2913/92.<fref id="1">1</fref></avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <fotnote id="/fotnote/1+">1 Council Regulation (EEC) No 2913/92 of 12 October 1992 establishing the Community Customs Code (OJ L 302, 19.10.1992, p. 1).</fotnote>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g2">
              <pverdi>Article 2</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Definitions</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/2/ledd/1">For the purposes of this Regulation, the definitions laid down in Articles 2 and 3 of Regulation (EC) No 178/2002, Article 2 of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council<fref id="1">1</fref> and Article 3 of Commission Regulation (EC) No 669/2009<fref id="2">2</fref> shall apply.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/2/ledd/2">For the purpose of this Regulation, a consignment corresponds to a lot as referred to in Commission Directive 2002/63/EC.
<fotnote id="/fotnote/1++">1 Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 29 April 2004 on official controls performed to ensure the verification of compliance with feed and food law, animal health and animal welfare rules (OJ L 165, 30.4.2004, p. 1).</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/2+">2 Commission Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 of 24 July 2009 implementing Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council as regards the increased level of official controls on imports of certain feed and food of non-animal origin and amending Decision 2006/504/EC (OJ L 194, 25.7.2009, p. 11).</fotnote></ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g3">
              <pverdi>Article 3</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Import into the Union</ptittel>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/3/ledd/1/liste/1">
                <lverdi>1.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/3/ledd/1/liste/1/avsnitt/1">Consignments referred to in Article 1(1) and (2) may only be imported into the Union in accordance with the procedures laid down in this Regulation.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/3/ledd/1/liste/2">
                <lverdi>2.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/3/ledd/1/liste/2/avsnitt/1">Consignments referred to in Article 1(1) and (2) may only enter the Union through a Designated Point of Entry (DPE) as defined in Regulation (EC) No 669/2009.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g4">
              <pverdi>Article 4</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Analytical report</ptittel>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/1">
                <lverdi>1.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/1/avsnitt/1">Consignments referred to in Article 1(1) and (2) shall be accompanied by an analytical report issued by a laboratory accredited in accordance with EN ISO/IEC 17025 for the analysis of PCP in feed and food, demonstrating that the product imported does not contain more than 0,01 mg/kg pentachlorophenol (PCP).</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/2">
                <lverdi>2.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/2/avsnitt/1">The analytical report shall indicate:</avsnitt>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/2.a">
                  <lverdi>(a)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/2.a/avsnitt/1">the results of sampling and analysis for the presence of PCP, performed by the competent authorities of the country of origin, or of the country where the consignment is consigned from if that country is different from the country of origin;</avsnitt>
                </liste>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/2.b">
                  <lverdi>(b)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/2.b/avsnitt/1">the measurement uncertainty of the analytical result;</avsnitt>
                </liste>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/2.c">
                  <lverdi>(c)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/2.c/avsnitt/1">the limit of detection (LOD) of the analytical method; and</avsnitt>
                </liste>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/2.d">
                  <lverdi>(d)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/2.d/avsnitt/1">the limit of quantification (LOQ) of the analytical method.</avsnitt>
                </liste>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/3">
                <lverdi>3.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/3/avsnitt/1">The sampling referred to in paragraph 2 shall be performed in accordance with Directive 2002/63/EC.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/4">
                <lverdi>4.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/4/ledd/1/liste/4/avsnitt/1">The extraction before analysis shall be performed with an acidified solvent. The analysis shall be carried out according to the modified version of the Quechers method as set out on the website of the European Union Reference Laboratories for Residues of Pesticides<fref id="1">1</fref> or according to an equally reliable method.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <fotnote id="/fotnote/1+++">1 http://www.eurl-pesticides.eu/library/docs/srm/QuechersForGuarGum.pdf</fotnote>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/5" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g5">
              <pverdi>Article 5</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Health certificate</ptittel>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/5/ledd/1/liste/1">
                <lverdi>1.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/5/ledd/1/liste/1/avsnitt/1">The consignments referred to in Article 1(1) and (2) shall be accompanied by a health certificate corresponding to the model set out in the Annex.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/5/ledd/1/liste/2">
                <lverdi>2.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/5/ledd/1/liste/2/avsnitt/1">The health certificate shall be completed, signed and verified by an authorised representative of the competent authority of the country of origin, the Ministry of Commerce and Industry of India, or of the country where the consignment is consigned from if that country is different from the country of origin.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/5/ledd/1/liste/3">
                <lverdi>3.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/5/ledd/1/liste/3/avsnitt/1">The health certificate shall be drawn up in one of the official languages of the Member State where the designated point of entry is located. However, a Member State may consent that health certificates be drawn up in another official language of the Union.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/5/ledd/1/liste/4">
                <lverdi>4.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/5/ledd/1/liste/4/avsnitt/1">The health certificate shall be valid for four months from the date of its issue.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/6" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g6">
              <pverdi>Article 6</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Identification</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/6/ledd/1">Each consignment referred to in Article 1(1) and (2) shall be identified with an identification code. That code shall be identical to the identification code appearing on the analytical report referred to in Article 4 and on the health certificate referred to in Article 5.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/6/ledd/2">Each individual bag or package of the consignment shall be identified with that identification code.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/7" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g7">
              <pverdi>Article 7</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Prior notification of consignments</ptittel>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/7/ledd/1/liste/1">
                <lverdi>1.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/7/ledd/1/liste/1/avsnitt/1">Feed and food business operators shall give prior notification to the competent authorities at the DPE of:</avsnitt>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/7/ledd/1/liste/1.a">
                  <lverdi>(a)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/7/ledd/1/liste/1.a/avsnitt/1">the estimated date and time of physical arrival of the consignment; and</avsnitt>
                </liste>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/7/ledd/1/liste/1.b">
                  <lverdi>(b)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/7/ledd/1/liste/1.b/avsnitt/1">the nature of the consignment.</avsnitt>
                </liste>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/7/ledd/1/liste/2">
                <lverdi>2.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/7/ledd/1/liste/2/avsnitt/1">For the purpose of prior notification, feed and food business operators shall complete Part I of the common entry document (CED) provided for in Regulation (EC) No 669/2009. They shall transmit that document to the competent authority at the DPE at least one working day prior to the arrival of the consignment.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/7/ledd/1/liste/3">
                <lverdi>3.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/7/ledd/1/liste/3/avsnitt/1">For the completion of the CED, feed and food business operators shall take into account the notes for guidance for the CED laid down in Annex II to Regulation (EC) No 669/2009.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g8">
              <pverdi>Article 8</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Official controls</ptittel>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/1">
                <lverdi>1.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/1/avsnitt/1">The competent authority at the DPE shall carry out documentary checks of each consignment referred to in Article 1(1) and (2) to ensure compliance with the requirements laid down in Articles 4 and 5.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/2">
                <lverdi>2.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/2/avsnitt/1">The identity and physical checks of consignments referred to in Article 1(1) and (2) of this Regulation shall be carried out in accordance with Articles 8, 9 and 19 of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 at a frequency of 5 %.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/3">
                <lverdi>3.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/3/avsnitt/1">After completion of the checks, the competent authorities shall:</avsnitt>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/3.a">
                  <lverdi>(a)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/3.a/avsnitt/1">complete the relevant entries in Part II of the CED;</avsnitt>
                </liste>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/3.b">
                  <lverdi>(b)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/3.b/avsnitt/1">attach the results of the checks carried out in accordance with paragraph 2 of this Article;</avsnitt>
                </liste>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/3.c">
                  <lverdi>(c)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/3.c/avsnitt/1">provide and fill the CED reference number on the CED;</avsnitt>
                </liste>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/3.d">
                  <lverdi>(d)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/3.d/avsnitt/1">stamp and sign the original of the CED;</avsnitt>
                </liste>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/3.e">
                  <lverdi>(e)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/3.e/avsnitt/1">make and retain a copy of the signed and stamped CED.</avsnitt>
                </liste>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/4">
                <lverdi>4.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/4/avsnitt/1">The original of the CED, of the health certificate referred to in Article 5 and of the analytical report referred to in Article 4 shall accompany the consignment during its transport until it is released into free circulation.</avsnitt>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/8/ledd/1/liste/4/avsnitt/2">In case of authorisation of onward transportation of the consignment pending the results of the physical checks, as provided for in the third subparagraph of Article 8(2) of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009, an authenticated copy of the original CED shall accompany the consignment in place of the original.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/9" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g9">
              <pverdi>Article 9</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Splitting of a consignment</ptittel>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/9/ledd/1/liste/1">
                <lverdi>1.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/9/ledd/1/liste/1/avsnitt/1">Consignments shall not be split until all official controls have been completed, and the CED has been fully completed by the competent authorities as provided for in Article 8.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/9/ledd/1/liste/2">
                <lverdi>2.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/9/ledd/1/liste/2/avsnitt/1">In the case of subsequent splitting of the consignment, an authenticated copy of the CED shall accompany each part of the consignment during its transport until it is released for free circulation.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/10" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g10">
              <pverdi>Article 10</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Release into free circulation</ptittel>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/10/ledd/1/liste/1">
                <lverdi>1.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/10/ledd/1/liste/1/avsnitt/1">The release of consignments into free circulation shall be subject to the presentation by the feed or food business operator to the custom authorities of a CED duly completed by the competent authority once all official controls have been carried out. The CED may be presented physically or electronically.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/10/ledd/1/liste/2">
                <lverdi>2.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/10/ledd/1/liste/2/avsnitt/1">The custom authorities shall only release the consignment into free circulation if a favourable decision by the competent authority is indicated in box II.14 of the CED and box II.21 thereof is signed.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/11" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g11">
              <pverdi>Article 11</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Non-compliance</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/11/ledd/1">If the official controls establish non-compliance with the relevant Union legislation, the competent authority shall complete Part III of the CED and action shall be taken pursuant to Articles 19, 20 and 21 of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/12" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g12">
              <pverdi>Article 12</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Reports</ptittel>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/12/ledd/1/liste/1">
                <lverdi>1.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/12/ledd/1/liste/1/avsnitt/1">Member States shall submit to the Commission every three months a report summarising the analytical reports of official controls of consignments referred to in Article 1(1) and (2) pursuant to this Regulation. That report shall be submitted during the month following each quarter.</avsnitt>
              </liste>
              <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/12/ledd/1/liste/2">
                <lverdi>2.</lverdi>
                <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/12/ledd/1/liste/2/avsnitt/1">The report shall include the following information:</avsnitt>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/12/ledd/1/liste/2.a">
                  <lverdi>(a)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/12/ledd/1/liste/2.a/avsnitt/1">the number of consignments imported;</avsnitt>
                </liste>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/12/ledd/1/liste/2.b">
                  <lverdi>(b)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/12/ledd/1/liste/2.b/avsnitt/1">the number of consignments subjected to sampling for analysis;</avsnitt>
                </liste>
                <liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/12/ledd/1/liste/2.c">
                  <lverdi>(c)</lverdi>
                  <avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/12/ledd/1/liste/2.c/avsnitt/1">the results of the checks as provided for in Article 8(2).</avsnitt>
                </liste>
              </liste>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/13" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g13">
              <pverdi>Article 13</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Costs</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/13/ledd/1">All costs resulting from the official controls and any measures taken following non-compliance shall be borne by the feed and food business operators.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/14" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g14">
              <pverdi>Article 14</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Repeal</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/14/ledd/1">Regulation (EU) No 258/2010 is repealed.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/15" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g15">
              <pverdi>Article 15</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Transitional provisions</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/15/ledd/1">By way of derogation from Article 5(1), Member States shall authorise the imports of consignments referred to in Article 1(1) and (2) which left the country of origin before the date of entry into force of this Regulation accompanied by a health certificate as provided for by Regulation (EU) No 258/2010.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/16" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/g16">
              <pverdi>Article 16</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Entry into force</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/16/ledd/1">This Regulation shall enter into force on the twentieth day following that of its publication in the Official Journal of the European Union.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/16/ledd/2">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/16/ledd/3">Done at Brussels, 5 February 2015.
<br/></ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/16/ledd/4">
                <i>For the Commission</i>
                <br/>
              </ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/16/ledd/5">
                <i>The President</i>
                <br/>
                <marg niv="1" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/artikkel/16/ledd/5/marg/1">Jean-Claude JUNCKER</marg>
              </ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/overskrift/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/?1/?2/y2015.175/?3">
              <kverdi/>
              <ktittel align="center"> Vedlegg til forordning (EU) nr. 175/2015</ktittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.175/overskrift/3/ledd/1">Se pdf-filen for forordning (EU) 2015/175 nedenfor i avsnittet «Forordninger i PDF» for helsesertifikatet som skal følge forsendelsen.</ledd>
            </kapittel>
          </kapittel>
        </forordning>
      </kapittel>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-02-25-161/k4">
      <kverdi/>
      <ktittel> Forordninger i PDF</ktittel>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/4/ledd/1">Nedenfor gjengis forordning (EU) 2015/175.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/4/ledd/2">For å lese forordning (EU) 2015/175, med sertifikatet i vedlegget, på engelsk se her: <lenke url="https://lovdata.no/static//ltavd1/filer/grafikk/32015r0175e.pdf"><img src="/ltavd1/filer/grafikk/pdf.gif" alt="ikon"/></lenke></ledd>
    </kapittel>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
