<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2015-06-26-807" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2015-06-26-807</id>
    <dato>26.06.2015 nr. 807</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2015-06-26</dato>
    <publisert>I 2015 hefte 8 s 1367</publisert>
    <ikraft>10.07.2015</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2015-07-10</ikraft>
    <departement>Helse- og omsorgsdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§23">L19.12.2003 nr. 124 § 23</ref>, <ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§12">§ 12</ref>, <ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§14">§ 14</ref>, <ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§15">§ 15</ref>, <ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§16">§ 16</ref></hjemmel>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2012-05-04-407</endrer>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2015-0682</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Forskrift om redusert kontroll av importerte næringsmidler</korttittel>
    <korttittel>3 Forskrift om redusert kontroll ved import av næringsmidler som har vært kontrollert før eksport (Nr. 807)</korttittel>
    <tittel>Forskrift om redusert kontroll ved import av næringsmidler som har vært kontrollert før eksport</tittel>
    <redaksjonell_note><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Mattilsynet 26. juni 2015 med hjemmel i lov 19. desember 2003 nr. 124 om matproduksjon og mattrygghet mv. (matloven) § 23 tredje ledd, jf. § 12, § 14, § 15 og § 16.
<br/><b>EØS-henvisninger:</b> EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kap. I innledende del nr. 8 (forordning (EU) 2015/949).</redaksjonell_note>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/p1">
      <pverdi>§ 1.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Virkeområde</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/1/ledd/1">Forskriften omfatter kontroll av visse importerte næringsmidler fra tredjestater, når Norge er første mottakssted innen EØS-området og hvor næringsmidlene har vært kontrollert av myndighetene før eksport. Forskriften omfatter følgende næringsmidler:
<liste id="/paragraf/1/ledd/1/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/paragraf/1/ledd/1/liste/a/avsnitt/1">hvete og hvetemel fra Canada,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/paragraf/1/ledd/1/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/paragraf/1/ledd/1/liste/b/avsnitt/1">jordnøtter (peanøtter) fra USA, og</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/paragraf/1/ledd/1/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/paragraf/1/ledd/1/liste/c/avsnitt/1">mandler fra USA.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/1/ledd/2">Ved konflikt mellom forordningens bestemmelser og denne bestemmelse, går alltid forordningens bestemmelser foran.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/p2">
      <pverdi>§ 2.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Pre-eksportkontroll av næringsmidler og redusert importkontroll</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/2/ledd/1">EØS-avtalens vedlegg I kap. I innledende del nr. 8 (forordning (EU) 2015/949) om godkjennelse av pre-eksportkontroll utført av visse tredjestater på visse næringsmidler med hensyn til forekomst av visse mykotoksiner gjelder som forskrift med de tilpasninger som følger av vedlegg I, protokoll 1 til avtalen og avtalen for øvrig.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/p3">
      <pverdi>§ 3.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Tilsyn og vedtak</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/3/ledd/1">Mattilsynet fører tilsyn og kan fatte nødvendige enkeltvedtak, jf. matloven § 23, for å oppnå etterlevelse av bestemmelser gitt i eller i medhold av denne forskriften. Mattilsynet kan også fatte enkeltvedtak i henhold til matloven § 24 til § 26.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/p4">
      <pverdi>§ 4.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Straff</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/4/ledd/1">Overtredelse av bestemmelser gitt i denne forskriften eller enkeltvedtak gitt i medhold av forskriften, er straffbart i henhold til matloven § 28.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/5" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/p5">
      <pverdi>§ 5.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Ikrafttredelse</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/5/ledd/1">Denne forskrift trer i kraft 10. juli 2015. Samtidig oppheves forskrift 4. mai 2012 nr. 407 om redusert kontroll av importerte næringsmidler som har vært kontrollert i tredjestat før eksport.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/k1">
      <kverdi/>
      <ktittel> Forordninger</ktittel>
      <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/1/overskrift/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/k1/?2">
        <kverdi/>
        <ktittel> Forordning (EU) 2015/949 (engelsk versjon)</ktittel>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/1/overskrift/2/ledd/1">Nedenfor gjengis til informasjon norsk oversettelse av vedlegg I kapittel I innledende del nr. 8 (forordning (EU) 2015/949) med de endringer og tillegg som følger av EØS-tilpasningen av rettsakten i samsvar med vedlegg I til EØS-avtalen.</ledd>
        <forordning>
          <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/?1/?2/y2015.949">
            <kverdi/>
            <ktittel align="center"> COMMISSION IMPLEMENTING REGULATION (EU) 2015.949 <br/> of 19 June 2015 <br/> approving the pre-export checks carried out on certain food by certain third countries as regards the presence of certain mycotoxins <br/> (Text with EEA relevance) <br/></ktittel>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/1">THE EUROPEAN COMMISSION,</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/2">Having regard to the Treaty on the Functioning of the European Union,</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/3">Having regard to Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 29 April 2004 on official controls performed to ensure the verification of compliance with feed and food law, animal health and animal welfare rules,<fref id="/fotnote/1">1</fref> and in particular Article 23 thereof,</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4">Whereas:
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/1"><lverdi>(1)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/1/avsnitt/1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 1881/2006<fref id="2">2</fref> lays down permitted maximum levels of ochratoxin A and aflatoxins in food. Only foods complying with the maximum level may be placed on the Union market.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/2"><lverdi>(2)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/2/avsnitt/1">Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 provides an obligation for the Member States to ensure that official controls are carried out regularly, on a risk basis and with appropriate frequency in order to achieve the objectives of the Regulation, which are, inter alia, preventing, eliminating or reducing to acceptable levels risks to humans and animals.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/3"><lverdi>(3)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/3/avsnitt/1">Article 23 of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 provides that specific pre-export checks that a third country carries out on feed and food immediately prior to export to the European Union with a view to verifying that the exported products satisfy Union requirements may be approved.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/4"><lverdi>(4)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/4/avsnitt/1">Such an approval may only be granted to a third country if an European Union audit has shown that feed or food exported to the European Union meets Union requirements or equivalent requirements and that the controls carried out in the third country prior to dispatch are considered sufficiently effective and efficient as to replace or reduce the documentary, identity and physical checks laid down in EU law.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/5"><lverdi>(5)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/5/avsnitt/1">In April 2005, the United States of America (hereinafter referred to as the 'United States') have submitted to the Commission an application for obtaining an approval of the pre-export checks performed by the competent authorities of the United States on the aflatoxin contamination in peanuts intended for export to the Union.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/6"><lverdi>(6)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/6/avsnitt/1">After an audit performed by the Commission's Food and Veterinary Office (FVO), the approval of those pre-export checks aiming at ensuring compliance with the maximum levels of aflatoxins laid down in Union law was granted by Commission Decision 2008/47/EC.<fref id="3">3</fref></avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/7"><lverdi>(7)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/7/avsnitt/1">On 8 October 2007, Canada submitted to the Commission an application for obtaining an approval of the pre- export checks performed by the competent authorities of Canada on the ochratoxin A contamination in wheat (common and durum) and wheat flour intended for export to the European Union.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/8"><lverdi>(8)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/8/avsnitt/1">The Commission assessed in detail the information provided by the Canadian Grain Commission, the competent authority of Canada under the responsibility of which the pre-export checks are performed, and considered that the guarantees provided are satisfactory in order to accept the application for approval of the pre-export checks on wheat and certain derived products thereof as regards the presence of ochratoxin A. Therefore the approval of those pre-export checks aiming at ensuring compliance with the maximum levels of ochratoxin A laid down in Union law was granted by Commission Implementing Regulation (EU) No 844/2011.<fref id="4">4</fref></avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/9"><lverdi>(9)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/9/avsnitt/1">On 21 November 2012, the United States have submitted to the Commission an application for obtaining an approval of the pre-export checks performed by the competent authorities of the United States of America on the aflatoxin contamination in almonds intended for export to the Union.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/10"><lverdi>(10)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/10/avsnitt/1">After an audit performed by the Commission's FVO and having assessed in detail the additional information provided by the United States, the Commission considers that the guarantees provided are satisfactory and justify the approval of the pre-export checks. It is therefore appropriate to grant approval of those pre-export checks aiming at ensuring compliance with the maximum levels of aflatoxins laid down in Union law.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/11"><lverdi>(11)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/11/avsnitt/1">It is appropriate to have all approvals of pre-export checks carried out by certain third countries as regards the presence of mycotoxins in food into one Regulation in order to simplify legislation and ensure an uniform approach. Therefore, Decision 2008/47/EC and Implementing Regulation (EU) No 844/2011 should be replaced and the rules contained in those acts be merged with this Implementing Regulation. Nevertheless some small changes have been introduced to align the provisions as regards frequency of controls and to update the provisions to reflect changes in CN codes.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/12"><lverdi>(12)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/12/avsnitt/1">In accordance with Article 16(2) of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004, Member States are required to adjust the frequency of physical checks on imports to the risk associated with different categories of food and taking into account, among other things, the guarantees provided by the competent authorities of the third country of origin of the food in question. Systematic pre-export checks carried out under the responsibility of the competent authority of the third country in conformity with the Union approval in accordance with Article 23 of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 provide a satisfactory level of guarantees in relation to the mycotoxin contamination and therefore allow Member States to reduce the frequency of physical checks performed on those commodities.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/13"><lverdi>(13)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/13/avsnitt/1">The low control frequency established in Annex to this Regulation should be followed by Member States importing many consignments of the foodstuffs concerned. Member States importing only a limited number of consignments of the foodstuffs concerned should ensure a low frequency of controls, without being able to comply with the established frequency of controls.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/14"><lverdi>(14)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/4/liste/14/avsnitt/1">The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on Plants, Animals, Food and Feed,
<fotnote id="/fotnote/1">1 OJ L 165, 30.4.2004, p. 1.</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/2">2 Commission Regulation (EC) No 1881/2006 of 19 December 2006 setting maximum levels for certain contaminants in foodstuffs (OJ L 364, 20.12.2006, p. 5).</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/3">3 Commission Decision 2008/47/EC of 20 December 2007 approving the pre-export checks carried out by the United States of America on peanuts and derived products thereof as regards the presence of aflatoxins (OJ L 11, 15.1.2008, p. 12).</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/4">4 Commission Implementing Regulation (EU) No 844/2011 of 23 August 2011 approving the pre-export checks carried out by Canada on wheat and wheat flour as regards the presence of ochratoxin A. (OJ L 218, 24.8.2011, p. 4).
<br/></fotnote></avsnitt></liste></ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/ledd/5">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</ledd>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/?1/?2/y2015.949/g1">
              <pverdi>Article 1</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Approval of pre-export checks</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/1/ledd/1">1. Pre-export checks carried out prior to export to the Union by the Canadian Grain Commission, as competent authority, regarding ochratoxin A in wheat and wheat flour listed in Annex I and produced on the territory of Canada are approved.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/1/ledd/2">2. The following pre-export checks carried out prior to export to the Union by the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), as competent authority, are approved:
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/1/ledd/2/liste/a"><lverdi>(a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/1/ledd/2/liste/a/avsnitt/1">pre-export checks regarding aflatoxins in peanuts listed in Annex I and produced on the territory of the United States;</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/1/ledd/2/liste/b"><lverdi>(b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/1/ledd/2/liste/b/avsnitt/1">pre-export checks regarding aflatoxins in almonds listed in Annex I and produced on the territory of the United States.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/?1/?2/y2015.949/g2">
              <pverdi>Article 2</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Accompanying documents and identification of the consignments</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/2/ledd/1">1. Each consignment of products referred to in Article 1 shall be accompanied by:
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/a"><lverdi>(a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/a/avsnitt/1">a report containing the results of sampling and analysis performed in accordance with the provisions of Commission Regulation (EC) No 401/2006,<fref id="1">1</fref> or with equivalent requirements, by a laboratory approved for that purpose by the competent authority;</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/b"><lverdi>(b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/b/avsnitt/1">a certificate in accordance with the model set out in Annex II, completed, verified and signed by a representative of the competent authority; the certificate shall be valid for four months from the date of issuance.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/2/ledd/2">2. Each consignment of products referred to in Article 1 shall bear an identification code which shall be reproduced on the report and on the certificate referred to in paragraph 1. Each individual bag, or other packaging form, or packaging combining several individual entities into one package, of the consignment shall be identified with the same code.
<fotnote id="/fotnote/1+">1 Commission Regulation (EC) No 401/2006 of 23 February 2006 laying down the methods of sampling and analysis for the official control of mycotoxins in foodstuffs (OJ L 70, 9.3.2006, p. 12).</fotnote></ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/?1/?2/y2015.949/g3">
              <pverdi>Article 3</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Splitting of consignments</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/3/ledd/1">If a consignment is split, copies of the certificate provided for in Article 2(1)(b) and certified by the competent authority of the Member State on whose territory the splitting has taken place, shall accompany each part of the split consignment until it is released for free circulation.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/?1/?2/y2015.949/g4">
              <pverdi>Article 4</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Official controls</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/4/ledd/1">In accordance with the provisions of Article 16(2) and Article 23(2) of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004, the frequency of the physical checks carried out by the Member States on consignments of products referred to in Article 1 and presented in accordance with Article 2 shall be reduced to the maximum percentage of the number of presented consignments as set out in Annex I.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/5" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/?1/?2/y2015.949/g5">
              <pverdi>Article 5</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Repeal</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/5/ledd/1">Decision 2008/47/EC and Implementing Regulation (EU) No 844/2011 are hereby repealed.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/5/ledd/2">References to the repealed Decision and Implementing Regulation shall be construed as references to this Regulation.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/6" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/?1/?2/y2015.949/g6">
              <pverdi>Article 6</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Entry into force</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/6/ledd/1">This Regulation shall enter into force on the twentieth day following that of its publication in the <i>Official Journal of the European Union</i>.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/6/ledd/2">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949/artikkel/6/ledd/3">Done at Brussels, 19 June 2015.
<br/></ledd>
              <table niv="1" frame="0">
                <tgroup cols="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
                  <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="26*"/>
                  <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="50*"/>
                  <tbody>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">
                        <i>For the Commission</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="2"> </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">
                        <i>The President</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="2"> </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Jean-Claude JUNCKER </entry>
                      <entry colname="2"> </entry>
                    </row>
                  </tbody>
                </tgroup>
              </table>
            </artikkel>
            <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949wi" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/?1/?2/y2015.949/wi">
              <kverdi>ANNEX I</kverdi>
              <ktittel/>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949wi/ledd/1">Produkter nevnt i artikkel 1 og frekvens for den fysiske kontrollen nevnt i artikkel 4:</ledd>
              <table niv="1" frame="1">
                <thgroup cols="6" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
                  <colspec colname="1" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
                  <colspec colname="2" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="3" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="13*"/>
                  <colspec colname="4" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="5" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="6" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <tbody>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">
                        <b>Næringsmiddel</b>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">
                        <b>KN-kode</b>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">
                        <b>Norsk varenummer</b>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="4">
                        <b>Opprinnelsesstat</b>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="5">
                        <b>Mykotoksin</b>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="6">
                        <b>Hyppighet av fysiske kontroller (%) ved import</b>
                      </entry>
                    </row>
                  </tbody>
                </thgroup>
                <tgroup cols="6" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
                  <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
                  <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="13*"/>
                  <colspec colname="4" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="5" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="6" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <tbody>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Hvete </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">1001 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">10.01 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4"><br/>Canada </entry>
                      <entry colname="5"><br/>Okratoksin A </entry>
                      <entry colname="6"><br/>&lt; 1 </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Hvetemel </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">1101 00 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">11.01.0000 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4"/>
                      <entry colname="5"/>
                      <entry colname="6"> </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Jordnøtter (peanøtter), med skall </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">1202 41 00 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">12.02.4190 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4"><br/><br/><br/>USA </entry>
                      <entry colname="5"><br/><br/><br/>Aflatoksiner </entry>
                      <entry colname="6"><br/><br/><br/>&lt; 1 </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Jordnøtter (peanøtter), uten skall </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">1202 42 00 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">12.02.4290 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4"/>
                      <entry colname="5"/>
                      <entry colname="6"> </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Jordnøtter (peanøtter), tilberedt/konservert på annen måte </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">2008 11 91;
<br/>2008 11 96;
<br/>2008 11 98 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3"><br/>20.08.1180;
<br/>20.08.1191 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4"/>
                      <entry colname="5"/>
                      <entry colname="6"> </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Mandler, med skall </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">0802 11 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">08.02.1100 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4">USA </entry>
                      <entry colname="5">Aflatoksiner </entry>
                      <entry colname="6">&lt; 1 </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Mandler, uten skall </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">0802 12 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">08.02.1200 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4"/>
                      <entry colname="5"/>
                      <entry colname="6"> </entry>
                    </row>
                  </tbody>
                </tgroup>
              </table>
            </kapittel>
            <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949wii" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/?1/?2/y2015.949/wii">
              <kverdi>ANNEX II</kverdi>
              <ktittel/>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2015.949wii/ledd/1">Se pdf-filen for forordning (EU) 2015/949 nedenfor i avsnittet «Forordninger i PDF» for helsesertifikatet som skal følge forsendelsen.</ledd>
            </kapittel>
          </kapittel>
        </forordning>
      </kapittel>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2015-06-26-807/k3">
      <kverdi/>
      <ktittel> Forordninger i pdf</ktittel>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/3/ledd/1">Nedenfor gjengis forordning (EU) 2015/949.
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/3/ledd/1/marg/1">For å lese forordning (EU) 2015/949, med helsesertifikatet i vedlegg II, på engelsk se her: <lenke url="https://lovdata.no/static//ltavd1/filer/grafikk/32015r0949e.pdf"><img src="/ltavd1/filer/grafikk/pdf.gif" alt="ikon"/></lenke></marg></ledd>
    </kapittel>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
