<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2017-12-20-2329" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2017-12-20-2329</id>
    <dato>20.12.2017 nr. 2329</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2017-12-20</dato>
    <ikraft>01.01.2018</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2018-01-01</ikraft>
    <departement>Samferdselsdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="lov-1993-06-11-101-§9-1">L11.06.1993 nr. 101 § 9-1</ref>, <ref id="lov-1993-06-11-101-§9-2">§ 9-2</ref>, <ref id="lov-1993-06-11-101-§9-7">§ 9-7</ref>, <ref id="for-1999-12-10-1265">F10.12.1999 nr. 1265</ref>, <ref id="for-1999-12-10-1273">F10.12.1999 nr. 1273</ref></hjemmel>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/1995-01-11-42</endrer>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2006-12-11-1388</endrer>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2007-10-16-1152</endrer>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2016-01-22-49</endrer>
    <rettet>03.01.2018 (<ref id="for-1999-12-10-1273-§13">§ 13</ref> første ledd bokstav b)</rettet>
    <journalnummer>2017-1516</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Regulations on observation flights conducted under the Treaty on Open Skies</korttittel>
    <tittel>Regulations on observation flights conducted under the Treaty on Open Skies</tittel>
    <marg niv="1" id="/marg/1"><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Luftfartstilsynet 20. desember 2017 med hjemmel i lov 11. juni 1993 nr. 101 om luftfart (luftfartsloven) § 9-1, § 9-2 og § 9-7, jf. delegeringsvedtak 10. desember 1999 nr. 1265 og delegeringsvedtak 10. desember 1999 nr. 1273.
<br/></marg>
    <ledd id="/ledd/1">Adopted by Luftfartstilsynet 20 December 2017 pursuant to Act of 11 June 1993 No 101 on aviation <ref id="=lov-19930611-101-p9-1">§ 9-1</ref>, <ref id="=lov-19930611-101-p9-2">§ 9-2</ref> and <ref id="=lov-19930611-101-p9-7">§ 9-7</ref>, cf. Royal Decree of <ref id="=for-19991210-1265">10 December 1999 No 1265</ref>; cf. the Ministry of Transport and Communications' Delegation Decision of <ref id="=for-19991210-1273">10 December 1999 No 1273</ref>.</ledd>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g1">
      <pverdi>Section 1</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Purpose</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/1/ledd/1">The purpose of these regulations is to clarify the conduct of observation flights by state parties, which are considered civil aviation flights, when performing observation flights in Norway and Norwegian airspace in accordance with the Treaty on Open Skies of 24 March 1992.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g2">
      <pverdi>Section 2</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Definitions and abbreviations</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1">For the purpose of these Regulations, the below terms from the Treaty on Open Skies are meant to be understood as follows:
<liste id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/a/avsnitt/1">«Observed Party» means the State Party, i.e. Norway, or group of States Parties, over whose territory an observation flight is conducted or is intended to be conducted, from the time it has received notification thereof from an observing Party until completion of the procedures relating to that flight, or personnel acting on behalf of that State Party or group of States Parties.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/b/avsnitt/1">«Observing Party» means the State Party or group of States Parties that intends to conduct or conducts an observation flight over the territory of another State Party or group of States Parties, from the time that it has provided notification of its intention to conduct an observation flight until completion of the procedures relating to that flight, or personnel acting on behalf of that State Party or group of States Parties.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/c/avsnitt/1">«Point of entry» means a point designated by the observed Party for the arrival of personnel of the observing Party on the territory of the observed Party.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/d"><lverdi>d)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/d/avsnitt/1">«Point of exit» means a point designated by the observed Party for the departure of personnel of the observing Party from the territory of the observed Party.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/e"><lverdi>e)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/e/avsnitt/1">«Open Skies airfield» means an airfield designated by the observed Party as a point where an observation flight may commence or terminate.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/f"><lverdi>f)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/f/avsnitt/1">«Refuelling airfield» means an airfield designated by the observed Party used for fuelling and servicing of observation aircraft and transport aircraft.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/g"><lverdi>g)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/g/avsnitt/1">«Observation aircraft» means an unarmed, fixed wing aircraft designated to make observation flights, registered by the relevant authorities of a State Party and equipped with agreed sensors.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/h"><lverdi>h)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/2/ledd/1/liste/h/avsnitt/1">«Sensor» means equipment of a category specified in Article IV, paragraph 1 of the Treaty on Open Skies that is installed on an observation aircraft for use during the conduct of observation flights.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/2/ledd/2">For the purpose of these Regulations, the below abbreviations are meant to be understood as follows:
<liste id="/artikkel/2/ledd/2/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/2/ledd/2/liste/a/avsnitt/1">AMSL: Above Mean Sea Level</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/2/ledd/2/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/2/ledd/2/liste/b/avsnitt/1">ATC: Air Traffic Control.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g3">
      <pverdi>Section 3</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Principal rule</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/3/ledd/1">All observation flights must be carried out in accordance with the Treaty on Open Skies, the filed flight plan (FPL) and applicable air traffic regulations.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g4">
      <pverdi>Section 4</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Point of entry/exit</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/4/ledd/1">Point of entry and point of exit shall be Oslo Airport, Gardermoen (ENGM), N 60-12-10, E 011-05-02.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/5" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g5">
      <pverdi>Section 5</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Open Skies Airfields</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/5/ledd/1">The following are the Norwegian Open Skies airfields:
<liste id="/artikkel/5/ledd/1/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/5/ledd/1/liste/a/avsnitt/1">Oslo Airport, Gardermoen (ENGM), N 60-12-10, E 011-05-02</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/5/ledd/1/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/5/ledd/1/liste/b/avsnitt/1">Bardufoss Airport (ENDU), N69-03-21, E 018-32-25.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/6" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g6">
      <pverdi>Section 6</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Refuelling airfield</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/6/ledd/1">Refuelling may take place at Trondheim Airport, Værnes (ENVA), N 63-27-27, E 010-55-27.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/7" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g7">
      <pverdi>Section 7</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Priority</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/7/ledd/1">In accordance with the Treaty on Open Skies, aircraft undertaking observation flights are to be afforded priority over any regular air traffic.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/7/ledd/2">When within controlled airspace, observation flights are to be afforded non-deviating status and priority over all other aircraft except
<liste id="/artikkel/7/ledd/2/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/7/ledd/2/liste/a/avsnitt/1">aircraft in an emergency</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/7/ledd/2/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/7/ledd/2/liste/b/avsnitt/1">aircraft performing roles where the safety of life is involved</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/7/ledd/2/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/7/ledd/2/liste/c/avsnitt/1">aircraft transporting heads of state</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/7/ledd/2/liste/d"><lverdi>d)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/7/ledd/2/liste/d/avsnitt/1">state aircraft performing roles for national security.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/7/ledd/3">Observation flights outside of controlled airspace (Class G airspace) must be carried out in accordance with standardised European visual flight rules (VFR) and give way accordingly.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/8" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g8">
      <pverdi>Section 8</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Flight Safety</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/8/ledd/1">In order to ensure the highest level of flight safety all observation flights should be carried out in controlled airspace. All flights in controlled airspace requires ATC clearance. Except when necessary for take-off or landing flights in terminal control areas (TMA) must be carried out at minimum 7000 feet AMSL.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/8/ledd/2">For flight safety reasons and to assist in affording priority over other regular air traffic, whilst operating outside of controlled airspace (Class G airspace), observation flights are strongly recommended to remain within the bounds of radio and surveillance coverage.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/8/ledd/3">For flight safety reasons it should be published a NOTAM that informs about the observation flights.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/9" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g9">
      <pverdi>Section 9</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Existing restricted and danger areas</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/9/ledd/1">Restricted and danger areas that are effected by observation flights shall be deactivated, and information to relevant operators and agencies shall be distributed accordingly.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/9/ledd/2">If the area in question cannot be deactivated, Norwegian armed forces personnel must ensure that the flight can be safely conducted.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/10" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g10">
      <pverdi>Section 10</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Language proficiency</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/10/ledd/1">For flight safety reasons the pilot and pilot-in-command must have minimum Operational Level (Level 4) in English in accordance with the ICAO Language Proficiency Rating Scale.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/11" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g11">
      <pverdi>Section 11</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Inspection of observation aircraft and sensors</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/11/ledd/1">Norwegian authorities may conduct an examination and inventory of the observation aircraft and sensors, as specified in the Treaty on Open Skies, at Oslo Airport, Gardermoen.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/11/ledd/2">Norwegian aviation authorities may demand access to any aircraft that is used for aviation activities in Norway and perform a ramp inspection, cf. Aviation Act 11 June 1993 No 101 <ref id="=lov-19930611-101-p4-8">section 4-8</ref>.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/12" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g12">
      <pverdi>Section 12</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Infringements</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/12/ledd/1">Observation flights that violates the regime established in the Treaty on Open Skies or applicable air traffic regulations must immediately be terminated. The air traffic control or chief flight monitor have the authority to terminate the flight.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/13" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g13">
      <pverdi>Section 13</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Amendment of other regulations</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/13/ledd/1">At the time of entry into force the following amendments are made to existing regulations:
<liste id="/artikkel/13/ledd/1/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/13/ledd/1/liste/a/avsnitt/1">Forskrift 11. januar 1995 nr. 42 om opprettelse av restriksjonsområde EN R402 punkt 1.1.4 skal lyde: Restriksjonene i denne forskrift gjelder ikke for ambulanseflyginger og flyginger etter Avtalen om det åpne luftrom.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/13/ledd/1/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/13/ledd/1/liste/b/avsnitt/1">Forskrift 11. desember 2006 nr. 1388 om opprettelse av restriksjonsområde EN R203 § 3 andre ledd skal lyde: Også ambulanse-, politi, søk- og redningsoppdrag og flyginger etter Avtalen om det åpne luftrom må innhente særskilt tillatelse fra Lufttrafikktjenesten på Flesland før flyging i området EN R203 kan gjennomføres.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/13/ledd/1/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/13/ledd/1/liste/c/avsnitt/1">Forskrift 16. oktober 2007 nr. 1152 om opprettelse av et permanent restriksjonsområde EN R102 over sentrum av Oslo § 3 andre ledd skal lyde: Forbudet gjelder ikke flyging i forbindelse med politi-, ambulanse-, forsvars-, søk- og redningsoppdrag og flyginger etter Avtalen om det åpne luftrom under forutsetning av at flygingen innrettes etter publiserte anbefalinger for VFR-trafikk i Oslo-området.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/artikkel/13/ledd/1/liste/d"><lverdi>d)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/artikkel/13/ledd/1/liste/d/avsnitt/1">Forskrift 22. januar 2016 nr. 49 om etablering av permanent restriksjonsområde EN R103 over området rundt Kongsvinger i forbindelse med det årlige World Rally Championship, Rally Sweden § 4 andre punktum skal lyde: Operasjoner i tilknytning til militær-, ambulanse-, politi-, søk- og redningsoppdrag og flyginger etter Avtalen om det åpne luftrom skal prioriteres foran annen trafikk i restriksjonsområdet.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/artikkel/14" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-12-20-2329/g14">
      <pverdi>Section 14</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Entry into force</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/artikkel/14/ledd/1">These regulations shall enter into force 1 January 2018.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
