<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2017-02-20-203" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2017-02-20-203</id>
    <dato>20.02.2017 nr. 203</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2017-02-20</dato>
    <ikraft>23.02.2017</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2017-02-23</ikraft>
    <departement>Helse- og omsorgsdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§23">L19.12.2003 nr. 124 § 23</ref>, <ref id="lov-2003-12-19-124-§16">§ 16</ref>, <ref id="for-2003-12-19-1790">F19.12.2003 nr. 1790</ref>, <ref id="for-2004-05-05">F05.05.2004</ref>nr. 884</hjemmel>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2016-02-12-149</endrer>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2017-0174</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Forskrift om kontroll av mikrobiologisk forurensning</korttittel>
    <tittel>Forskrift om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av visse næringsmidler fra tredjestater på grunn av mikrobiologisk forurensning</tittel>
    <redaksjonell_note><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Mattilsynet 20. februar 2017 med hjemmel i lov 19. desember 2003 nr. 124 om matproduksjon og mattrygghet mv. (matloven) § 23 tredje ledd, jf. § 16, jf. delegeringsvedtak 19. desember 2003 nr. 1790 og delegeringsvedtak 5. mai 2004 nr. 884.
<br/><b>EØS-henvisninger:</b> EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kap. I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2017/186).</redaksjonell_note>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/p1">
      <pverdi>§ 1.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Virkeområde</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/1/ledd/1">Forskriften gjelder utvidet kontroll ved import av sesamfrø og paanblader (Piper Betle) fra India til bruk som næringsmidler når Norge er innførselssted i EØS-området.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/1/ledd/2">Forskriften omfatter ikke personlige forsendelser beregnet på privat bruk.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/p2">
      <pverdi>§ 2.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Importbetingelser</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/2/ledd/1">EØS-avtalens vedlegg I kap. I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2017/186) om særlige importbetingelser for visse næringsmidler fra tredjestater på grunn av mikrobiologisk forurensning, og endrer forordning (EF) nr. 669/2009, gjelder som forskrift med de tilpasninger som følger av vedlegg I og II, protokoll 1 til avtalen og avtalen for øvrig.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/p3">
      <pverdi>§ 3.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Utpekte innførselssteder (DPE)</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/3/ledd/1">Mattilsynets grensekontrollstasjoner ved Oslo lufthavn Gardermoen, Oslo havn, Borg havn og Larvik havn utpekes som innførselssteder (DPE) i henhold til forordning (EU) 2017/186 artikkel 7.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/3/ledd/2">Driftsansvarlig for næringsmiddelforetaket eller dennes representant skal fremstille forsendelsen for kontroll ved ett av disse innførselsstedene.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/p4">
      <pverdi>§ 4.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Gebyr</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/4/ledd/1">Driftsansvarlig for næringsmiddelforetaket eller dennes representant skal betale gebyr for den offentlige kontrollen ved import av forsendelser av næringsmidler.</ledd>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2">For import av forsendelser av næringsmidler skal det betales:
<liste id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/a"><lverdi>a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/a/avsnitt/1">kr 1505,- per forsendelse for dokumentkontroll,</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/b"><lverdi>b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/b/avsnitt/1">kr 755,- per time eller kr 375,- per påbegynt halvtime når det gjennomføres identitetskontroll og fysisk kontroll av forsendelsen, og</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/c"><lverdi>c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/paragraf/4/ledd/2/liste/c/avsnitt/1">kostnadene for analyseprøvene for forsendelsen.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/5" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/p5">
      <pverdi>§ 5.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Tilsyn og vedtak</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/5/ledd/1">Mattilsynet fører tilsyn og kan fatte nødvendige enkeltvedtak, jf. matloven § 23, for å oppnå etterlevelse av bestemmelser gitt i eller i medhold av denne forskriften. Mattilsynet kan også fatte enkeltvedtak i henhold til matloven § 24 til § 26.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/6" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/p6">
      <pverdi>§ 6.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Straff</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/6/ledd/1">Overtredelse av bestemmelser gitt i denne forskriften eller enkeltvedtak gitt i medhold av forskriften, er straffbart i henhold til matloven § 28.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <paragraf id="/paragraf/7" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/p7">
      <pverdi>§ 7.</pverdi>
      <ptittel>Ikrafttredelse</ptittel>
      <ledd id="/paragraf/7/ledd/1">Denne forskriften trer i kraft 23. februar 2017. Samtidig oppheves forskrift 12. februar 2016 nr. 149 om særskilte beskyttelsestiltak ved import av paanblader fra India.</ledd>
    </paragraf>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/k1">
      <kverdi/>
      <ktittel> Forordninger</ktittel>
      <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/1/overskrift/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/k1/?2">
        <kverdi/>
        <ktittel> Forordning (EU) 2017/186 (engelsk)</ktittel>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/1/overskrift/2/ledd/1">Nedenfor gjengis til informasjon EØS-avtalen vedlegg I kapittel I del 7.1 nr. 13, kap. II nr. 41 og vedlegg II kap. XII nr. 54zzzc (forordning (EU) 2017/186) med de endringer og tillegg som følger av EØS-tilpasningen av rettsakten i samsvar med vedlegg I og II til EØS-avtalen.</ledd>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/1/overskrift/2/ledd/2">Sertifikatet nevnt i artikkel 5 finnes under vedlegg III i pdf-filen nedenfor.</ledd>
        <forordning>
          <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186">
            <kverdi/>
            <ktittel align="center"> COMMISSION IMPLEMENTING REGULATION (EU) 2017.186 <br/> of 2 February 2017 <br/>laying down specific conditions applicable to the introduction into the Union of consignments from certain third countries due to microbiological contamination and amending Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 <br/></ktittel>
            <marg niv="1" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/marg/1">(Text with EEA relevance)
<br/></marg>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/1">THE EUROPEAN COMMISSION,</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/2">Having regard to the Treaty on the Functioning of the European Union,</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/3">Having regard to Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 28 January 2002 laying down the general principles and requirements of food law, establishing the European Food Safety Authority and laying down procedures in matters of food safety,<fref id="/fotnote/1">1</fref> and in particular Article 53(1)(b)(ii) thereof,</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/4">Having regard to Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 29 April 2004 on official controls performed to ensure the verification of compliance with feed and food law, animal health and animal welfare rules,<fref id="2">2</fref> and in particular Article 15(5) thereof,</ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5">Whereas:
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/1"><lverdi>(1)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/1/avsnitt/1">Article 53 of Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 provides for the possibility to adopt appropriate Union emergency measures for food imported from a third country in order to protect human health, animal health and the environment, where it is evident that there is a serious risk that cannot be contained satisfactorily by means of measures taken by the Member States individually.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/2"><lverdi>(2)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/2/avsnitt/1">Article 11 of Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 requires that food imported into the Union for placing on the market within the Union is to comply with the relevant requirements of food law or conditions recognised by the Union to be at least equivalent thereto or, where a specific agreement exists between the Union and the exporting country, with requirements contained therein.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/3"><lverdi>(3)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/3/avsnitt/1">Regulation (EC) No 852/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council<fref id="3">3</fref> lays down general rules for food business operators on the hygiene of foodstuffs.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/4"><lverdi>(4)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/4/avsnitt/1">Article 11 of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 sets the requirements for sampling and analysis methods used in the context of official controls.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/5"><lverdi>(5)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/5/avsnitt/1">Article 14 of Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 provides that unsafe food products are not to be placed on the market. According to Regulation (EC) No 882/2004, the Competent Authorities are to verify the food business operators' compliance with Union legislation.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/6"><lverdi>(6)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/6/avsnitt/1">Commission Regulation (EC) No 669/2009<fref id="4">4</fref> lays down rules concerning the increased level of official controls on imports of certain feed and food of non-animal origin listed in Annex I to that Regulation.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/7"><lverdi>(7)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/7/avsnitt/1">For many years, there has been a high frequency of non-compliance with microbiological safety issues in sesame seeds ('Sesamum seeds') and betel leaves (<i>'Piper betle L.'</i>) from India. An increased frequency of official controls on import of those foods has therefore been established in 2014 with regard to the presence of <i>Salmonella spp</i>. Nonetheless these increased controls confirmed the high frequency of non-compliance of those foods with microbiological safety due to <i>Salmonella spp</i>. The import of those foods constitutes therefore a serious risk to public health within the Union and it is therefore necessary to adopt Union emergency measures.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/8"><lverdi>(8)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/8/avsnitt/1">Guarantees from the competent authorities of exporting countries that those foods have been produced in line with the hygiene provisions set up in Regulation (EC) No 852/2004 are necessary to protect human health in the Union. In order to ensure harmonised enforcement of import controls across the Union, all consignments of such foods should be accompanied by a health certificate signed by the competent authorities of exporting countries and by the results of analytical tests guaranteeing that they have been sampled and analysed with satisfactory results for the presence of microbiological pathogens.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/9"><lverdi>(9)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/9/avsnitt/1">Article 6 of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 requires the food business operators, responsible for consignments, to give prior notification of the arrival and nature of such consignments at the designated point of entry (DPE).</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/10"><lverdi>(10)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/10/avsnitt/1">Article 8 of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 requires, with regard to the increased level of official controls, those controls to cover documentary, identity and physical checks. Documentary checks are to be carried out without undue delay on all consignments within two working days from the time of arrival at the DPE and identity and physical checks, including laboratory analysis, at the frequencies set out in Annex I to that Regulation.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/11"><lverdi>(11)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/11/avsnitt/1">In order to ensure an efficient organisation and harmonised import controls at Union level with regard to the presence of microbiological pathogens in certain foods from certain third countries, specific import conditions for such foods should be laid down. For legal clarity, it is appropriate to gather all foods from third countries subject to specific conditions because of microbiological risks into one Regulation. Therefore the provisions regarding Betel leaves from India laid down in Commission Implementing Regulation (EU) 2016/166<fref id="5">5</fref> should be inserted into this Regulation and Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 should be amended accordingly.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/12"><lverdi>(12)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/12/avsnitt/1">Implementing Regulation (EU) 2016/166 should be repealed and replaced simultaneously by a more general Regulation laying down the provisions as regards import of certain foods from certain third countries due to microbiological contamination.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/13"><lverdi>(13)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/5/liste/13/avsnitt/1">The measures provided for in this Regulation are in accordance with the opinion of the Standing Committee on Plants, Animals, Food and Feed,
<fotnote id="/fotnote/1">1 OJ L 31, 1.2.2002, p. 1.</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/2">2 OJ L 165, 30.4.2004, p. 1.</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/3">3 Regulation (EC) No 852/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 29 April 2004 on the hygiene of foodstuffs (OJ L 139, 30.4.2004, p. 1).</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/4">4 Commission Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 of 24 July 2009 implementing Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 of the European Parliament and of the Council as regards the increased level of official controls on imports of certain feed and food of non-animal origin and amending Decision 2006/504/EC (OJ L 194, 25.7.2009, p. 11).</fotnote>
<fotnote id="/fotnote/5">5 Commission Implementing Regulation (EU) 2016/166 of 8 February 2016 laying down specific conditions applicable to the import of foodstuffs containing or consisting of betel leaves (ȘPiper betleș) from India and amending Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 (OJ L 32, 9.2.2016, p. 143).
<br/></fotnote></avsnitt></liste></ledd>
            <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/ledd/6">HAS ADOPTED THIS REGULATION:</ledd>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g1">
              <pverdi>Article 1</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Subject matter and scope</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/1/ledd/1">This Regulation shall apply to the introduction of the foods listed in Annex I.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g2">
              <pverdi>Article 2</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Definitions</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/2/ledd/1">For the purpose of this Regulation, the definitions laid down in Articles 2 and 3 of Regulation (EC) No 178/2002, in Article 2 of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004 and in Article 3 of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 shall apply.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g3">
              <pverdi>Article 3</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Introduction into the Union</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/3/ledd/1">The food business operator shall ensure that:
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/3/ledd/1/liste/1"><lverdi>1.</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/3/ledd/1/liste/1/avsnitt/1">Consignments of foods referred to in Annex I («food») shall only be introduced into the Union in accordance with the procedures laid down in this Regulation.</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/3/ledd/1/liste/2"><lverdi>2.</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/3/ledd/1/liste/2/avsnitt/1">Consignments of foods shall only be introduced into the Union through the designated point of entry («DPE»).</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g4">
              <pverdi>Article 4</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Results of sampling and analysis accompanying the consignment</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/4/ledd/1">1. Each consignment of foods shall be accompanied by the results of sampling and analysis performed by the competent authority of the third country of dispatch verifying the absence of the hazard specified in Annex I.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/4/ledd/2">2. The sampling and the analysis referred to in paragraph 1 shall be performed in accordance with Chapter III 'Sampling and analysis' in Title II of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004. In particular, the sampling shall be performed in accordance with the relevant standards of the ISO (International Organisation for Standardisation) and the guidelines of the Codex Alimentarius used as reference and the analysis for Salmonella shall be performed according to the reference method EN/ISO 6579 (the latest updated version of the detection method) or a method validated against it in accordance with the protocol set out in EN/ISO 16140 or other internationally accepted similar protocols.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/5" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g5">
              <pverdi>Article 5</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Health certificate</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/5/ledd/1">1. The consignments of foods listed in Annex I shall be accompanied by a health certificate in accordance with the model set out in Annex III.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/5/ledd/2">2. The health certificate shall be signed and stamped by an authorised representative of the competent authority of the third country of dispatch.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/5/ledd/3">3. The health certificate and its attachments shall be drawn up in the official language, or in one of the official languages, of the Member State where the DPE is located. However, the Member State of the DPE may consent to health certificates being drawn up in another official language of the Union.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/5/ledd/4">4. The health certificate shall be valid for a period of four months from the date of issue, but no longer than six months from the date of the last microbiological laboratory analysis.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/6" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g6">
              <pverdi>Article 6</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Identification</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/6/ledd/1">Each consignment of foods shall be identified with an identification code (consignment code) which corresponds to the identification code referred to on the results of the sampling and analysis referred to in Article 4 and the health certificate referred to in Article 5. Each individual bag, or other packaging form, of the consignment shall be identified with that identification code.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/7" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g7">
              <pverdi>Article 7</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Prior notification of consignments</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/7/ledd/1">1. Food business operators or their representatives shall give prior notification of the estimated date and time of physical arrival of consignments of food and of the nature of the consignment to the competent authority of the DPE.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/7/ledd/2">2. For the purpose of prior notification, food business operators or their representatives shall complete Part I of the common entry document («CED») and transmit that document to the competent authority of the DPE, at least one working day prior to the physical of arrival of the consignment.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/7/ledd/3">3. For the completion of the CED, food business operators or their representatives shall take into account the notes for guidance for the CED laid down in Annex II to Regulation (EC) No 669/2009.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/7/ledd/4">4. CEDs shall be drawn up in the official language, or in one of the official languages, of the Member State where the DPE is located. However, a Member State of the DPE may consent to CEDs being drawn up in another official language of the Union.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g8">
              <pverdi>Article 8</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Official controls</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/1">1. The competent authority at the DPE shall carry out documentary checks for each consignment of food to ascertain compliance with the requirements laid down in Articles 4 and 5.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/2">2. The identity checks and physical checks on food shall be carried out in accordance with Articles 8, 9 and 19 of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 at the frequency set out in Annex II to this Regulation.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/3">3. Where a consignment of food is not accompanied by the results of sampling and analysis referred to in Article 4 and the health certificate referred to in Article 5 or where those results or that health certificate do not comply with the requirements laid down in this Regulation, the consignment shall not be imported into the Union and shall be re-dispatched to the third country of origin or destroyed.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/4">4. After completion of the identity checks and physical checks, the competent authorities shall:
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/4/liste/a"><lverdi>(a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/4/liste/a/avsnitt/1">complete the relevant entries of Part II of the CED;</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/4/liste/b"><lverdi>(b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/4/liste/b/avsnitt/1">attach the results of sampling and analysis carried out, in accordance with paragraph 2 of this Article;</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/4/liste/c"><lverdi>(c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/4/liste/c/avsnitt/1">provide the CED with the CED reference number;</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/4/liste/d"><lverdi>(d)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/4/liste/d/avsnitt/1">stamp and sign the original of the CED;</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/4/liste/e"><lverdi>(e)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/4/liste/e/avsnitt/1">make and retain a copy of the signed and stamped CED.</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/8/ledd/5">5. The originals of the CED and the health certificate referred to in Article 5 with the accompanying results of sampling and analysis referred to in Article 4 shall accompany the consignment during transportation and until it is released for free circulation. In case of authorisation of onward transportation of the consignments pending the results of the physical checks, a certified copy of the original CED shall be issued. Where authorisation is given, the competent authority at the DPE shall notify the competent authority at the point of destination and appropriate arrangements shall be put in place to ensure that the consignment remains under the continuous control of the competent authorities and cannot be tampered with in any manner pending the results of the physical checks.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/9" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g9">
              <pverdi>Article 9</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Splitting of a consignment</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/9/ledd/1">1. Consignments shall not be split until all checks have been completed, and the CED has been fully filled in by the competent authorities of the DPE as provided for in Article 8.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/9/ledd/2">2. In the case of subsequent splitting of the consignment, an authenticated copy of the CED shall accompany each part of the consignment during its transport and until it is released for free circulation.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/10" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g10">
              <pverdi>Article 10</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Release for free circulation</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/10/ledd/1">The release for free circulation of consignments of food listed in Annex I shall be subject to the presentation (physically or electronically) by the food business operators or their representatives to the customs authorities of a CED duly filled in by the competent authority of the DPE once all official controls have been carried out and favourable results from physical checks, where such checks are required, are known. The customs authorities shall only release the consignment for free circulation if a favourable decision by the competent authority is indicated in box II.14 and signed in box II.21 of the CED.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/11" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g11">
              <pverdi>Article 11</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Non-compliance</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/11/ledd/1">If the official controls establish non-compliance with the relevant provisions of Regulation (EC) No 852/2004, the competent authority of the DPE shall complete Part III of the CED and shall take actions as laid down in provisions of Articles 19, 20 and 21 of Regulation (EC) No 882/2004.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/12" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g12">
              <pverdi>Article 12</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Reports</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/12/ledd/1">Member States shall submit to the Commission a report of all analytical results on consignments of foods pursuant to Article 8 of this Regulation.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/12/ledd/2">That report shall cover a period of six months and shall be submitted biannually by the end of the month following each semester.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/12/ledd/3">The report shall include the following information:
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/12/ledd/3/liste/a"><lverdi>(a)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/12/ledd/3/liste/a/avsnitt/1">number of consignments introduced, including size in terms of net weight and country of origin of each consignment;</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/12/ledd/3/liste/b"><lverdi>(b)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/12/ledd/3/liste/b/avsnitt/1">number of consignments subjected to sampling for analysis;</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/12/ledd/3/liste/c"><lverdi>(c)</lverdi><avsnitt id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/12/ledd/3/liste/c/avsnitt/1">results of the identity checks and physical checks referred to in Article 8(2).</avsnitt></liste></ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/13" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g13">
              <pverdi>Article 13</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Costs</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/13/ledd/1">All costs resulting from the official controls provided for in Article 8, including sampling, analysis, storage and any measures taken in case of non-compliance as referred to in Article 11, shall be borne by the food business operators.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/14" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g14">
              <pverdi>Article 14</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Transitional measures</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/14/ledd/1">Member States shall authorise introduction of consignments of food which left the third country of dispatch, prior to the date of entry into force of this Regulation without being accompanied by a health certificate as referred to in Article 5 and the results of sampling and analysis as referred to in Article 4.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/15" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g15">
              <pverdi>Article 15</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Repeal</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/15/ledd/1">Regulation (EC) 2016/166 is repealed.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/16" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g16">
              <pverdi>Article 16</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Amendment of Regulation (EC) No 669/2009</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/16/ledd/1">Regulation (EC) No 669/2009 is amended in accordance with Annex IV to this Regulation.</ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <artikkel type="forordning" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/17" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/g17">
              <pverdi>Article 17</pverdi>
              <ptittel>Entry into force</ptittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/17/ledd/1">This Regulation shall enter into force on the twentieth day following that of its publication in the <i>Official Journal of the European Union</i>.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/17/ledd/2">This Regulation shall be binding in its entirety and directly applicable in all Member States.</ledd>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/17/ledd/3">Done at Brussels,
<br/>
<marg niv="2" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/17/ledd/3/marg/1"><i>For the Commission</i></marg>
<marg niv="2" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/17/ledd/3/marg/2"><i>The President</i></marg>
<marg niv="2" id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/artikkel/17/ledd/3/marg/3">Jean Claude JUNCKER</marg></ledd>
            </artikkel>
            <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/vedlegg/i" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/vi">
              <kverdi/>
              <ktittel align="center"> Vedlegg I til forordning (EU) 2017/186</ktittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/vedlegg/i/ledd/1">
                <i>List of foods mentioned in Article 1</i>
              </ledd>
              <table niv="1" frame="1">
                <thgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
                  <colspec colname="1" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
                  <colspec colname="2" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
                  <colspec colname="3" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
                  <colspec colname="4" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
                  <colspec colname="5" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
                  <tbody>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">
                        <i>Næringsmidler (tiltenkt bruk)</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">
                        <i>KN-kode</i>
                        <fref id="1">1</fref>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">
                        <i>Norske varenummer</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="4">
                        <i>Opprinnelses-stat</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="5">
                        <i>Fare</i>
                      </entry>
                    </row>
                  </tbody>
                </thgroup>
                <tgroup cols="5" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
                  <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
                  <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
                  <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
                  <colspec colname="4" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
                  <colspec colname="5" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="15*"/>
                  <tbody>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Sesamfrø </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">1207 40 90 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">12.07.4090 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4">India </entry>
                      <entry colname="5">Salmonella </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">
                        <i>(Næringsmidler - friske eller kjølte)</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="2"/>
                      <entry colname="3"/>
                      <entry colname="4"/>
                      <entry colname="5"> </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Betelblader (paanblader) (<i>Piper betle L.</i>) </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">ex 1404 90 00 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">ex 14.04.9000 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4">India </entry>
                      <entry colname="5">Salmonella </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">
                        <i>(Næringsmidler)</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="2"/>
                      <entry colname="3"/>
                      <entry colname="4"/>
                      <entry colname="5"> </entry>
                    </row>
                  </tbody>
                </tgroup>
              </table>
              <fotnote id="/fotnote/1+">1 Når bare visse produkter i en underposisjon skal undersøkes, og det ikke finnes noen særskilt varenummer i tolltariffen, står det «ex» foran underposisjonen.</fotnote>
            </kapittel>
            <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/vedlegg/ii" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/vii">
              <kverdi/>
              <ktittel align="center"> Vedlegg II til forordning (EU) 2017/186</ktittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/vedlegg/ii/ledd/1">
                <i>Frequency of identity and physical checks for the foods mentioned in Article 1 at the designated point of entry (DPE) according to Article 8(2)</i>
              </ledd>
              <table niv="1" frame="1">
                <thgroup cols="6" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
                  <colspec colname="1" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="2" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="3" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="4" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="5" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="6" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <tbody>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">
                        <i>Næringsmidler (tiltenkt bruk)</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">
                        <i>KN-kode</i>
                        <fref id="1">1</fref>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">
                        <i>Norske varenummer</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="4">
                        <i>Opprinnelsesstat</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="5">
                        <i>Fare</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="6">
                        <i>Hyppighet av fysiske kontroller og identitetskontroller (%)</i>
                      </entry>
                    </row>
                  </tbody>
                </thgroup>
                <tgroup cols="6" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
                  <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="2" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="3" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="4" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="5" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="6" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <tbody>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Sesamfrø </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">1207 40 90 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">12.07.4090 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4">India </entry>
                      <entry colname="5">Salmonella<fref id="2">2</fref> </entry>
                      <entry colname="6">20 </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">
                        <i>(Næringsmidler - friske eller kjølte)</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="2"/>
                      <entry colname="3"/>
                      <entry colname="4"/>
                      <entry colname="5"/>
                      <entry colname="6"> </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Betelblader (paanblader) (<i>Piper betle L</i>.) </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">ex 1404 90 00 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">ex 14.04.9000 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4">India </entry>
                      <entry colname="5">Salmonella<fref id="2">2</fref> </entry>
                      <entry colname="6">10 </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">
                        <i>(Næringsmidler)</i>
                      </entry>
                      <entry colname="2"/>
                      <entry colname="3"/>
                      <entry colname="4"/>
                      <entry colname="5"/>
                      <entry colname="6"> </entry>
                    </row>
                  </tbody>
                </tgroup>
              </table>
              <fotnote id="/fotnote/1++">1 Når bare visse produkter i en underposisjon skal undersøkes, og det ikke finnes noen særskilt varenummer i tolltariffen, står det «ex» foran underposisjonen.</fotnote>
              <fotnote id="/fotnote/2+">2 Referansemetode EN/ISO 6579 (den siste oppdaterte utgave av påvisingsmetoden) eller en metode som er i overensstemmelse med protokollen i EN/ISO 16140 eller andre liknende internasjonalt anerkjente protokoller.</fotnote>
            </kapittel>
            <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/vedlegg/iii" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/viii">
              <kverdi/>
              <ktittel align="center"> Vedlegg III til forordning (EU) 2017/186</ktittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/vedlegg/iii/ledd/1">For helsesertifikatet for forordning (EU) 2017/186 se pdf-filen nedenfor under avsnittet Forordninger i PDF.</ledd>
            </kapittel>
            <kapittel id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/vedlegg/iv" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/?1/?2/y2017.186/viv">
              <kverdi/>
              <ktittel align="center"> Vedlegg IV til forordning (EU) 2017/186</ktittel>
              <ledd id="/overskrift/1/overskrift/2/tittel/2017.186/vedlegg/iv/ledd/1">In Annex I to Regulation (EC) No 669/2009, the following entry is deleted:</ledd>
              <table niv="1" frame="1">
                <tgroup cols="6" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
                  <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="2" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="3" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="4" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="5" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <colspec colname="6" align="center" valign="top" colwidth="12*"/>
                  <tbody>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">Sesamfrø </entry>
                      <entry colname="2">1207 40 90 </entry>
                      <entry colname="3">12.07.4090 </entry>
                      <entry colname="4">India </entry>
                      <entry colname="5">Salmonella<sup>12</sup> </entry>
                      <entry colname="6">20 </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                      <entry colname="1">(<i>Næringsmidler - friske eller kjølte</i>) </entry>
                      <entry colname="2"/>
                      <entry colname="3"/>
                      <entry colname="4"/>
                      <entry colname="5"/>
                      <entry colname="6"> </entry>
                    </row>
                  </tbody>
                </tgroup>
              </table>
            </kapittel>
          </kapittel>
        </forordning>
      </kapittel>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/3" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/k3">
      <kverdi/>
      <ktittel> Forordninger i pdf</ktittel>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/3/ledd/1">Nedenfor gjengis forordning (EU) 2017/186.</ledd>
      <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/3/overskrift/4" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2017-02-20-203/k3/?4">
        <kverdi/>
        <ktittel> Forordning (EU) 2017/186</ktittel>
        <ledd id="/kapittel/3/overskrift/4/ledd/1">For å lese forordning (EU) 2017/186, med helsesertifikatet i vedlegg III, se her: <lenke url="https://lovdata.no/static/32017r0186e-01.pdf"><img src="pdf.gif" alt="ikon"/></lenke></ledd>
      </kapittel>
    </kapittel>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
