<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2014-07-25-1016" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-07-25-1016">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2014-07-25-1016</id>
    <dato>25.07.2014 nr. 1016</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2014-07-25</dato>
    <publisert>I 2014 hefte 10 s 1588</publisert>
    <ikraft>25.07.2014</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2014-07-25</ikraft>
    <departement>Utenriksdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="for-2014-03-21-301-§5">F21.03.2014 nr. 301 § 5</ref>, <ref id="lov-2001-04-27-14">L27.04.2001 nr. 14</ref></hjemmel>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2014-03-21-301</endrer>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2014-0733</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Endr. i forskrift om restriktive tiltak vedrørende Ukraina</korttittel>
    <korttittel>4 Endr. i forskrift om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet og uavhengighet (Nr. 1016)</korttittel>
    <tittel>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet og uavhengighet</tittel>
    <marg niv="1" id="/marg/1"><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Utenriksdepartementet 25. juli 2014 med hjemmel i forskrift 21. mars 2014 nr. 301 om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet og uavhengighet § 5.</marg>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/i" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-07-25-1016/ki">
      <kverdi>I</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/1">I forskrift 21. mars 2014 nr. 301 om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet og uavhengighet gjøres følgende endringer:
<br/></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2">§ 2 (1) oppheves.
<br/></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3">Ny § 2 (1) skal lyde:</ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/4">(1) EUs vedlagte forordning (EU) nr. 269/2014 om restriktive tiltak mot handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet og uavhengighet (som endret av forordning (EU) nr. 284/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 433/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 476/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 477/2014, forordning (EU) nr. 577/2014 og forordning (EU) nr. 753/2014) gjelder som forskrift med de tilpasninger som følger av denne bestemmelsen.
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/4/marg/1">Gjeldende vedlegg I erstattes av vedlagte vedlegg I.
<br/></marg></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5">Vedlegg I skal lyde:</ledd>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="vedlegg" id="/vedlegg/i" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-07-25-1016/vi">
      <kverdi>Vedlegg I</kverdi>
      <ktittel>Liste over personer og enheter</ktittel>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/1">Informasjon vedrørende samtlige listeførte personer er rubrisert slik:
<liste id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/1/liste/1"><lverdi>-</lverdi><avsnitt id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/1/liste/1/avsnitt/1">Navn</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/1/liste/2"><lverdi>-</lverdi><avsnitt id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/1/liste/2/avsnitt/1">Identifiserende informasjon og fødselsdato der tilgjengelig</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/1/liste/3"><lverdi>-</lverdi><avsnitt id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/1/liste/3/avsnitt/1">Grunnlag</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/1/liste/4"><lverdi>-</lverdi><avsnitt id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/1/liste/4/avsnitt/1">Dato for EUs listeføring
<br/></avsnitt></liste></ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/2">
        <i>1. Sergey Valeryevich Aksyonov</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/2/marg/1">d.o.b. 26.11.1972
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/2/marg/2">Aksyonov was elected «Prime Minister of Crimea» in the Crimean Verkhovna Rada on 27 February 2014 in the presence of pro-Russian gunmen. His «election» was decreed unconstitutional by Oleksandr Turchynov on 1 March. He actively lobbied for the «referendum» of 16 March 2014.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/2/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/3">
        <i>2. Vladimir Andreevich Konstantinov (Bладимир Aндрeeвич Кoнcтантинoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/3/marg/1">d.o.b. 19.11.1956</marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/3/marg/2">Vladimirovca, Slobozia District, Republic of Moldova
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/3/marg/3">As speaker of the Verkhovna Rada of Crimea, Konstantinov played a relevant role in the decisions taken by the Verkhovna Rada of Crimea concerning the 'referendum' against the territorial integrity of Ukraine and called on voters to cast votes in favour of Crimean Independence.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/3/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/4">
        <i>3. Rustam Ilmirovich Temirgaliev</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/4/marg/1">d.o.b. 15.08.1976
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/4/marg/2">As Deputy Chairman of the Council of Ministers of Crimea, Temirgaliev played a relevant role in the decisions taken by the Verkhovna Rada concerning the «referendum» against territorial integrity of Ukraine. He lobbied actively for integration of Crimea into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/4/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/5">
        <i>4. Deniz Valentinovich Berezovskiy</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/5/marg/1">d.o.b. 15.07.1974
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/5/marg/2">Berezovskiy was appointed commander of the Ukrainian Navy on 1 March 2014 and swore an oath to the Crimean armed force, thereby breaking his oath. The Prosecutor-General's Office of Ukraine launched an investigation against him for high treason.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/5/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/6">
        <i>5. Aleksei Mikhailovich Chaliy</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/6/marg/1">d.o.b. 13.06.1961
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/6/marg/2">Chaliy became «Mayor of Sevastopol» by popular acclamation on 23 February 2014 and accepted this «vote». He actively campaigned for Sevastopol to become a separate entity of the Russian Federation following a referendum on 16 March 2014.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/6/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/7">
        <i>6. Pyotr Anatolyevich Zima (Пëтр Aнатoльeвич Зима)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/7/marg/1">d.o.b. 29.3.1965
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/7/marg/2">Zima was appointed as the new head of the Crimean Security Service (SBU) on 3 March 2014 by «Prime Minister» Aksyonov and accepted this appointment. He has given relevant information including a database to the Russian Intelligence Service (SBU). This included information on Euro-Maidan activists and human rights defenders of Crimea. He played a relevant role in preventing Ukraine's authorities from controlling the territory of Crimea. On 11 March 2014 the formation of an independent Security Service of Crimea was proclaimed by former SBU officers of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/7/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/8">
        <i>7. Yuriy Gennadyevich Zherebtsov (Юрий Гeннадьeвич Жeрeбцoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/8/marg/1">d.o.b. 19.11.1965
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/8/marg/2">Counsellor of the Speaker of the Verkhovna Rada of Crimea, one of the leading organizers of the 16 March 2014 «referendum» against Ukraine's territorial integrity.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/8/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/9">
        <i>8. Sergey Pavlovych Tsekov</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/9/marg/1">d.o.b. 28.03.1953
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/9/marg/2">Vice Speaker of the Verkhovna Rada; Tsekov initiated together with Sergey Aksyonov the unlawful dismissal of the government of the Autonomous Republic of Crimea (ARC). He drew into this endeavour Vladimir Konstantinov, threatening him with his dismissal. He publicly recognized that the MPs from Crimea were the initiators of inviting Russian soldiers to take over Verkhovna Rada of Crimea. He was one of the first Crimean Leaders to ask in public for annexation of Crimea to Russia.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/9/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/10">
        <i>9. Ozerov, Viktor Alekseevich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/10/marg/1">d.o.b. 5.1.1958 in Abakan, Khakassia
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/10/marg/2">Chairman of the Security and Defense Committee of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Ozerov, on behalf of the Security and Defense Committee of the Federation Council, publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/10/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/11">
        <i>10. Dzhabarov, Vladimir Michailovich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/11/marg/1">d.o.b. 29.9.1952
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/11/marg/2">First Deputy-Chairman of the International Affairs Committee of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Dzhabarov, on behalf of the International Affairs Committee of the Federation Council, publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/11/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/12">
        <i>11. Klishas, Andrei Aleksandrovich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/12/marg/1">d.o.b. 9.11.1972 in Sverdlovsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/12/marg/2">Chairman of the Committee on Constitutional Law of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Klishas publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine. In public statements Klishas sought to justify a Russian military intervention in Ukraine by claiming that «the Ukrainian President supports the appeal of the Crimean authorities to the President of the Russian Federation on landing an all-encompassing assistance in defense of the citizens of Crimea».
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/12/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/13">
        <i>12. Ryzhkov, Nikolai Ivanovich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/13/marg/1">d.o.b. 28.9.1929 in Duleevka, Donetsk region, Ukrainian SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/13/marg/2">Member of the Committee for federal issues, regional politics and the North of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Ryzhkov publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/13/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/14">
        <i>13. Bushmin, Evgeni Viktorovich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/14/marg/1">d.o.b. 4.10.1958 in Lopatino, Sergachiisky region, RSFSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/14/marg/2">Deputy Speaker of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Bushmin publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/14/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/15">
        <i>14. Totoonov, Aleksandr Borisovich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/15/marg/1">d.o.b. 3.3.1957 in Ordzhonikidze, North Ossetia
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/15/marg/2">Member of the Committee on culture, science, and information of the Federation Council of the Russian Federation. On 1 March 2014 Totoonov publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/15/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/16">
        <i>15. Panteleev, Oleg Evgenevich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/16/marg/1">d.o.b. 21.7.1952 in Zhitnikovskoe, Kurgan region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/16/marg/2">First Deputy Chairman of the Committee on Parliamentary Issues. On 1 March 2014 Panteleev publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/16/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/17">
        <i>16. Mironov, Sergei Mikhailovich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/17/marg/1">d.o.b. 14.2.1953 in Pushkin, Leningrad region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/17/marg/2">Member of the Council of the State Duma; Leader of Fair Russia faction in the Duma of the Russian Federation. Initiator of the bill allowing Russian Federation to admit in its composition, under the pretext of protection of Russian citizens, territories of a foreign country without a consent of that country or of an international treaty.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/17/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/18">
        <i>17. Zheleznyak, Sergei Vladimirovich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/18/marg/1">d.o.b. 30.7.1970 in St Petersburg (former Leningrad)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/18/marg/2">Deputy Speaker of the State Duma of the Russian Federation. Actively supporting use of Russian Armed Forces in Ukraine and annexation of Crimea. He led personally the demonstration in support of the use of Russian Armed Forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/18/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/19">
        <i>18. Slutski, Leonid Eduardovich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/19/marg/1">d.o.b. 4.01.1968 in Moscow
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/19/marg/2">Chairman of the Commonwealth of Independent States (CIS) Committee of the State Duma of the Russian Federation (member of the LDPR). Actively supporting use of Russian Armed Forces in Ukraine and annexation of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/19/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/20">
        <i>19. Vitko, Aleksandr Viktorovich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/20/marg/1">d.o.b. 13.9.1961 in Vitebsk (Belarusian SSR)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/20/marg/2">Commander of the Black Sea Fleet, Vice-Admiral. Responsible for commanding Russian forces that have occupied Ukrainian sovereign territory.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/20/marg/3">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/21">
        <i>20. Anatoliy Alekseevich Sidorov (Aнатoлий Aлeкceeвич Cидoрoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/21/marg/1">d.o.b. 2.7.1958
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/21/marg/2">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/21/marg/3">Commander of Russia's Western Military District, units of which are deployed in Crimea. He is responsible for part of the Russian military presence in Crimea which is undermining the sovereignty of Ukraine and assisted the Crimean authorities in preventing public demonstrations against moves towards a 'referendum' and incorporation into Russia.
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/22">
        <i>21. Aleksandr Viktorovich Galkin (Aлeкcандр Bиктoрoвич &gt;Галкин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/22/marg/1">d.o.b. 22.3.1958
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/22/marg/2">Commander of Russia's Southern Military District 'SMD'. SMD forces are deployed in Crimea. He is responsible for part of the Russian military presence in Crimea which is undermining the sovereignty of Ukraine and assisted the Crimean authorities in preventing public demonstrations against moves towards a 'referendum' and incorporation into Russia.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/22/marg/3">The Black Sea Fleet comes under Galkin's command; much of the force movement into Crimea has come through the Southern Military District.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/22/marg/4">17.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/23">
        <i>22. Rogozin, Dmitry Olegovich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/23/marg/1">d.o.b. 21.12.1963; in Moscow
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/23/marg/2">Deputy Prime Minister of the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/23/marg/3">Publicly called for the annexation of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/23/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/24">
        <i>23. Glazyev, Sergey</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/24/marg/1">d.o.b. 1.1.1961, Zaporozhye, (Ukrainian SSR)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/24/marg/2">Adviser to the President of the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/24/marg/3">Publicly called for the annexation of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/24/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/25">
        <i>24. Matviyenko, Valentina Ivanova</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/25/marg/1">d.o.b. 7.4.1949, Shepetovka, Khmelnitskyi oblast (Ukrainian SSR)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/25/marg/2">Speaker of the Federation Council. On 1 March 2014, publicly supported in the Federation Council the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/25/marg/3">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/26">
        <i>25. Naryshkin, Sergei Evgenevich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/26/marg/1">d.o.b. 27.10.1954, St Petersburg (former Leningrad)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/26/marg/2">Speaker of the State Duma. Publicly supported the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine. Publicly supported the Russia-Crimea reunification treaty and the related federal constitutional law.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/26/marg/3">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/27">
        <i>26. Kiselyov, Dmitry Konstantinovich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/27/marg/1">d.o.b. 26.4.1954
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/27/marg/2">Appointed by Presidential Decree on 9 December 2013 Head of the Russian Federal State news agency «Rossiya Segodnya». Central figure of the government propaganda supporting the deployment of Russian forces in Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/27/marg/3">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/28">
        <i>27. Nosatov, Alexander Mihailovich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/28/marg/1">d.o.b. 27.3.1963 Sevastopol, (Ukrainian SSR)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/28/marg/2">Deputy-Commander of the Black Sea Fleet, Rear-Admiral. Responsible for commanding Russian forces that have occupied Ukrainian sovereign territory.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/28/marg/3">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/29">
        <i>28. Kulikov, Valery Vladimirovich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/29/marg/1">d.o.b. 1.9.1956, Zaporozhye, (Ukrainian SSR)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/29/marg/2">Deputy-Commander of the Black Sea Fleet, Rear Admiral. Responsible for commanding Russian forces that have occupied Ukrainian sovereign territory.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/29/marg/3">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/30">
        <i>29. Surkov, Vladislav Yurievich</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/30/marg/1">d.o.b. 21.9.1964, Solntsevo, Lipetsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/30/marg/2">Aide to the President of the Russian Federation. He was an organiser of the process in Crimea by which local Crimean communities were mobilised to stage actions undermining the Ukrainian authorities in Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/30/marg/3">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/31">
        <i>30. Mikhail Grigoryevich Malyshev (Mиxаил Григoрьeвич Mалышeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/31/marg/1">d.o.b. 10.10.1955
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/31/marg/2">Chair of the Crimea Electoral Commission.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/31/marg/3">Chair of the Crimean Electoral Commission. Responsible for administering the Crimean 'referendum'. Responsible under the Russian system for signing 'referendum' results.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/31/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/32">
        <i>31. Valery Kirillovich Medvedev (Bалeрий Кириллoвич Meдвeдeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/32/marg/1">d.o.b. 21.8.1946</marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/32/marg/2">Russia
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/32/marg/3">Responsible for administering the Crimean 'referendum'. Responsible under the Russian system for signing 'referendum' results.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/32/marg/4">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/33">
        <i>32. Lt. Gen. Igor Nikolaevich Turchenyuk (Игoрь Hикoлаeвич Tyрчeнюк)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/33/marg/1">d.o.b. 5.12.1959</marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/33/marg/2">Kirghizia/Osh
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/33/marg/3">Commander of the Russian forces in Crimea
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/33/marg/4">The de-facto Commander of Russian troops deployed on the ground in Crimea (whom Russia continues to refer to officially as 'local self-defence militias').
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/33/marg/5">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/34">
        <i>33. Elena Borisovna Mizulina (Eлeна Бoриcoвна Mизyлина)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/34/marg/1">d.o.b. 9.12.1954</marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/34/marg/2">Buly, Kostroma Oblast
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/34/marg/3">Deputy in the State Duma
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/34/marg/4">Originator and co-sponsor of recent legislative proposals in Russia that would have allowed regions of other countries to join Russia without their central authorities prior agreement.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/34/marg/5">21.3.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/35">
        <i>34. Dmitry Nikolayevich Kozak</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/35/marg/1">Born 7.11.1958 in Kirovohrad, Ukrainian SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/35/marg/2">Deputy Prime Minister. Responsible for overseeing the integration of the annexed Autonomous Republic of Crimea into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/35/marg/3">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/36">
        <i>35. Oleg Yevgenyvich Belaventsev</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/36/marg/1">Born 15.9.1949 in Moscow
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/36/marg/2">Plenipotentiary Representative of the President of the Russian Federation into the so called 'Crimean Federal District', Non-permanent member of the Russian Security Council. Responsible for the implementation of the constitutional prerogatives of the Russian Head of State on the territory of the annexed Autonomous Republic of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/36/marg/3">29.4.2014 3.
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/37">
        <i>36. Oleg Genrikhovich Savelyev</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/37/marg/1">Born 27.10.1965 in Leningrad
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/37/marg/2">Minister for Crimean Affairs. Responsible for the integration of the annexed Autonomous Republic of Crimea into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/37/marg/3">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/38">
        <i>37. Sergei Ivanovich Menyailo</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/38/marg/1">Born 22.8.1960 in Alagir, North-Ossetian Autonomous SSR, RSFSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/38/marg/2">Acting governor of the Ukrainian annexed city of Sevastopol.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/38/marg/3">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/39">
        <i>38. Olga Fedorovna Kovatidi</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/39/marg/1">Born 7.5.1962 in Simferopol, Ukrainian SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/39/marg/2">Member of the Russian Federation Council from the annexed Autonomous Republic of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/39/marg/3">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/40">
        <i>39. Ludmila Ivanovna Shvetsova</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/40/marg/1">Born 24.9.1949 in Alma-Ata, USSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/40/marg/2">Deputy Chairman of State Duma, United Russia - Responsible for initiating legislation to integrate the annexed Autonomous Republic of Crimea into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/40/marg/3">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/41">
        <i>40. Sergei Ivanovich Neverov</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/41/marg/1">Born 21.12.1961 in Tashtagol, USSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/41/marg/2">Deputy Chairman of State Duma, United Russia. Responsible for initiating legislation to integrate the annexed Autonomous Republic of Crimea into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/41/marg/3">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/42">
        <i>41. Igor Dmitrievich Sergun</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/42/marg/1">Born 28.3.1957
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/42/marg/2">Director of GRU (Main Intelligence Directorate), Deputy Chief of the General Staff of the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation, Lieutenant-General. Responsible for the activity of GRU officers in Eastern Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/42/marg/3">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/43">
        <i>42. Valery Vasilevich Gerasimov</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/43/marg/1">Born 8.9.1955 in Kazan
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/43/marg/2">Chief of the General Staff of the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation, First Deputy Minister of Defence of the Russian Federation, General of the Army. Responsible for the massive deployment of Russian troops along the border with Ukraine and lack of de-escalation of the situation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/43/marg/3">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/44">
        <i>43. German Prokopiv</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/44/marg/1">Active leader of the 'Lugansk Guard'. Took part in the seizure of the building of the Lugansk regional office of the Security Service, recorded a video address to President Putin and Russia from the occupied building. Close links with the 'Army of the South-East'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/44/marg/2">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/45">
        <i>44. Valeriy Dmitrievich Bolotov (Bалeрий Дмитриeвич Бoлoтoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/45/marg/1">d.o.b. 13.2.1970</marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/45/marg/2">Stachanov, Lugansk Oblast, Ukrainian SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/45/marg/3">One of the leaders of the separatist group 'Army of the South-East' which occupied the building of the Security Service in the Lugansk region. Before seizing the building he and other accomplices possessed arms apparently supplied illegally from Russia and from local criminal groups.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/45/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/46">
        <i>45. Andriy Yevgenevich Purgin (Aндрeй &gt;Eвгeньeвич Пyргин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/46/marg/1">d.o.b. 26.1.1972
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/46/marg/2">Head of the 'Donetsk Republic', active participant and organiser of separatist actions, co-ordinator of actions of the 'Russian tourists' in Donetsk. Co-founder of a 'Civic Initiative of Donbasfor the Eurasian Union'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/46/marg/3">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/47">
        <i>46. Denys Pushylin</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/47/marg/1">Born in Makiivka
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/47/marg/2">One of the leaders of the Donetsk People's Republic. Participated in the seizure and occupation of the regional administration. Active spokesperson for the separatists.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/47/marg/3">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/48">
        <i>47. Sergey Gennadevich Tsyplakov (Ceргeй Гeннадьeвич Цыплакoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/48/marg/1">d.o.b. 1.5.1983</marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/48/marg/2">Donetsk, Ukrainian SSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/48/marg/3">One of the leaders of ideologically radical organization People's Militia of Donbas. He took active part in the seizure of a number of state buildings in Donetsk region.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/48/marg/4">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/49">
        <i>48. Igor Vsevolodovich Girkin a.k.a. Igor Strelkov (Игoрь Bceвoлoдoвич Гиркин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/49/marg/1">d.o.b. 17.12.1970 passport no. 4506460961
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/49/marg/2">Identified as staff of Main Intelligence Directorate of the General Staff of the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation (GRU). He was involved in incidents in Sloviansk. He is the assistant on security issues to Sergey Aksionov, self-proclaimed prime-minister of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/49/marg/3">29.4.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/50">
        <i>49. Vyacheslav Viktorovich Volodin</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/50/marg/1">Born 4 February 1964 in Alekseevka, Saratov region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/50/marg/2">First Deputy Chief of Staff of the Presidential Administration of Russia. Responsible for overseeing the political integration of the annexed Ukrainian region of Crimea into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/50/marg/3">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/51">
        <i>50. Vladimir Shamanov</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/51/marg/1">Born 15.02.1954 in Barnaul
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/51/marg/2">Commander of the Russian Airborne Troops, Colonel-General. In his senior position holds responsibility for the deployment of Russian airborne forces in Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/51/marg/3">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/52">
        <i>51. Vladimir Nikolaevich Pligin</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/52/marg/1">Born 19.05.1960 in Ignatovo, Vologodsk Oblast, USSR
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/52/marg/2">Chair of the Duma Constitutional Law Committee. Responsible for facilitating the adoption of legislation on the annexation of Crimea and Sevastopol into the Russian Federation.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/52/marg/3">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/53">
        <i>52. Petr Grigorievich Jarosh</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/53/marg/1">Acting Head of the Federal Migration Service office for Crimea. Responsible for the systematic and expedited issuance of Russian passports for the residents of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/53/marg/2">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/54">
        <i>53. Oleg Grigorievich Kozyura</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/54/marg/1">Born 19.12.1962 in Zaporozhye
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/54/marg/2">Acting Head of the Federal Migration Service office for Sevastopol. Responsible for the systematic and expedited issuance of Russian passports for the residents of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/54/marg/3">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/55">
        <i>54. Viacheslav Ponomariov Vyacheslav Vladimirovich Ponomariov (Bячecлав Bладимирoвич Пoнoмарëв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/55/marg/1">d.o.b. 2.5.1965</marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/55/marg/2">Slovinsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/55/marg/3">Self-declared mayor of Slaviansk. Ponomarev called on Vladimir Putin to send in Russian troops to protect the city and later asked him to supply weapons. Ponomarev's men are involved in kidnappings (they captured Ukrainian reporter Irma Krat and Simon Ostrovsky, a reporter for Vice News, both were later released. They detained military observers under OSCE Vienna Document).
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/55/marg/4">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/56">
        <i>55. Igor Mykolaiovych Bezler Igor Nikolaevich Bezler, (Игoрь Hикoлаeвич Бeзлeр)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/56/marg/1">d.o.b. 30.12.1965 Simferopol
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/56/marg/2">One of the leaders of self-proclaimed militia of Horlivka. He took control of the Security Service of Ukraine's Office in Donetsk region building and afterwards seized the Ministry of Internal Affairs' district station in the town of Horlivka. He has links to Ihor Strielkov under which command he was involved in the murder of Peoples' Deputy of the Horlivka's Municipal Council Volodymyr Rybak according to the SBU.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/56/marg/3">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/57">
        <i>56. Igor Kakidzyanov</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/57/marg/1">One of the leaders of armed forces of the self-proclaimed 'Donetsk People's Republic'. The aim of the forces is to 'protect the people of Donetsk People's Republic and territorial integrity of the republic' according to Pushylin, one of the leaders of the 'Donetsk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/57/marg/2">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/58">
        <i>57. Oleg Tsariov Oleg Anatolevich Tsariov (Oлeг Aнатoлiйoвич Царьoв) (Oлeг Aнатoльeвич Царëв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/58/marg/1">d.o.b. 2.6.1970</marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/58/marg/2">Dnipropetrovsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/58/marg/3">Member of the Rada. Publicly called for the creation of the Federal Republic of Novorossia, composed of South Eastern Ukrainian regions.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/58/marg/4">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/59">
        <i>58. Roman Lyagin (Poман Лягин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/59/marg/1">d.o.b. 30.5.1980</marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/59/marg/2">Donetsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/59/marg/3">Head of the 'Donetsk People's Republic' Central Electoral Commission. Actively organised the referendum on 11 May on the self-determination of the 'Donetsk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/59/marg/4">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/60">
        <i>59. Aleksandr Malykhin</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/60/marg/1">Head of the 'Lugansk People's Republic' Central Electoral Commission. Actively organised the referendum on 11 May on the self-determination of the 'Lugansk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/60/marg/2">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/61">
        <i>60. Natalia Vladimirovna Poklonskaya</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/61/marg/1">Born 18.03.1980 in Eupatoria
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/61/marg/2">Prosecutor of Crimea. Actively implementing Russia's annexation of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/61/marg/3">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/62">
        <i>61. Igor Sergeievich Shevchenko</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/62/marg/1">Acting Prosecutor of Sevastopol. Actively implementing Russia's annexation of Sevastopol.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/62/marg/2">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/63">
        <i>62. Aleksandr Yurevich Borodai (Aлeкcандр Юрьeвич Бoрoдай)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/63/marg/1">d.o.b: 25.7.1972 in Moscow
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/63/marg/2">So called 'Prime Minister of People's Republic of Donetsk'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/63/marg/3">Responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so called 'government of the Donetsk People' s Republic' (e.g. on 8 July stated 'our military is conducting a special operation against the Ukrainian «fascists»'), Signatory of the Memorandum of Understanding on 'Novorossiya union'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/63/marg/4">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/64">
        <i>63. Alexander Khodakovsky (Aлeкcандр Ceргeeвич Xoдакoвcкий)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/64/marg/1">So called 'Minister of Security of People's Republic of Donetsk'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/64/marg/2">Responsible for the separatist security activities of the so called 'government of the Donetsk People' s Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/64/marg/3">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/65">
        <i>64. Alexandr Aleksandrovich Kalyussky (Aлeкcандр Aлeкcандрoвич Калюccкий)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/65/marg/1">So called 'de facto Deputy Prime Minister for Social Affairs of DPR'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/65/marg/2">Responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so called 'government of the Donetsk People' s Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/65/marg/3">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/66">
        <i>65. Alexander Khryakov</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/66/marg/1">So called 'Information and Mass Communications Minister of DPR'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/66/marg/2">Responsible for the pro-separatist propaganda activities of the so called 'government of the Donetsk People' s Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/66/marg/3">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/67">
        <i>66. Marat Bashirov</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/67/marg/1">So called 'Prime Minister of the Council of Ministers of the People' s Republic of Luhansk, confirmed on 8 Jul'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/67/marg/2">Responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so called 'government of the People' s Republic of Luhansk'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/67/marg/3">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/68">
        <i>67. Vasyl Nikitin</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/68/marg/1">So called 'Vice Prime Minister of the Council of Ministers of the People' s Republic of Luhansk', (used to be the so called 'Prime Minister of the People' s Republic of Luhansk', and former spokesman of the 'Army of the Southeast').
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/68/marg/2">Responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so called 'government of the People' s Republic of Luhansk'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/68/marg/3">Responsible for the statement of the Army of the Southeast that the Ukrainian presidential elections in the 'People's Republic of Luhansk' cannot take place due to the 'new' status of the region.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/68/marg/4">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/69">
        <i>68. Aleksey Karyakin (Aлeкceй &gt;Карякин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/69/marg/1">1979
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/69/marg/2">So called 'Supreme Council Chair of the People' s Republic of Luhansk'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/69/marg/3">Responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the 'Supreme Council', responsible for asking the Russian Federation to recognize the independence of 'People' s Republic of Luhansk'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/69/marg/4">Signatory of the Memorandum of Understanding on the 'Novorossiya union'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/69/marg/5">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/70">
        <i>69. Yurij Ivakin (Юрий Ивакин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/70/marg/1">So called 'Minister of Internal Affairs of the People' s Republic of Luhansk'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/70/marg/2">Responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so called 'government of the People' s Republic of Luhansk'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/70/marg/3">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/71">
        <i>70. Igor Plotnitsky</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/71/marg/1">So called 'Defence Minister of the People' s Republic of Luhansk'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/71/marg/2">Responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so called 'government of the People' s Republic of Luhansk'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/71/marg/3">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/72">
        <i>71. Nikolay Kozitsyn</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/72/marg/1">June 20, 1956 in Donetsk region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/72/marg/2">Commander of Cossack forces.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/72/marg/3">Responsible for commanding separatists in Eastern Ukraine fighting against the Ukrainian government forces.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/72/marg/4">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/73">
        <i>72. Oleksiy Mozgovy (Oлeкciй Moзгoвий)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/73/marg/1">One of the leaders of armed groups in Eastern Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/73/marg/2">Responsible for training separatists to fight against the Ukrainian government forces.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/73/marg/3">12.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/74">
        <i>Entities:</i>
        <br/>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/75">
        <i>1. PJSC Chernomorneftegaz a.k.a Chornomornaftogaz</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/75/marg/1">Prospekt Kirova/ per. Sovarkomovskji 52/1 Simferopol, Crimea
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/75/marg/2">On 17.03.2014 the 'Parliament of Crimea' adopted a resolution declaring the appropriation of assets belonging to Chernomorneftegaz enterprise on behalf of the 'Republic of Crimea'. The enterprise is thus effectively confiscated by the Crimean 'authorities'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/75/marg/3">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/76">
        <i>2. Feodosia a.k.a Feodossyskoje Predprijatije po obespetscheniju nefteproduktami</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/76/marg/1">98107, Crimea, Feodosiya, Geologicheskaya str.2 Company providing transhipment services for crude oil and oil products.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/76/marg/2">On 17.03.2014 the 'Parliament of Crimea' adopted a resolution declaring the appropriation of assets belonging to Feodosia enterprise on behalf of the 'Republic of Crimea'. The enterprise is thus effectively confiscated by the Crimean 'authorities'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/vedlegg/i/ledd/76/marg/3">12.5.2014</marg>
      </ledd>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/ii" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-07-25-1016/kii">
      <kverdi>II</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/ii/ledd/1">Endringene trer i kraft straks.</ledd>
    </kapittel>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
