<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2014-05-20-656" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-05-20-656">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2014-05-20-656</id>
    <dato>20.05.2014 nr. 656</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2014-05-20</dato>
    <publisert>I 2014 hefte 7 s 977</publisert>
    <ikraft>20.05.2014</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2014-05-20</ikraft>
    <departement>Utenriksdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="for-2003-08-15-1050-§9">F15.08.2003 nr. 1050 § 9</ref>, <ref id="lov-2003-06-27-58">L27.06.2003 nr. 58</ref></hjemmel>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2003-08-15-1050</endrer>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2014-0417</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Endr. i forskrift om tiltak mot Zimbabwe</korttittel>
    <korttittel>4 Endr. i forskrift om særlige tiltak mot Republikken Zimbabwe (Nr. 656)</korttittel>
    <tittel>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om særlige tiltak mot Republikken Zimbabwe</tittel>
    <redaksjonell_note><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Utenriksdepartementet 20. mai 2014 med hjemmel i forskrift 15. august 2003 nr. 1050 om særlige tiltak mot Republikken Zimbabwe § 9.</redaksjonell_note>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/i" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-05-20-656/ki">
      <kverdi>I</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/1">I forskrift 15. august 2003 nr. 1050 om særlige tiltak mot Republikken Zimbabwe gjøres følgende endringer:
<br/></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2">Forskriftens tittel skal lyde:
<br/></ledd>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2/avsnitt/1">
        <i>Forskrift om restriktive tiltak mot Republikken Zimbabwe</i>
        <br/>
      </avsnitt>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2/avsnitt/2">Ny § 7 fjerde ledd skal lyde:</avsnitt>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2/avsnitt/3">Forbudene i første og tredje ledd gjelder ikke for personer og enheter listeført i vedlegg III.
<br/></avsnitt>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2/avsnitt/4">Nåværende § 7 fjerde og femte ledd blir nye femte og sjette ledd.
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2/avsnitt/4/marg/1">Vedlegg I til denne forskrift erstatter eksisterende vedlegg II.
<br/></marg></avsnitt>
      <avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2/avsnitt/5">Vedlegg II til denne forskrift blir nytt vedlegg III.</avsnitt>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/ii" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-05-20-656/kii">
      <kverdi>II</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/ii/ledd/1">Forskriften skal tre i kraft straks.</ledd>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="vedlegg" id="/vedlegg/1" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-05-20-656/v1">
      <kverdi>Vedlegg 1</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <avsnitt id="/vedlegg/1/ledd//avsnitt/1">Vedlegg II: Liste med fysiske og juridiske personer, enheter og organer omhandlet i § 7</avsnitt>
      <avsnitt id="/vedlegg/1/ledd//avsnitt/2">I. Personer</avsnitt>
      <table niv="1" frame="1">
        <thgroup cols="4" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="10*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1"/>
              <entry colname="2">
                <i>Name (and any aliases)</i>
              </entry>
              <entry colname="3">
                <i>Identifying information</i>
              </entry>
              <entry colname="4">
                <i>Grounds for designation</i>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </thgroup>
        <tgroup cols="4" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="10*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(1) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mugabe, Robert Gabriel </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- President, born 21.2.1924;
<br/>- Passport AD001095 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Head of Government and responsible for activities that seriously undermine democracy, respect for human rights and the rule of law. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(2) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Abu Basutu, Titus Mehliswa Johna </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Air Vice-Marshal, Matebeleland South. Born 2.6.1956 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior military officer, directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections in the Gwanda area. Deputy to Air Marshal Perence Shiri (100 on the list). </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(3) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Bonyongwe, Happyton Mabhuya </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Director-General Central Intelligence Organisation, born 6.11.1960;
<br/>- Passport AD002214;
<br/>- ID 63-374707A13 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior security figure with a close association with the ZANU-PF (Zimbabwe African National Union - Patriotic Front) faction of the government and complicit in forming or directing repressive state policy. Accused of kidnapping, torturing and killing MDC activists in June 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(4) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Buka (a.k.a. Bhuka), Flora </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- President's office (Former Minister of State for Special Affairs responsible for Land and Resettlement Programmes, former Minister of State in the Vice-President's office and former Minister of State for the Land Reform in the President's Office), born 25.2.1968 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Minister of State in Vice-President Nkomo's Office Responsible for organising violence in the Gokwe area and targeting the MDC leadership in 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(5) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Bvudzijena, Wayne </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Assistant Police Commissioner, Police Spokesperson; Born 24.04.1958.
<br/>- ID 29-008792V71 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior member of police force. Police spokesperson. In 2008 blamed MDC for sheltering those responsible for electoral violence in the MDC's provincial and national headquarters. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(6) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Charamba, George </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Permanent Secretary, Department for Information and Publicity, born 4.4.1963;
<br/>- Passport AD002226;
<br/>- Passport AD001255
<br/>- ID 07-003617B07 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior civil servant closely associated with the ZANU-PF faction of the government. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(7) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chidarikire, Faber Edmund </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Provincial Governor for Mashonaland West, former Mayor of Chinhoyi, born 6.6.1946;
<br/>- ID 70-056539L70 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Former ZANU-PF mayor of Chinoyi and provincial governor Associated with the ZANU-PF faction of the Government. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(8) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chigwedere, Aeneas Soko </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Provincial Governor: Mashonaland East, former Minister, born 25.11.1939.
<br/>- ID 25-15430J80 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Provincial Governor associated with the ZANU-PF faction of the government. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(9) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chihota, Phineas </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Deputy Minister for Industry and International Trade. Born 23.11.1950 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of Government. Threatened MDC supporters with death and associated with abduction and torture of people in June 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(10) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chihuri, Augustine </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Police Commissioner, born 10.3.1953.
<br/>- Passport AD000206.
<br/>- ID 68-034196M68 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior police officer and member of the Joint Operational Command, closely associated with the repressive policies of ZANU-PF. Publically confessed to support ZANU-PF in contravention of the Police Act. In June 2009 ordered the police to drop all cases related to murders committed to the run-up to the June 2008 Presidential election. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(11) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chinamasa, Patrick Anthony </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister of Justice, Legal and Parliamentary Affairs, born 25.1.1947.
<br/>- ID 63-005591M42 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of Government. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(12) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chindori-Chininga, Edward Takaruza </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Former Minister of Mines and Mining Development, born 14.3.1955.
<br/>- Passport AN388694.
<br/>- ID 63-377216C71 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Former member of the Government with ongoing ties to the ZANU-PF faction of government as ZANU-PF Member of Parliament. Commander of the militia bases in Guruve in the run up to the 2008 elections. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(13) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chinotimba, Joseph </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Vice Chairman of the Zimbabwe National Liberation War Veterans Association, leader of ZANU-PF militia. Born 06.06.1957.
<br/>- ID 63-312672W11 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">During the 2008 elections Chinotimba led group who destroyed Admore Chibutu's home. Together with army members and ZANU-PF supporters attacked Tongeyi Jeremiah's home on May 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(14) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chipwere Augustine </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Brigadier General, former Colonel, Bindura South </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Directly involved in the terror campaign before and during the 2008 elections. Responsible for political upheaval in Bindura. Senior military officer, promoted by the President in 2011. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(15) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chiwenga, Constantine </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Commander Zimbabwe Defence Forces, General (former Army Commander, Lieutenant General), born 25.8.1956.
<br/>- Passport AD000263.
<br/>- ID 63-327568M80 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Member of Joint Operational Command and complicit in forming or directing repressive state policy. Used army for farm takeovers. During 2008 elections was a prime architect of the violence associated with the process of the Presidential run-off. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(16) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chombo, Ignatius Morgan Chiminya </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister of Local Government, Urban and Rural Development, born 1.8.1952.
<br/>- Passport AD000500.
<br/>- ID 70-086938D70 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of the Government and responsible for undermining MDC in local government by restricting funding and harassment. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(17) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Dinha, Martin </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Provincial Governor for Mashonaland Central </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Provincial governor associated with ZANU-PF faction of government. Involved in farm disruptions at Rockwood village concession 2009. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(18) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Goche, Nicholas Tasunungurwa </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister of Transport, Communications and Infrastructural Development (former Minister of State for National Security in the President's Office), born 1.8.1946.
<br/>- ID 63-355978S68 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of the Government. In June 2008 forced all NGOs to cease their field work and food distribution. Responsible for militia base in Shamva and implicated in violence in that area. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(19) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Gono, Gideon </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Governor of the Reserve Bank of Zimbabwe (central bank), born 29.11.59.
<br/>- Passport AD000854.
<br/>- ID 58-001824K07 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Ties to the ZANU-PF faction of the Government and complicit in forming or directing repressive state policy. Illegally channelled funds to ZANU-PF in 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(20) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Gurira, Cephas T. </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Brigadier; former Colonel, Zimbabwe Defence Forces. Born 1.5.1963.
<br/>- ID 29-061056D29 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the 2008 elections. Responsible for inciting violence in Mhondoro. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(21) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Gwekwerere, Stephen (alias Steven) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Colonel, Chinhoyi </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections. Part of group that assaulted people in Chinoyi in 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(22) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Kachepa, Newton </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Member of Parliament for Mudzi North. Born 10.2.70.
<br/>- ID 32-088209M48 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Member of Parliament, involved in the murder of Peter Tom Butao on 14 April 2008 and Kingswell Mateta in July 2008. He directed the torture of many MDC supporters in his constituency. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(23) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Karakadzai, Mike Tichafa </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Air Commodore, Harare Metropolitan Province. Born 7.3.57.
<br/>- ID 63-632526N13 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections by leading the abductions and violence in Harare in 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(24) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Kasukuwere, Saviour </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Deputy Minister for Youth Development Indigenisation and Empowerment and ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy-Secretary for Youth Affairs, born 23.10.1970.
<br/>- ID 45-046113Q45 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of the Government. Organised those involved in violent riots in Harare in February 2011. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(25) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Kazangarare, Jawet </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- ZANU-PF Councillor in Hurungwe North and war veteran. Born 12.4.1957.
<br/>- ID 38-102814B58 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Directly involved in the government-orchestrated terror campaign waged before and during the elections in 2008. Responsible for spearheading violent persecution of MDC supporters in Hurungwe, including rape, murder and destruction of homes and notably involved in murdering Tapiwa Mubwanda, MDC electoral agent in Hurungwe North in May 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(26) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Khumalo, Sibangumuzi </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Brigadier General, Matebeleland North. Born 16.8.1954.
<br/>- ID 08-448357W73 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections. In February 2011, alleged to be part of strategy to unleash violence and terror by deploying senior officers to coordinate the campaign to retain Mugabe in power. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(27) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Kunonga, Nolbert (a.k.a. Nobert) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Self-appointed Anglican Bishop </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Vociferous supporter of the regime. His followers were backed by the police in committing acts of violence against church supporters in 2011. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(28) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Kwainona, Martin </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Assistant Commissioner, born 19.1.1953;
<br/>- Passport AD001073.
<br/>- ID 63-293627V45 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior police officer, passed orders to local authorities to incite violence in Kanyuchi Village, Mount Darwin in April 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(29) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Langa, Andrew </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Deputy Minister for Public Service (former Deputy Minister of Transport and Communications). Born 13.1.65.
<br/>- ID 21-017934E21 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of the Government. In 2005 opened fire on 11 members of the MDC Youth Assembly. Intimidated voters on election day 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(30) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mabunda, Musarashana </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Assistant Police Commissioner. Born 11.11.58.
<br/>- ID 22-026198T13 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Member of the security forces and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of the freedom of peaceful assembly. Directed 11 March 2007 beatings, torture and repression. June 2008 threatened to kill Lovemore Madhuku. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(31) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Machaya, Jason (a.k.a. Jaison) Max Kokerai </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Provincial Governor: Midlands. Former Deputy Minister of Mines and Mining Development, born 13.6.1952.
<br/>- ID 26-003018Z26 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Provincial Governor: Midlands. Associated with ZANU-PF faction of Government. Used influence to block investigation into politically motivated murder which his son allegedly committed. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(32) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Made, Joseph Mtakwese </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister of Agricultural Engineering and Mechanisation (Former Minister of Agriculture and Rural Development), born 21.11.1954.
<br/>- Passport AN000144.
<br/>- ID 29-128547N42 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of the Government </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(33) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Madzongwe, Edna (a.k.a. Edina) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- ZANU-PF President of Senate, born 11.7.1943.
<br/>- ID 63-748119H32 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Member of the ZANU-PF politburo. Used influence to motivate political prosecutions in February 2008. Involved in violence in Chegutu including the takeover of the Stockade Citrus Estate in 2008, giving direct orders to those leading the repression. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(34) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Maluleke, Titus </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Provincial Governor: Masvingo (Former Deputy Minister of Education, Sports and Culture) </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Provincial Governor associated with ZANU-PF members of government. Championed land invasions in Masvingo in 2009. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(35) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mangwana, Paul Munyaradzi </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Chair of the Constitutional Select Committee (COPAC) and former Minister of State for Indigenisation and Empowerment, born 10.8.1961.
<br/>- Passport AD000459.
<br/>- ID 22-017031E12 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of the Government. Sponsored and directed activities of ZANU-PF terror gangs in Chivi Central in May/June 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(36) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Marumahoko, Reuben </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Deputy Minister for Regional Integration and International Cooperation and former Deputy Minister for Foreign Affairs (former Deputy Minister for Home Affairs), born 4.4.1948.
<br/>- ID 63-311317Y71 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of the Government. Commander of ZANU-PF militia in Hurungwe. With a group of ZANU-PF supporters and war veterans he assaulted MDC supporters and destroyed several homes in Hurungwe district between April and July 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(37) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Masuku, Angeline </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Provincial Governor: Matabeleland South and ZANU-PF Politburo, Secretary for Disabled and Disadvantaged, born 14.10.1936.
<br/>- ID 08-266228E19 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Provincial Governor associated with ZANU-PF faction of government. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(38) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mathema, Cain Ginyilitshe Ndabazekhaya </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Provincial Governor, Bulawayo. Born 28.1.1948.
<br/>- ID 63-682168J73 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Provincial Governor associated with ZANU-PF faction of government. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(39) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mathuthu, Thokozile (alias Sithokozile) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Provincial Governor: Matabeleland North and ZANU-PF Politburo, Deputy Secretary for Transport and Social Welfare </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Provincial Governor associated with ZANU-PF faction of government. In June 2008 used position to incite hatred against MDC supporters. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(40) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Matibiri, Innocent Tonderai </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Deputy Police Commissioner. Born 9.10.1968.
<br/>- ID 63-729730V70 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior member of the security forces, linked to the murder of a farm labourer. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(41) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Matiza, Joel Biggie </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Former Deputy Minister for Rural Housing and Social Amenities, born 17.8.1960.
<br/>- Passport ZA557399 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Former ZANU-PF Member of the Government. Organised bases in Murehwa West and South, from where ZNAU-PF supporters which he supervised killed Edward Pfuka on 17 June 2008 and Moses Nyada on 19 June 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(42) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Matonga, Brighton (a.k.a. Bright) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Former Deputy Minister for Information and Publicity, born 1969 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">- Former ZANU-PF Member of the Government. Party spokesperson. Led a group of ZANU-PF supporters that murdered the wife of Dadidrayi Chipiro. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(43) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mhandu, Cairo (a.k.a. Kairo) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Major ZNA. Born 23.11.1960.
<br/>- ID 63-371574V15 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Directly involved in the campaign of terror waged before and after the elections in 2008. Led group of supporters and war veterans who killed Gibbs Tawenga and Hama Ngowani on 30 June 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(44) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mhonda, Fidellis </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Colonel, Rushinga. Born 2.1.1958.
<br/>- ID 75-139696G81 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the 2008 elections. Led political violence in Rushinga. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(45) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Midzi, Amos Bernard (Mugenva) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Former Minister of Mines and Mining Development (former Minister of Energy and Power Development), born 4.7.1952 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF party Chairman in Harare. Former member of the Government associated with ZANU-PF faction of government. Organised convoy of ZANU-PF supporters and soldiers who assaulted people and destroyed homes in June 2008. Linked with violence in Epworth, supporting militia bases in 2008 and again in 2011. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(46) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mnangagwa, Emmerson Dambudzo </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister of Defence born 15.9.1946.
<br/>- Passport AD00060.
<br/>- ID 63-450183P67 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of Government and member of Joint Operation Command. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(47) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mohadi, Kembo Campbell Dugishi </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Co-Minister of Home Affairs (former Deputy Minister of Local Government, Public Works and National Housing), born 15.11.1949.
<br/>- ID 02-012912X02 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of Government and member of Joint Operational Command. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(48) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Moyo, Jonathan Nathaniel </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Former Minister of State for Information and Publicity in the President's Office, born 12.1.1957.
<br/>- Passport AD000432.
<br/>- ID 63-857281M73 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Former member of the ZANU-PF Government. Incited violence and hatred, and architect of laws inhibiting freedom of speech. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(49) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Moyo, Sibusio Bussie </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Brigadier General ZNA </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Directly involved in the campaign of terror waged before and after the elections, including the murder of MDC supporters. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(50) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Moyo, Simon Khaya </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Chairman of ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy Secretary for Legal Affairs, born 1945. born 1.10.1945.
<br/>- Passport ZD001512.
<br/>- ID 63-735452P56 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Member of the ZANU-PF politburo with ongoing ties to its repressive policy. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(51) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mpofu, Obert Moses </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister for Mines and Mining Development former Minister for Industry and International Trade (former Provincial Governor: Matabeleland North) (ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy Secretary for National Security), born 12.10.1951. - Passport ZD001549.
<br/>- ID 08-186074F79 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of Government. In March 2008 incited ZANU-PF supports to drive MDC opponents out of their homes to stop them voting. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(52) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Muchena, Henry </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Air Vice-Marshal, Midlands. Head of ZANU-PF Commissariat </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior military officer linked to ZANU-PF, directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections. Spearheaded violence in Zhombe and Gokwe during 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(53) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Muchena, Olivia Nyembesi (a.k.a. Nyembezi) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister for Women's Affairs, Gender and Community Development, former Minister of State for Science and Technology in the President's Office (former Minister of State in Vice-President Msika's Office), born 18.8.1946.
<br/>- Passport AD000086.
<br/>- ID 63-337191X50 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of the Government. Linked to politically motivated murders and personally involved in the destruction of Revai Kativhu's home on 1 May 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(54) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Muchinguri, Oppah Chamu Zvipange </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- ZANU-PF Politburo Secretary for Gender and Culture (Former Minister for Women's Affairs, Gender and Community Development), born 14.12.1958.
<br/>- ID 63-741411R50 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Former ZANU-PF member of the Government, remains a member of ZANU-PF politburo. Played a lead role in the violence in Masvingo province in 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(55) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mudede, Tobaiwa (a.k.a. Tonneth) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Registrar General, born 22.12.1942.
<br/>- ID 36-452750E70 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Ties to the ZANU-PF faction of Government and complicit in forming or directing state policy, notably in relation to election rigging. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(56) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mugabe, Grace </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Born 23.7.1965;
<br/>- Passport AD001159.
<br/>- ID 63-646650Q70 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Associated with the ZANU-PF faction of the government. Took over the Iron Mask Estate in 2002; alleged to illicitly derive large profits from diamond mining. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(57) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mujuru, Joyce Teurai Ropa </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Vice President (former Minister of Water Resources and Infrastructural Development), born 15.4.1955.
<br/>- ID 63-445325J18 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of Government. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(58) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mumbengegwi, Simbarashe Simbanenduku </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Minister of Foreign Affairs, born 20.7.1945;
<br/>- Passport AD001086.
<br/>- ID 63-677272A12 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of Government. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(59) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Murerwa, Herbert Muchemwa </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister of Lands and Rural Resettlement, born 31.7.1941.
<br/>- Passport AD001167.
<br/>- ID 25-021670R25 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of Government </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(60) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Musariri, Munyaradzi </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Assistant Police Commissioner </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior member of the security forces and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of the freedom of peaceful assembly, notably in Murambatsvina in July 2005. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(61) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mushohwe, Christopher Chindoti </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Provincial Governor: Manicaland. (Former Minister of Transport and Communications, former Deputy Minister of Transport and Communications), born 6.2.1954.
<br/>- ID 63-101480P75 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Provincial Governor associated with ZANU-PF. In February 2009 accompanied by soldiers told the Chiadzwa community they would be relocated without compensation. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(62) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mutasa, Didymus Noel Edwin </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister of State for Presidential Affairs in the President's Office, former Minister of State for National Security, Land Reform and Resettlement in the Office of the President, ZANU-PF, Secretary for Administration, born 27.7.1935.
<br/>- ID 63-358184Q42 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of the Government. Involved in murders in Manicaland. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(63) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mutezo, Munacho Thomas Alvar </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Former Minister for Water Resources and Infrastructural Development. Born 14.2.54.
<br/>- Passport AN187189.
<br/>- ID 29-129727W44 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Former member of the Government, associated with ZANU-PF. Orchestrated a campaign of terror and intimidating MDC supporters in Chimanimani West in conjunction with the Zimbabwean National Army in August 2010. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(64) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mutinhiri, Ambros (a.k.a. Ambrose) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Former Minister of Youth Development, Gender and Employment Creation, Retired Brigadier. Born 22.2.1944.
<br/>- Passport AD000969.
<br/>- ID 63-285106H32 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Former ZANU-PF Member of Government. March 2008 led a group of ZANU-PF supporters to Landas and assaulted several MDC supporters. Set up and supported military bases in Chihota where many MDC supporters were assaulted and tortured. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(65) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mzembi, Walter </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister for Tourism and the Hospitality Industry, former Deputy Minister for Water Resources and Infrastructural Development, born 16.3.1964.
<br/>- ID 22-050240B22 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of the Government. Responsible for organising groups of ZANU-PF supporters to assault Masvingo residents prior to MDC's 8th year anniversary celebrations. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(66) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mzilikazi, Morgan S. </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Colonel (MID), Buhera Central </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections. Involved in election violence in Makoni and Buhera in 2008. July 2008 abducted MDC MP for Buhera South. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(67) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Nguni, Sylvester Robert </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister of State in the President's Officer, former Minister of Economic Development (Former Deputy Minister for Agriculture), born 4.8.1955 alt 4.5.1955.
<br/>- Passport ZE215371.
<br/>- ID 63-453707V32 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of the Government </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(68) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Nhema, Francis Chenayimoyo Dunstan </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister of Environment and Natural Resources Management and former Minister of Environment and Tourism, born 7.4.1959 alt 17.4.1959. - Passport AD000966.
<br/>- ID 63-117843A66 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of Government. In September 2009 forced for safari operators to give up shares in ranches and conservancies. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(69) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Nyanhongo, Magadzire Hubert </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Deputy Minister of Energy and Power Development, former Deputy Minister of Transport and Communications. Born 26.11.1957.
<br/>- ID 34-032890W34 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of the Government. Involved in organising anti-MDC violence in Epworth and Nyanga in 2011. Involved in politically motivated murder in 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(70) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Nyikayaramba, Douglas </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Brigadier General, Mashonaland East. Commander 3rd Brigade </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior officer directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the 2008 elections. Ordered junior soldiers to deal with MDC supporters in Manicaland. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(71) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Nyoni, Sithembiso Gile Glad </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister of Small and Medium Enterprises Development and Employment Creation, born 20.9.1949.
<br/>- Passport AD000223.
<br/>- ID 08-434871M67 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of Government </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(72) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Rugeje, Engelbert Abel </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Major-General, Masvingo Province. Director,
<br/>- Defence Studies, Zimbabwe Defence Forces. DOB 17.7.1959.
<br/>- ID 63-539305L04 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior army officer directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the 2008 elections by coordinating most of the violent incidents in Masvingo. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(73) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Rungani, Victor Tapiwa Chashe </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Colonel, Chikomba. Born 29.6.1949.
<br/>- ID 22-025306Z04 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections in Chikomba in 2008, including assaults and abductions. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(74) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sakupwanya, Stanley Urayayi </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- ZANU-PF Politburo Deputy Secretary for Health and Child Welfare. Born 14.5.1939.
<br/>- ID 63-435281R50 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Member of the ZANU-PF politburo associated with the ZANU-PF faction of the Government. Linked to electoral violence in Makoni during the 2008 Presidential elections. Commander of a base in Makoni used for interrogations. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(75) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Savanhu, Tendai </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- ZANU-PF Deputy Secretary for Transport and Social Welfare, born 21.3.1968 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">- Member of the ZANU-PF politburo associated with the ZANU-PF faction of the Government. Organised militias to assault MDC supporters in Mbare, leading to violence and chaos, in February 2011. Involved in abductions of MDC women in June 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(76) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sekeramayi, Sydney (a.k.a. Sidney) Tigere </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister of State for National Secuirty in the President's Office. Former Minister of Defence, born 30.3.1944.
<br/>- ID 63-358166W43 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of Government and member of ZANU-PF Joint Operational Command </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(77) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sekeremayi, Lovemore </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Chief Elections Officer </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Ties to the ZANU-PF faction of government and complicit in forming or directing oppressive state policy through election rigging in 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(78) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Shamu, Webster Kotiwani </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Minister for Media, Information and Publicity; former Minister of State for Policy Implementation (former Minister of State for Policy Implementation in the President's Office), born 6.6.1945.
<br/>- Passport AN203141.
<br/>- ID 63-676065N32 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of the Government involved activities interfering with the freedom of the press in 2009. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(79) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Shamuyarira, Nathan Marwirakuwa </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- ZANU-PF Politburo Secretary for Information and Publicity, born 29.9.1928 or 29.9.1930.
<br/>- Passport AD000468.
<br/>- ID 63-327601Y32 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Member of the ZANU-PF politburo with strong ties to the ZANU-PF government faction. Involved in violent attempted farm take-over in September 2009 which ended in an arson attack. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(80) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Shiri, Perence (a.k.a. Bigboy) Samson Chikerema </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Air Marshal (Air Force), born 1.11.1955.
<br/>- ID 29-098876M18 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior military officer and member of ZANU-PF Joint Operational Command and complicit in forming or directing oppressive state policy. Involved in political violence in Chiadzwa in October 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(81) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Shungu, Etherton </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Brigadier General, Mashonaland Central </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior military officer in the ZANU-PF Cmmissariat, directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections in Bindura in 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(82) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sibanda, Chris </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Colonel, Bulawayo Province </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections in Byo in 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(83) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sibanda, Jabulani </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Former Chair, National War Veterans Association, born 31.12.1970 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Ties to the ZANU-PF faction of government and complicit in forming or directing oppressive state policy. Involved in violence against MDC supporters in Makoni, Bikita, Masvingo and Guto particularly in relation to the implementation of an outreach programme in 2010. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(84) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sibanda, Misheck Julius Mpande </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Cabinet Secretary (successor to Charles Utete), born 3.5.1949. - ID 63-685365X67 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Associated with ZANU-PF faction of government. In March 2010 gave instructions to ministers and cabinet secretaries to report to ZANU-PF politicians and not the Prime Minister Morgan Tsvangirai. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(85) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sibanda, Phillip Valerio (a.k.a. Valentine) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Commander Zimbabwe National Army, Lieutenant General, born 25.8.1956 or 24.12.1954.
<br/>- ID 63-357671H26 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior army figure with ties to the Government and complicit in forming or directing oppressive state policy, blaming NGOs for unrest in September 2009. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(86) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sigauke, David </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Brigadier General, Mash West Province </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior army figure directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections, including violence and torture against civilians in the diamond fields and threatening a coup if the MDC won the elections. Linked to violence in Chinhoyi in 2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(87) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sikosana, (a.k.a. Sikhosana), Absolom </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- ZANU-PF Politburo Secretary for Youth Affairs </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Member of the ZANU-PF politburo associated with the ZANU-PF faction of the Government. Threatened to unleash violence in 2011 if sanctions not removed. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(88) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Tarumbwa, Nathaniel Charles </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Brigadier General, Manicaland and Mutare South. Born 6.10.1960.
<br/>- ID 63-849216W75 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior military officer directly involved in the terror campaign waged before and during the elections. In charge of torture base in Makoni West, Mutasa Central in 2007/2008. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(89) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Tomana, Johannes </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Attorney General. Born 9.9.1967.
<br/>- ID 50-036322F50 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">ZANU-PF Member of Government. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(90) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Veterai, Edmore </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Senior Assistant Police Commissioner, Officer Commanding Harare. Born 20.11.1962.
<br/>- ID 08-260467S04 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Senior member of the security forces and bearing wide responsibility for serious violations of the freedom of peaceful assembly, and involved in invasion of Farm Thirty. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(91) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Zimondi, Paradzai Willings </entry>
              <entry colname="3">- Prisons Director, born 4.3.1947.
<br/>- ID 75-145185Z47 </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Member of Joint Operational Command and complicit in forming or directing oppressive state policy. Responsible for funding and accommodating militias in 2008. Ordered prison officers to vote for Mugabe, and responsible for human rights abuses in prisons. </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <avsnitt id="/vedlegg/1/ledd//avsnitt/3">II. Entities</avsnitt>
      <table niv="1" frame="1">
        <thgroup cols="4" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="10*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1"/>
              <entry colname="2">
                <i>Name</i>
              </entry>
              <entry colname="3">
                <i>Identifying information</i>
              </entry>
              <entry colname="4">
                <i>Grounds for designation</i>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </thgroup>
        <tgroup cols="4" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="10*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="3" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <colspec colname="4" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="20*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(1) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Cold Comfort Farm Trust Co-operative </entry>
              <entry colname="3">7 Cowie Road, Tynwald, Harare, Zimbabwe. </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Owned by Didymus Mutasa, Grace Mugabe also involved. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(2) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Comoil (PVT) Ltd. </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Block D, Emerald Hill Office, Emerald Park, Harare, Zimbabwe. 2nd Floor, Travel Plaza, 29 Mazoe Street, Box CY22344, Causeway, Harare, Zimbabwe. </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Owned by Saviour Kasukuwere. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(3) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Famba Safaris </entry>
              <entry colname="3">4 Wayhill Lane, Umwisdale, Harare, Zimbabwe; PO Box CH273, Chisipite, Harare, Zimbabwe. </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Major shareholder is Webster Shamu. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(4) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Jongwe Printing and Publishing Company (PVT) Ltd. (a.k.a. Jongwe Printing and Publishing Co., a.k.a. Jongwe Printing and Publishing Company) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">14 Austin Road, Coventry Road, Workington, PO Box 5988, Harare, Zimbabwe. </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Publishing arm associated with the ZANU-PF faction of the Government </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(5) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">M &amp; S Syndicate (PVT) Ltd. </entry>
              <entry colname="3">First Floor, Victory House, 88 Robert Mugabe Road, Harare, Zimbabwe; PO Box 1275, Harare, Zimbabwe. </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Investment company associated with the ZNU-PF faction of the Government. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(6) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">OSLEG Ltd. (a.k.a. Operation Sovereign Legitimacy) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">Lonhoro House, Union Avenue, Harare, Zimbabwe. </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Controlled by Zimbabwe army. Associated with the Ministry of Defence and the ZANU-PF faction of Government. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(7) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Swift Investments (PVT) Ltd. </entry>
              <entry colname="3">730 Cowie Road, Tynwald, Harare, Zimbabwe; PO Box 3928, Harare, Zimbabwe. </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Associated with the ZANU-PF faction of Government. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(8) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Zidco Holdings (a.k.a. Zidco Holdings (PVT) Ltd.) </entry>
              <entry colname="3">PO Box 1275, Harare, Zimbabwe. </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Financial holding company associated with the ZNU-PF faction of the Government. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(9) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Zimbabwe Defence Industries </entry>
              <entry colname="3">10th floor, Trustee House, 55 Samora Machel Avenue, PO Box 6597, Harare, Zimbabwe. </entry>
              <entry colname="4">Associated with the Ministry of Defence and the ZANU-PF faction of Government. </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="vedlegg" id="/vedlegg/2" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-05-20-656/v2">
      <kverdi>Vedlegg 2</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <avsnitt id="/vedlegg/2/ledd//avsnitt/1">Vedlegg III: Liste med personer og enheter og organer omhandlet i § 7 fjerde ledd</avsnitt>
      <avsnitt id="/vedlegg/2/ledd//avsnitt/2">I. Persons</avsnitt>
      <table niv="1" frame="1">
        <thgroup cols="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="50*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1"/>
              <entry colname="2">
                <i>Name (and any aliases)</i>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </thgroup>
        <tgroup cols="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="50*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(1) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Abu Basutu, Titus Mehliswa Johna </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(2) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Buka (a.k.a. Bhuka), Flora </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(3) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Bvudzijena, Wayne </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(4) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Charamba, George </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(5) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chidarikire, Faber Edmund </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(6) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chigwedere, Aeneas Soko </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(7) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chihota, Phineas </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(8) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chinamasa, Patrick Anthony </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(9) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chindori-Chininga, Edward Takaruza </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(10) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chinotimba, Joseph </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(11) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chipwere Augustine </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(12) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chombo, Ignatius Morgan Chiminya </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(13) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Dinha, Martin </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(14) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Goche, Nicholas Tasunungurwa </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(15) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Gono, Gideon </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(16) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Gurira, Cephas T. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(17) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Gwekwerere, Stephen (alias Steven) </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(18) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Kachepa, Newton </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(19) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Karakadzai, Mike Tichafa </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(20) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Kasukuwere, Saviour </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(21) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Kazangarare, Jawet </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(22) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Khumalo, Sibangumuzi </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(23) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Kunonga, Nolbert (a.k.a. Nobert) </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(24) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Kwainona, Martin </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(25) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Langa, Andrew </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(26) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mabunda, Musarashana </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(27) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Machaya, Jason (a.k.a. Jaison) Max Kokerai </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(28) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Made, Joseph Mtakwese </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(29) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Madzongwe, Edna (a.k.a. Edina) </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(30) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Maluleke, Titus </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(31) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mangwana, Paul Munyaradzi </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(32) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Marumahoko, Reuben </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(33) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Masuku, Angeline </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(34) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mathema, Cain Ginyilitshe Ndabazekhaya </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(35) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mathuthu, Thokozile (alias Sithokozile) </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(36) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Matibiri, Innocent Tonderai </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(37) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Matiza, Joel Biggie </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(38) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Matonga, Brighton (a.k.a. Bright) </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(39) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mhandu, Cairo (a.k.a. Kairo) </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(40) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mhonda, Fidellis </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(41) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Midzi, Amos Bernard (Mugenva) </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(42) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mnangagwa, Emmerson Dambudzo </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(43) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mohadi, Kembo Campbell Dugishi </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(44) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Moyo, Jonathan Nathaniel </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(45) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Moyo, Sibusio Bussie </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(46) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Moyo, Simon Khaya </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(47) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mpofu, Obert Moses </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(48) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Muchena, Henry </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(49) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Muchena, Olivia Nyembesi (a.k.a. Nyembezi) </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(50) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Muchinguri, Oppah Chamu Zvipange </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(51) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mudede, Tobaiwa (a.k.a. Tonneth) </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(52) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mujuru, Joyce Teurai Ropa </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(53) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mumbengegwi, Simbarashe Simbanenduku </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(54) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Murerwa, Herbert Muchemwa </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(55) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Musariri, Munyaradzi </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(56) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mushohwe, Christopher Chindoti </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(57) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mutezo, Munacho Thomas Alvar </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(58) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mutinhiri, Ambros (a.k.a. Ambrose) </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(59) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mzembi, Walter </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(60) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mzilikazi, Morgan S. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(61) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Nguni, Sylvester Robert </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(62) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Nhema, Francis Chenayimoyo Dunstan </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(63) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Nyanhongo, Magadzire Hubert </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(64) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Nyoni, Sithembiso Gile Glad </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(65) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Rugeje, Engelbert Abel </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(66) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Rungani, Victor Tapiwa Chashe </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(67) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sakupwanya, Stanley Urayayi </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(68) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Savanhu, Tendai </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(69) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sekeramayi, Sydney (a.k.a. Sidney) Tigere </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(70) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sekeremayi, Lovemore </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(71) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Shamu, Webster Kotiwani </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(72) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Shamuyarira, Nathan Marwirakuwa </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(73) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Shungu, Etherton </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(74) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sibanda, Chris </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(75) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sibanda, Misheck Julius Mpande </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(76) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sigauke, David </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(77) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sikosana, (a.k.a. Sikhosana), Absolom </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(78) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Tarumbwa, Nathaniel Charles </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(79) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Tomana, Johannes </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(80) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Veterai, Edmore </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(81) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Zimondi, Paradzai Willings </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(82) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Bonyongwe, Happyton Mabhuya </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(83) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chihuri, Augustine </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(84) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Chiwenga, Constantine </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(85) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Mutasa, Didymus Noel Edwin </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(86) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Nyikayaramba, Douglas </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(87) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Shiri, Perence (a.k.a. Bigboy) Samson Chikerema </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(88) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sibanda, Jabulani </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(89) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Sibanda, Phillip Valerio (a.k.a. Valentine) </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <avsnitt id="/vedlegg/2/ledd//avsnitt/3">II. Entities</avsnitt>
      <table niv="1" frame="1">
        <thgroup cols="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="50*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1"/>
              <entry colname="2">
                <b>Name</b>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </thgroup>
        <tgroup cols="2" rowsep="0" colsep="0">
          <colspec colname="1" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="6*"/>
          <colspec colname="2" align="left" valign="top" colwidth="50*"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(1) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Cold Comfort Farm Trust Co-operative </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(2) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Comoil (PVT) Ltd. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(3) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Famba Safaris </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(4) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Jongwe Printing and Publishing Company (PVT) Ltd. (a.k.a. Jongwe Printing and Publishing Co., a.k.a. Jongwe Printing and Publishing Company) </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(5) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">M &amp; S Syndicate (PVT) Ltd. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(6) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">OSLEG Ltd. (a.k.a. Operation Sovereign Legitimacy) </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(7) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Swift Investments (PVT) Ltd. </entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry colname="1">(8) </entry>
              <entry colname="2">Zidco Holdings (a.k.a. Zidco Holdings (PVT) Ltd.) </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </kapittel>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
