<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dokument xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="https://lovdata.no/regelverk" xsi:schemaLocation="lov-eksempel.xsd" id="for-2014-07-29-1022" type="lt" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-07-29-1022">
  <metadata>
    <type>lt</type>
    <base>LT</base>
    <id>LT/lt/2014-07-29-1022</id>
    <dato>29.07.2014 nr. 1022</dato>
    <dato type="iso">2014-07-29</dato>
    <publisert>I 2014 hefte 11 s 1688</publisert>
    <ikraft>05.08.2014</ikraft>
    <ikraft type="iso">2014-08-05</ikraft>
    <departement>Utenriksdepartementet</departement>
    <etat/>
    <gjelder>Norge</gjelder>
    <hjemmel><ref id="for-2014-03-21-301-§5">F21.03.2014 nr. 301 § 5</ref>, <ref id="lov-2001-04-27-14">L27.04.2001 nr. 14</ref></hjemmel>
    <endrer type="ref">https://lovdata.no/for/2014-03-21-301</endrer>
    <rettet/>
    <journalnummer>2014-0745</journalnummer>
  </metadata>
  <tekst>
    <korttittel>Endr. forskrift om tiltak vedr. Ukrainas integritet mv.</korttittel>
    <korttittel>4 Endr. i forskrift om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet og uavhengighet (Nr. 1022)</korttittel>
    <tittel>Forskrift om endring i forskrift om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet og uavhengighet</tittel>
    <marg niv="1" id="/marg/1"><b>Hjemmel:</b> Fastsatt av Utenriksdepartementet 29. juli 2014 med hjemmel i forskrift 21. mars 2014 nr. 301 om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet og uavhengighet § 5.</marg>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/i" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-07-29-1022/ki">
      <kverdi>I</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/1">I forskrift 21. mars 2014 nr. 301 om restriktive tiltak vedrørende handlinger som undergraver eller truer Ukrainas territorielle integritet, suverenitet og uavhengighet gjøres følgende endringer:
<br/>
<marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/1/marg/1">Følgende personer skal legges til Vedlegg I:
<br/></marg></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2">
        <i>73. Mikhail Efimovich FRADKOV (MиXаил Eфимoвич Фрадкoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2/marg/1">Born on 1.9.1950 in Kurumoch, Kuibyshev region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2/marg/2">Permanent member of the Security Council of the Russian Federation; Director of the Foreign Intelligence Service of the Russian Federation. As a member of the Security Council, which provides advice on and coordinates national security affairs, he was involved in shaping the policy of the Russian Government threatening the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/2/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3">
        <i>74. Nikolai Platonovich PATRUSHEV (Hикoлай Платoнoвич Патрyшeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/marg/1">Born on 11.7.1951 in Leningrad (St Petersburg)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/marg/2">Permanent member and Secretary of the Security Council of the Russian Federation. As a member of the Security Council, which provides advice on and coordinates national security affairs, he was involved in shaping the policy of the Russian Government threatening the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/3/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/4">
        <i>75. Aleksandr Vasilievich BORTNIKOV (Aлeкcандр Bаcильeвич Бoртникoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/4/marg/1">Born on 15.11.1951 in Perm
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/4/marg/2">Permanent member of the Security Council of the Russian Federation; Director of the Federal Security Service (FSB). As a member of the Security Council, which provides advice on and coordinates national security affairs, he was involved in shaping the policy of the Russian Government threatening the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/4/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5">
        <i>76. Rashid Gumarovich NURGALIEV (Pашид Гyмарoвич Hyргалиeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5/marg/1">Born on 8.10.1956 in Zhetikara, Kazakh Soviet Socialist Republic
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5/marg/2">Permanent member and Deputy Secretary of the Security Council of the Russian Federation. As a member of the Security Council, which provides advice on and coordinates national security affairs, he was involved in shaping the policy of the Russian Government threatening the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/5/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6">
        <i>77. Boris Vyacheslavovich GRYZLOV (Бoриc Bячecлавoвич Грызлoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6/marg/1">Born on 15.12.1950 in Vladivostok
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6/marg/2">Permanent member of the Security Council of the Russian Federation. As a member of the Security Council, which provides advice on and coordinates national security affairs, he was involved in shaping the policy of the Russian Government threatening the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/6/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7">
        <i>78. Sergei Orestovoch BESEDA (Ceргeй Oрecтoвич Бeceда)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7/marg/1">1954
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7/marg/2">Commander of the Fifth Service of the FSB, Federal Security Service of the Russian Federation. As a senior FSB officer, he heads a service responsible which oversees intelligence operations and international activity.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/7/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/8">
        <i>79. Mikhail Vladimirovich DEGTYAREV (Mиxаил Bладимирoвич Дeгтярëв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/8/marg/1">Born on 10.7.1981 in Kuibyshev (Samara)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/8/marg/2">Member of the State Duma. On 23.5.2014 he announced the inauguration of the 'de facto embassy' of the unrecognized, so-called, 'Donetsk People's Republic' in Moscow, he contributes to undermine or threaten the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/8/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9">
        <i>80. Ramzan Akhmadovitch KADYROV (Pамзан Axматoвич Кадырoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/marg/1">Born on 5.10.1976 in Tsentaroy.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/marg/2">President of the Republic of Chechnya. Kadyrov made statements in support of the illegal annexation of Crimea and in support of the armed insurgency in Ukraine. He stated inter alia on 14 June 2014 that he 'will do anything to help revive Crimea'. In that context, he was awarded the medal for 'the liberation of Crimea' by the Acting Head of the Autonomous Republic of Crimea for the support he provided to the unlawful annexation of Crimea. In addition, on 1 June 2014 he expressed his readiness to send 74 000 Chechen volonteers to Ukraine if requested to do so.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/9/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10">
        <i>81. Alexander Nikolayevich TKACHYOV (AЛEКCAHДP HИКOЛAEBИЧ Tкачëв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/marg/1">Born on 23.12.1960 in Vyselki.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/marg/2">Governor of the Krasnodar Krai. He was awarded the medal 'for the liberation of Crimea' by the Acting head of the Autonomous Republic of Crimea for the support he provided to the unlawful annexation of Crimea. At that occasion, the Acting Head of the Autonomous Republic of Crimea said that Tkachyov was one of the first to express his support to the new 'leadership' of Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/10/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/11">
        <i>82. Pavel GUBAREV (Павeл Юрьeвич Гyбарeв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/11/marg/1">Born on 10.2.1983 in Sievierodonetsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/11/marg/2">One of the self-described leaders of the so-called 'people' Republic of Donetsk'. He requested Russian intervention in eastern Ukraine, including through the deployment of Russian peacekeeping forces. He is associated with Igor Strelkov/Girkin, who is responsible for actions which undermine or threaten the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. Gubarev is responsible for recruiting people for armed forces of separatists. Responsible for taking over of the regional government building in Donetsk with pro-Russian forces and proclaimed himself the 'people's governor'. Despite being arrested for threatening the territorial integrity of Ukraine, and subsequently released, he has continued to play a prominent role in separatist activities, thus undermining the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/11/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/12">
        <i>83. Ekaterina GUBAREVA (Eкатeрина Юрьeвна Гyбарeва)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/12/marg/1">Born on 5.7.1983 in Kakhovka
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/12/marg/2">In her capacity of so called 'Minister of Foreign Affairs' she is responsible of defending the so called 'Donetsk People's Republic', thus undermining the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. In addition, her bank account is used to finance illegal armed separatist groups. In taking on and acting in this capacity she has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/12/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/13">
        <i>84. Fedor BEREZIN (Фëдoр Дмитриeвич Бeрeзин)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/13/marg/1">Born on 7.2.1960 in Donetsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/13/marg/2">The so-called 'deputy defence minister' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic'. He is associated with Igor Strelkov/Girkin, the so-called 'defence minister' of the so-called 'Donetsk People's Republic', who is responsible for actions which undermine or threaten the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. In taking on and acting in this capacity Berezin has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/13/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/14">
        <i>85. Valery Vladimirovich KAUROV (Bалeрий Bладимирoвич Каyрoв)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/14/marg/1">Born on 2.4.1956 in Odessa
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/14/marg/2">The self-described 'president' of the so-called 'Republic of Novorossiya' who has called on Russia to deploy troops to Ukraine. In taking on and acting in this capacity he has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/14/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/15">
        <i>86. Serhii Anatoliyovych ZDRILIUK (Ceргeй Aнатoльeвич Здрылюкv)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/15/marg/1">Born on 23.6.1972 in Vinnytsia region
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/15/marg/2">Senior aid to Igor Strelkov/Girkin who is responsible for actions which undermine or threaten the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine. In taking on and acting in this capacity, Zdriliuk has therefore supported actions and policies which undermine the territorial integrity, sovereignty and independence of Ukraine.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/15/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/16">
        <i>87. Vladimir ANTYUFEYEV (Bладимир Aнтюфeeв) (aka Vladimir SHEVTSOV, Vladimir Iurievici ANTIUFEEV, Vladimir Gheorghievici ALEXANDROV, Vadim Gheorghievici SHEVTSOV)</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/16/marg/1">Born on 19.2. 1951 in Novosibirsk
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/16/marg/2">Former 'Ministry of State Security' in the separatist region of Transnistria. Since 9 July 2014, he has been the first vice-prime minister of Donetsk People's Republic, responsible for security and law enforcement. In his capacity, he is responsible for the separatist 'governmental' activities of the so called 'government of the Donetsk People's Republic'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/16/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/16/marg/4">Listen over enheter i vedlegg I erstattes med:
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/17">
        <i>Enheter:</i>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18">Informasjon vedrørende samtlige listeførte enheter er rubrisert slik:
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/liste/1"><lverdi>-</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/liste/1/avsnitt/1">Navn</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/liste/2"><lverdi>-</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/liste/2/avsnitt/1">Adresse</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/liste/3"><lverdi>-</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/liste/3/avsnitt/1">Grunnlag</avsnitt></liste>
<liste id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/liste/4"><lverdi>-</lverdi><avsnitt id="/kapittel/i/ledd/18/liste/4/avsnitt/1">Dato for EUs listeføring
<br/></avsnitt></liste></ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/19">
        <i>1. PJSC Chernomorneftegaz a.k.a Chornomornaftogaz</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/19/marg/1">Prospekt Kirova/per. Sovarkomovskji 52/1 Simferopol, Crimea
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/19/marg/2">On 17.03.2014 the 'Parliament of Crimea' adopted a resolution declaring the appropriation of assets belonging to Chernomorneftegaz enterprise on behalf of the 'Republic of Crimea'. The enterprise is thus effectively confiscated by the Crimean 'authorities'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/19/marg/3">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/20">
        <i>2. Feodosia a.k.a Feodossyskoje Predprijatije po obespetscheniju nefteproduktami</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/20/marg/1">98107, Crimea, Feodosiya, Geologicheskaya str. 2 Company providing transhipment services for crude oil and oil products.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/20/marg/2">On 17.03.2014 the 'Parliament of Crimea' adopted a resolution declaring the appropriation of assets belonging to Feodosia enterprise on behalf of the 'Republic of Crimea'. The enterprise is thus effectively confiscated by the Crimean 'authorities'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/20/marg/3">12.5.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/21">
        <i>3. State ferry enterprise 'Kerch ferry' (Гocyдарcтвeнная cyдoxoдная кoмпания 'Кeрчeнcкая парoмная пeрeправа'), Gosudarstvenoye predpriyatiye, Kerchenskaya paromnaya pereprava</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/21/marg/1">16 Tselibernaya Street, 98307 Kerch(Aвтoнoмная Pecпyблика Крым, г. Кeрчь, yл. Цeлимбeрная, 16) code: 14333981
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/21/marg/2">The ownership of the entity was transferred contrary to the Ukrainian law. The 'Parliament of Crimea' adopted a resolution No. 1757-6/14 on 17.3.2014 'On nationalization of some companies belonging to the Ukrainian ministries of infrastructure or agriculture' and the 'Presidium of the Parliament of Crimea' adopted a decision No. 1802-6/14 on 24.3.2014'On state-owned Ferry Enterprise Kerch Ferry' declaring the appropriation of assets belonging to the state ferry enterprise 'Kerch Ferry' on behalf of the 'Republic of Crimea'. The enterprise is thus effectively confiscated by the Crimean 'authorities'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/21/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/22">
        <i>4. State enterprise 'Sevastopol commercial seaport' (Гocyдарcтвeннoe прeдприятиe 'Ceваcтoпoльcкий мoрcкoй тoргoвый пoрт'), Gosudarstvenoye predpriyatiye, Sevastopolski morskoy torgovy port</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/22/marg/1">3 Place Nakhimova, 99011 Sevastopol (99011, г. Ceваcтoпoль, пл. Hаxимoва, 3) code: 01125548
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/22/marg/2">The ownership of the entity was transferred contrary to the Ukrainian law. On 17.3.2014 the 'Parliament of Crimea' adopted a resolution No. 1757-6/14 'On nationalization of some companies belonging to the Ukrainian ministries of infrastructure or agriculture' declaring the appropriation of assets belonging to the state enterprise 'Sevastopol commercial seaport' on behalf of the 'Republic of Crimea'. The enterprise is thus effectively confiscated by the Crimean 'authorities'. In terms of volume of trade, it is the biggest commercial seaport in Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/22/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/23">
        <i>5. State enterprise 'Kerch commercial sea port' (Гocyдарcтвeннoe прeдприятиe 'Кeрчeнcкий мoрcкoй тoргoвый пoрт'), Gosudarstvenoye predpriyatiye, Kerchenski morskoy torgovy port</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/23/marg/1">28 Kirova Str., 98312, Kerch, Autonomous Republic of Crimea, (98312, Aвтoнoмная Pecпyблика Крым, г. Кeрчь, yл. Кирoва, 28) Code: 01125554
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/23/marg/2">The ownership of the entity was transferred contrary to the Ukrainian law. The 'Parliament of Crimea' adopted a resolution No. 1757-6/14 on 17.3.2014 'On nationalization of some companies belonging to the Ukrainian ministries of infrastructure or agriculture' and a resolution No. 1865-6/14 on 26.3.2014 'On State-Owned Enterprise «Crimean Sea Ports' ('O Гocyдарcтвeннoм прeдприятии 'Крымcкиe мoрcкиe пoрты') declaring the appropriation of assets belonging to the state enterprise 'Kerch Commercial Sea Port' on behalf of the 'Republic of Crimea'. The enterprise is thus effectively confiscated by the Crimean 'authorities'. In terms of volume of trade, it is the second biggest commercial seaport in Crimea.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/23/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/24">
        <i>6. State enterprise Universal -Avia (Гocyдарcтвeннoм прeдприятии 'Унивeрcал-Aвиа'), Gosudarstvenoye predpriyatiye, 'Universal-Avia'</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/24/marg/1">5, Aeroflotskaya street, 95024 Simferopol (Aэрoфлoтcкая yлица, 5, Cимфeрoпoль г.)
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/24/marg/2">The ownership of the entity was transferred contrary to the Ukrainian law. On 24.3.2014 the 'Presidium of the Parliament of Crimea' adopted a decision 'On State-owned Enterprise 'Gosudarstvenoye predpriyatiye Universal-Avia' ('O Гocyдарcтвeннoм прeдприятии «Унивeрcал-Aвиа»)' No. 1794-6/14 declaring the appropriation of assets belonging to the state enterprise 'Universal-Avia' on behalf of the 'Republic of Crimea'. The enterprise is thus effectively confiscated by the Crimean 'authorities'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/24/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/25">
        <i>7. Resort 'Nizhnyaya Oreanda' (Cанатoрий 'Hижняя Oрeанда')</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/25/marg/1">Resort 'Nizhnyaya Oreanda', 08655, Yalta, Oreanda (08655, г.Ялта, пгт. Oрeанда, Cанатoрий 'Hижняя Oрeанда')
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/25/marg/2">The ownership of the entity was transferred contrary to the Ukrainian law. On 21 March the 'Presidium of the Parliament of Crimea' adopted a decision 'On the questions of creation of the Association of sanatoria and resorts' No. 1767-6/14 declaring the appropriation of assets belonging to the resort 'Nizhnyaya Oreanda' on behalf of the 'Republic of Crimea'. The enterprise is thus effectively confiscated by the Crimean 'authorities'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/25/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/26">
        <i>8. Crimean enterprise 'Azov distillery plant' (Крымcкoe рecпyбликанcкoe прeдприятиe 'Aзoвcкий ликeрoвoдoчный Завoд'), Azovsky likerovodochny zavod</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/26/marg/1">40 Zeleznodorozhnaya str., 96178 town of Azov, Jankoysky district (Джанкoйcкий райoн, пгт Aзoвcкoe, yл. Жeлeзнoдoрoжная, 40) code: 01271681
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/26/marg/2">The ownership of the entity was transferred contrary to the Ukrainian law. On 9 April the 'Presidium of the Parliament of Crimea' adopted a decision No 1991-6/14 'On the amendments to the Resolution of the State Council of the Republic of Crimea' of 26 March 26 2014 No. 1836-6/14 'On nationalization of the property of enterprises, institutions and organizations of agro-industrial complex, located in the territory of the Republic of Crimea' declaring the appropriation of assets belonging to the 'Azovsky likerovodochny zavod' on behalf of the 'Republic of Crimea'. The enterprise is thus effectively confiscated by the Crimean 'authorities'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/26/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/27">
        <i>9. State concern 'National Association of producers «Massandra»' (Hациoнальнoe прoизвoдcтвeннo-аграрнoe oбъeдинeниe 'Mаccандра'), Nacionalnoye proizvodstvenno agrarnoye obyedinenye Massandra</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/27/marg/1">6, str. Mira, Massandra 98600 city of Yalta (98600, г. Ялта, пгт Mаccандра, yл. Mира, д. 6) code: 00411890
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/27/marg/2">The ownership of the entity was transferred contrary to the Ukrainian law. On 9 April the 'Presidium of the Parliament of Crimea' adopted a decision No 1991-6/14 'On the amendments to the Resolution of the State Council of the Republic of Crimea' of 26 March No. 1836-6/14 'On nationalization of the property of enterprises, institutions and organizations of agro-industrial complex, located in the territory of the Republic of Crimea' declaring the appropriation of assets belonging to the state concern 'National Association of producers «Massandra»' on behalf of the 'Republic of Crimea'. The enterprise is thus effectively confiscated by the Crimean 'authorities'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/27/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/28">
        <i>10. 'State enterprise Magarach of the national institute of wine' (Гocyдарcтвeннoe прeдприятиe &gt;Aгрoфирма 'Mагарач' Hациoнальнoгo инcтитyта винoграда и вина 'Mагарач'), Gosudarstvenoye predpriyatiye 'Agrofirma Magarach' nacionalnogo instituta vinograda i vina 'Magarach'</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/28/marg/1">9 Chapayeva str., 98433 Vilino, Bakhchisarayski district, (98433, Aвтoнoмная Pecпyблика Крым, Баxчиcарайcкий райoн, c. Bилинo, yл. Чапаeва, д. 9) Code: 31332064
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/28/marg/2">The ownership of the entity was transferred contrary to the Ukrainian law. On 9 April the 'Presidium of the Parliament of Crimea' adopted a decision No 1991-6/14 'On the amendments to the Resolution of the State Council of the Republic of Crimea' of 26 March 26 2014 No. 1836-6/14 'On nationalization of the property of enterprises, institutions and organizations of agro-industrial complex, located in the territory of the Republic of Crimea' declaring the appropriation of assets belonging to the state enterprise 'Gosudarstvenoye predpriyatiye «Agrofirma Magarach» nacionalnogo instituta vinograda i vina «Magarach»' on behalf of the 'Republic of Crimea'. The enterprise is thus effectively confiscated by the Crimean 'authorities'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/28/marg/3">25.7.2014
<br/></marg>
      </ledd>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/i/ledd/29">
        <i>11. State enterprise 'Factory of sparkling wine Novy Svet' (Гocyдарcтвeннoe прeдприятиeЗавoд шампанcкиx вин 'Hoвый cвeт'), Gosudarstvenoye predpriyatiye 'Zavod shampanskykh vin Novy Svet'</i>
        <br/>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/29/marg/1">1 Shalyapina str., 98032 Sudak, Novy Svet (98032, г. Cyдак, пгт Hoвый Cвeт, yл. Шаляпина, д. 1) Code: 00412665
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/29/marg/2">The ownership of the entity was transferred contrary to the Ukrainian law. On 9 April the 'Presidium of the Parliament of Crimea' adopted a decision No. 1991-6/14 'On the amendments to the Resolution of the State Council of the Republic of Crimea' of 26 March 26 2014 No. 1836-6/14 'On nationalization of the property of enterprises, institutions and organizations of agro-industrial complex, located in the territory of the «Republic of Crimea» declaring the appropriation of assets belonging to the state enterprise «Zavod shampanskykh vin Novy Svet»' on behalf of the 'Republic of Crimea'. The enterprise is thus effectively confiscated by the Crimean 'authorities'.
<br/></marg>
        <marg niv="1" id="/kapittel/i/ledd/29/marg/3">25.7.2014</marg>
      </ledd>
    </kapittel>
    <kapittel type="kapittel" id="/kapittel/ii" url="https://lovdata.no/lovtidend/forskrift/2014-07-29-1022/kii">
      <kverdi>II</kverdi>
      <ktittel/>
      <ledd id="/kapittel/ii/ledd/1">Endringene trer i kraft ved kunngjøringen i Norsk Lovtidend.</ledd>
    </kapittel>
  </tekst>
</dokument>
